I heard there's a cabin up north...
Moshe! Amazing, inside a cave.
I'm not Jesus in a cave,
not in a wooden cabin or a tent in the desert.
I haven't done anything wrong to anyone.
Why bad? I'm just trying to find something that will make you happy.
So maybe we should fly abroad?
-What fly?
What, to Paris?
Let's fly to Los Angeles for Efrat,
The girls are already grown up.
-What Los Angeles?
I just got a little bonus.
I didn't win the lottery.
So, what do you want to do with the money?
-I don't know yet.
Whatever I feel like. First of all, meat.
I want to eat a good steak.
You got 3,200 shekels and all you want is a steak?
Do you know how long it's been since I
had a good steak? Like, properly aged.
A thick ribeye like that,
maybe with some coarse salt on it...
A steak you know you didn't just pay 90 shekels for.
I want to chow down on a cow at "A.V."
After that, do whatever you want
with the leftover bonus.
Alright, fine, so you have it in short.
Call "A.V." and book a table for yourself.
For you?
-Come on, what do you want?
They only have pieces of cow to eat there.
There's nothing for the girls to eat.
-So what, am I supposed to eat alone?
Take Manny. You always said
he's your favorite in the family,
and now he just had a son and he loves meat like you do,
so that's cool. Go, go with Manny
and chow down on a cow.
What is it, how much will it cost you?
-Honestly, it's doable.
But that doesn't get you off the cabin, right?
Alright, let's go. Find parking.
Look at me, look at me...
This belongs to that, it's going to green.
Dad, pass me the next cable.
Here, this is for the camera.
-For the camera.
I don't get why you guys don't buy a laptop.
When was the last time you surfed the internet?
We need to move forward.
-Sir, I'm doing a Kiddush here
from my living room in Israel
with my daughter Efrat in Los Angeles
via Skype. Is that advanced enough for you?
Here it is...
-Right?
This one for the remote.
For the mouse.
-Mouse.
That's it. It's connected, I think.
Just need to turn it on.
Can you just come sit?
I wanted to ask you something.
Sure.
I wanted to ask you something sensitive
about the internet.
Do you know who Itzik the Happy is?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hey, what's up?
What's new?
-Shabbat Shalom, Dad.
What's up? What's the week like?
-Are you doing Kiddush with Efrat?
Yeah, just need to turn it on and that's it.
-Is everything connected?
Yeah.
-Then come, come here for a sec,
I want to talk to him about something.
Tell me, are they here with the little one?
-Yeah, they're in the kitchen.
Great. What's up, Dad? What's the week like?
-You know how it is.
They say anyone over 60
who doesn't feel any pain,
it's a sign they're dead.
Alright, I'm going to say hi to Mom and Alin.
Dad, do you need help?
No, no. I don't need help.
Why do you think I'm limited in any way?
You don't need to be a professor to press a button
that says "Ooh" and "Oof." Oh, here it is.
What's up, Shushu?
Listen, you love meat, so I thought I'd invite you.
Let's go out tomorrow night, just you and me,
to grab a bite. We'll go for a steak.
Really good quality at A.V. I'm ordering.
I never say no to meat, it's a principle.
-Of course.
It's a deal?
-Deal.
Good thing I have ears, or else
the smile would tear my face apart.
Alright, I'm just going to confirm this with Alin...
-What do you need to confirm?
95% sure it's a done deal.
-Oh, then I'm calling A.V.
95% sure of a reservation?
-Cool.
Awesome.
-Awesome.
Just keep it quiet with Elio, okay?
I want it to be just you and me.
You know this family. It's...
Of course.
Hi, I want to reserve a steak for tomorrow.
A place. Sorry.
How sweet, look at him laugh.
Everyone says he has the same laugh as Manny.
Tell me, he's in the top percent, right?
Sure. Manny wasn't small either, right? It's in your genes.
Yeah, but he's a bit bigger
than Manny was at that age.
Knock on wood. Wow, wow, wow,
My sweetie, my sweet.
-Alright, healthy kid.
My little cutie, my small child,
Tiny tot, cutie pie, my little darling.
Don't listen to nonsense.
So, what happened to Dad?
-Oh, I don't know,
I have no idea. Ever since Elio and Manny came, he's been like this,
giving me the cold shoulder, not talking to me.
What’s he upset about now?
-I don’t know, no clue,
only God knows.
-Elio, can I have a moment?
Two on the bar, and if there’s a change,
I’ll let you know. Thanks.
There’s a problem with the computer software.
What’s the problem?
-What’s the problem...
Oh, also, acting all cool, being dismissive.
If I say there’s a problem, then there’s a problem.
And what about her?
-That I turned on the computer and nothing happens.
Are you sure you turned it on?
Did you press the power button?
-Stop messing with my head.
I pressed the right button.
-The big red one with the line on it.
Listen, I pressed the big button
that turns on the whole computer. Got it?
The one with the yellow sticker I put on
and I wrote "On" and "Off" on it. Got it?
It’s closed.
-What’s closed? What’s closed? It’s open.
Look, what’s wrong with you?
-What’s with the face?
I feel bad for her.
She’s home alone with the baby all day.
-Manny...
Do me a favor, both of you, okay?
Stop messing around, look at what's happening here?
Please. I don’t want
Efrat waiting there in Los Angeles
with her whole family because that’s not respectful.
Alright, alright, Dad. Shai, check
that everything's connected properly.
No problem. Worst case, if we can’t connect,
we can look at Orna a couple of times.
-What happened to you? Efrat is way prettier.
Efrat is way prettier? Oh, twins.
She’s way more into me.
-Well, the last time I saw
Efrat was when she gave birth to the... to Manny?
Yael.
-Gizelle.
Even then, she was a knockout.
So, does it make a noise when it’s on?
-Dad, tell me,
did you even turn on the screen?
What message?
-This screen.
What, isn’t it automatic?
-No, Dad, it’s not automatic.
Here, the power button is right here.
I need a sticker.
Well, anyway, there’s a problem because it won’t turn on.
Yeah, there’s probably an issue with the computer software.
So that’s what I said, there’s a problem.
When I say there’s a problem, there’s a problem.
Oh, thank God.
Your dad is a penny pincher. Oh, thank God,
do you know what time it is?
Go get dressed. I thought you’d help me a bit.
-Okay, just a sec,
How’s it going, babe?
-What’s up, sis?
All good, did you see the baby? What a giant!
-Why a giant?
He’s not a giant,
but you have to admit he’s big.
Big?
-He’s not big. He just has big bones.
Wait, what’s better? A kid that’s too small?
He’s a healthy kid.
-That’s not a kid, that’s a fridge.
Meirav...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Oh, here come Moshe and Orna.
Go get dressed, you’re half-naked.
Go, go, before Ilana tears you apart.
What’s up, Moshe?
-So, have you uploaded Efrat yet?
No, not yet, there’s a problem with the computer software.
You need to turn it off and on,
it always works. Move aside. Let me.
Enough, Moshe, Moshe, can you chill? We just did a restart.
And it didn’t start.
-No.
I always kick it
a little! A little kick, it always works.
That’s the advice they gave at tech support?
What’s the deal?
-You know, but what...
What’s going on with you guys? How’s the little one?
Honestly, thank God. We finished
renovating his room, it turned out amazing.
That’s great. So maybe we’ll come over tomorrow?
Moshe, me and the kids?
No, not tomorrow. Manny is going out with Shai.
Really?
-To which restaurant, I know. Something with cows.
Cows.
-Yeah.
Nice.
I don’t get why it’s not working.
-Give me a sec, Shai, I’ll handle it.
I had the same thing at home.
It’s nonsense, it’s a "BBS" issue.
What’s "BBS"?
-There’s no such thing.
Why do you say there isn’t? Here, look.
Hey, oh
-What?
What are you doing? He’s trying to start the computer.
What are you... stop kicking, stop kicking.
-It always works, Silvan.
What’s wrong with you? I’m going to get a manual.
Hold on! Keep this horse until I get back.
Helen...
-What?
Moshe...
Shabbat Shalom, babe.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Tell me, what am I hearing?
I don’t know, Mediterranean music usually. Right?
Tell me, what’s this story about Manny and Shai dating?
What... what’s the story... just, with Ilan...
They’re going to some steak place,
“Yeah, Moshe! One of those Saturday night spots.
You know, it’s half restaurant, half bar, something...
Just a place to raise a glass,
a place like that, a fancy place.
Oh, and Moshe doesn’t go because it’s fancy?
What?
-So why doesn’t Moshe go?
You know, you don’t see it on him
but inside he’s sensitive, sensitive,
He’s like porcelain in an elephant shop.
Tell me, what’s wrong with you? What,
it’s not like it was planned for weeks,
It's right here on the way, closed.
-So what?
You know, Shai, he felt like having meat
so he also invited Mabi.
Do you want him to invite Moshe too?
No problem,
he'll invite Moshe too.
-Great, because I won't have the energy
for his whining at home:
"Nobody loves me,
why did they say this and that?"
-No problem, no problem, sis.
It's on me, just relax.
-I'm going to grab a snack.
Shai, come here for a sec, babe. Come on, just a moment.
Hey, where's Mom?
-How should I know?
Give me that, give me that.
-No, I don't want to.
Sali? Sali, are you here?
You're not talking to me? Are you playing
childish games with me?
Just so you know, I can play
just as well as you can.
No wonder you don't know them.
Silvan.
-That's Tripov's.
He found it in the closet.
-What's that?
It's the old "iPod."
-How Grandpa Menachem loved them...
I had tons of tapes here, I really did.
Of Aris Su, of Trifonas, of Elikhi, there was...
Everything okay?
-Yeah, everything's fine.
And you?
Everything's fine.
So all this time you were... here?
Why, did something happen there?
-No, nothing. Nothing.
What are you looking for?
-What do you think I'm looking for?
I don't think. That's why
I'm asking. What are you looking for?
I'm looking for the computer manual.
It's over there.
-No, it's not there.
The helper stole it.
Look near the box of records.
I'm going back to the kitchen.
So what? So... I'm not...
Is it cheerful enough?
-Not really.
Moshe is coming with you tomorrow too.
-What? Why?
Because, Alin told Orna,
and Moshe will start crying
and I'll get the blame and I don't want that.
-But what...
And you can't put all that on Orna
for the whole amount,
so you're inviting Moshe too.
-No, I just wanted...
Come on, what's your deal? Why are you making a big deal out of this?
It's just Moshe. He's a little guy,
how much can he eat?
What? Did he take your plate?
He barely eats a quarter of a chicken himself.
I'll go change the order.
-Thanks, babe.
What order?
-Shai, Moshe and Manny
are going to some place.
-What place?
A place. Like... a bistro or something,
a bite to eat. You know... have a drink,
in honor of Sivan.
-Oh, great, great.
What about Dad?
-What about Dad?
Why didn't he invite Dad?
-Because...
Because what? Because what,
because he's not cheerful enough? Is that the deal?
What?
-Do me a favor, Shani, you know how sensitive he is.
Look, now he's sitting in his room,
giving me the silent treatment
like a little kid. Not because he probably heard and got hurt.
And who do you think he's taking all this out on?
Who is he taking all this out on?
On me.
So do me a favor and handle this
if you want a sane mom.
Okay, Mom, I'll take care of it.
-Thanks, sweetie.
Three at the bar and sorry.
Thanks, Shai, cool. I love meat.
Okay, I don't get why this isn't working.
Manny, do you remember how to open this in safe mode?
Wait a sec, they put me on hold.
Ah, it’ll pass in a moment.
I’ll call my support.
"With you every moment..."
-Did you call?
"Electric Company." What is this...
What an idiot I am
I instinctively called the Electric Company.
Because the fuse keeps blowing because of the AC.
Orna, you won’t believe this.
I, I instinctively...
You need to press something, "F4" or "F8."
Or "F5 1." Here’s the computer manual.
I saved it.
-No, it’s fine, Manny’s with support.
No, it shouldn’t be complicated.
Look, there’s English, there’s French,
there’s Arabic... what is this? Is there such writing?
That’s Thai.
-Honey, come here for a sec.
No way.
-Come on already.
Oh, hello, thank you so much,
I need technical support
and how long did it take you to answer this time?
No, no, no, sorry, sorry,
sorry, sorry, really.
No, no, no, I’m not complaining.
Not complaining.
Computer,
home
Sorry, I didn’t understand the question. I didn’t understand.
Excuse me, can you please
transfer me to someone with a different accent?
Moshe.
-No problem. I’m waiting. Thanks.
Moshe, can you explain to me what this...
Facebook thing is that everyone’s talking about?
What, what, what does it do?
-It’s an internal network
within the internet where you can
chat with whoever you want,
but Silvan, between us, it’s one big Sodom and Gomorrah.
What do you mean?
-Hello, I need technical support.
Sorry, I didn’t understand the question. I didn’t understand.
No, not yet.
-What, why did you hang up?
I can’t even recognize his accent.
-Well, no choice.
Moshe, what is this?
Really, is it... Sodom and Gomorrah?
Two... two, honey?
I don’t get it. How did it get this bad?
What did I even ask for? To quietly ride a cow.
You’re inviting Dad too.
And don’t let him touch your wallet.
I’m warning you.
I know him with your respect.
Even if he insists. Got it?
-Got it.
So, what? What happened? You’ll have fun together.
Think about it, all the guys together.
-I didn’t want guys.
I wanted a cow. A cow.
War
because, Dad. I’ll cook them for you. Sit
Here.
-Thanks, honey.
Ah, Coral. That’s her dad. Okay.
Okay. Wait, wait, wait, wait, slow down.
Speak slowly, I can’t keep up.
-Silvan, are you listening,
we’re going to eat meat tomorrow night.
So I thought maybe you’d join.
We’d love it. I’m inviting.
Tomorrow?
-Yeah. We’ll celebrate the birth of the first boy.
Is Moshe coming too?
-Yeah.
Alright.
I’m inviting.
-Not a chance.
Windows is up. I’m listening.
Tell me, for real,
this Facebook thing,
is it really like that, Sodom and Gomorrah?
What is it? Every couple of days you hear on the news
about someone who did something through this thing.
Rachel.
-Finally, he’s talking to me.
Rachel, come here, please.
-I'm coming.
What's going on with them today?
-No idea.
Oh, by the way, Dad's coming with them tomorrow.
-Really?
Shai from Shani invited the guys for meat tomorrow.
No kidding.
-No kidding.
What about my husband?
What husband? Since when do you have a husband?
Just because I don't have a husband doesn't mean you can skip over me.
What do you mean?
I mean every woman in the family
sends her husband to represent her,
so I want to too. Enough with this discrimination.
So what if I don't have a husband? Sorry,
I'm sending myself
to be the representative of my family at this meal
and I'll pay for myself if anyone has a problem with that.
It's just guys, and no one has a problem with you, Meirav.
Yeah, so why am I not invited?
-Well, say something.
What do you want from me?
-Mom.
Food will be ready soon. Grandpa! We need to talk.
Okay, Mr. Hasson, what did you go through today?
Can you please tell me who this happy Itzik is?
How long have you been together?
That he’s asking you to be his girlfriend like that?
What’s that?
Who is this happy Itzik?
And what are you doing to him that he’s so happy?
What are you talking about?
You're denying that you know happy Itzik?
Listen to me carefully. If you say
the word "Itzik" again
or the word "happy,"
I don’t know what I’ll do.
So let’s calm down now. Sit down, let’s relax. Let’s sit
quietly and calmly while you explain to me
what you’re talking about.
-Okay, okay. I’ll explain.
This afternoon, I came to shut down the computer,
and it was open, the computer,
on that brothel, Facebook,
and on your screen with your picture
happy Itzik is asking you to be his girlfriend.
Look, this is... this is neither the time nor the place,
the kids are out there. I don’t know happy Itzik,
I don’t want to know happy Itzik.
And as far as I’m concerned, you can be friends with happy Itzik,
maybe I’ll do that,
and then he won’t be so happy anymore.
Maybe, and now, when I do
a restart, will it work?
Okay. Do you want to wait with me
on the line to see if it comes up?
Oh, okay, okay, sorry. Sorry. Okay, Coral,
thank you. Say hi to everyone for me.
No, you’re right. Four at the bar
is really too much.
So a table. I know
it’s an extra 10 percent. Yeah.
A table for four. Sure, yes. Definitely sure.
Bye! Thanks and sorry.
-Honey, come here for a sec.
Are you making fun of me?
-No, no. It’s something completely different.
Ugh, you scared me.
Oh, it worked! Hey, it worked!
Meirav is coming with you too.
-Where to?
To Itzik Kale's show. To eat meat. Where else?
Your dad is crazy.
-And the apple doesn’t fall far from the tree.
I don’t want her coming with us.
-Okay, no choice.
No one’s asking you. It’s either this
or the events of 1929.
Shabbat Shalom.
I think they started.
How did it happen that she’s coming with us too?
Well, you don't really want to know, right?
-Right.
Now listen up, she doesn't have a dime to her name.
Not that I think she'll offer to pay,
yeah, but even if she does,
You're inviting Meirav too.
You realize your dream of the cabin is slipping away.
Come on, it's just Meirav, how much can she eat...?
Fine, I'll look for a cheap cabin.
-Cheaper than a cave?
Maybe a double bench in a public park.
Of course, the name is right there.
Beautiful, wait.
-Stranger.
What's this?
-It's Mom's Facebook page.
Wow, I can't believe it.
Itzik the Happy asked you to be friends too?
Who's Itzik the Happy?
-Yeah, who is Itzik the Happy?
You know, I think he asked me to be friends too.
What an embarrassment, I'm so sorry.
I think he got to you through me.
I think he somehow took over
my friends list.
And he's asking everyone to be friends.
-What are you saying?
Did you hear that, Silvan?
I heard, I heard, I'm not deaf.
I think he asked me too.
-He asked me too. I set up a date with him for tonight.
Okay, okay, I forgive you.
Can you see me?
-Here, that's Efrat on the nest.
Efrat.
-Efrat.
Efrati.
Hey, Mom, hi. Hello.
It's a messed-up connection.
-Because it's Los Angeles, it's far.
Efrati, apologize for us for the half-hour delay,
so we can start the Kiddush.
-Dad, actually, you guys were half an hour early
but... Moshe! Later,
is it okay with me if Grandpa does the Kiddush here?
No, why not suddenly? The main thing is that there's Kiddush.
Great, so everyone will be gathering here soon.
Efrati, how are you, sweetheart? How's everyone?
Everyone's doing great. The girls are here,
sitting, watching "The Pajamas."
Manny, how's it going with you? How's Sivan?
You probably don't have a moment to breathe.
-Yeah, I'm wiped out.
It's okay, I gave him a free evening tomorrow.
Tomorrow all the men of the Hasson family
are going out for meat.
And Meirav too.
-Why just the men?
Why actually? Don't we deserve to go out a bit?
Right, we haven't gone out together in ages.
Let's all go out together?
Tomorrow we're all going to the restaurant together.
How nice. Well,
too bad I can't be there.
Okay, wait, here, the Kiddush is starting.
-Sit down, honey, come here for a sec.
No, I can't. There's Kiddush now.
-Now!
Quiet, you can barely hear. Ben.
I think they started with "A Woman of Valor, who can find."
"A Woman of Valor, who can find..."
Honey, I'm so sorry.
-Cow, to go down on a cow,
that's all I asked for.
-Okay, it's on my plate.
I don't even know how it turned out. Like a reflex.
Sabri Marban-
-To life!
To life.
A cabin up north, huh? After the meal tomorrow
we should be thankful if
we have laundry money left for the Bahá'ís.
How did it come to this?
-I don't know. Come on, enough.
At least take comfort in the fact
that you're going to eat a good steak tomorrow.
Amen!
Pass it on.
I'm going to get the fish.
Cheers.
So tell me, which restaurant are you going to tomorrow?
To "A.V." It's a new place in Kerem HaTeimanim.
Their specialty is meat.
Is it kosher?
Because Mom and Dad only eat kosher.
Yeah, I'm trying to keep kosher too.
I can't believe it. I just wanted to dig into a steak.
Steak.
-Okay, babe, sorry, it's a good restaurant.
Come on, they have amazing skewers there.
A pargiyot is not a steak, sit down. A pargiyot is a chicken.
Fine. It's healthier.
-So instead of digging into a steak,
what it means is I have to
invite your whole family tomorrow
to a restaurant I don't even like
just to eat chicken with antibiotics.
Well, okay, but will it be cheaper for us?
Much cheaper. Alright.
And then you'll have money to invite me to a cabin in a cave.
Can you drop me off here?
I think Itzik the Happy lives around here.
Hope you have a good time.
They say that anyone over 60,
if they don't... if nothing hurts,
then that's a sign that they're... yeah.
That something's happened to them. Something's up.
Again, again, from here, from here.
I don't see any difference...
And what are you doing with him that's so good?
That he's so happy...
I didn't know what to say anymore.
What are you kicking? What is that?
Don't worry. It's working.
Ah.
-No. Wait, he needs... he needs to kick again.
You need to kick again.
And I'm going to get fish.
Oh, I'm going to get the fish.