It smells like someone died in the car.
Do you think someone died here?
Mom, she’s scaring me.
-No, nobody's dead, girls,
Dude, that’s a rotten apple.
Honey, maybe we should save this gift for later?
No, no, honey, we’re giving
my mom what I bought,
What you bought, leave it in the trunk.
You haven’t even seen her.
-Okay, no need.
Why are we leaving so early?
Because Grandma is celebrating her 60th birthday today.
How old is she?
-63.
Look at me, look at me and...
And let’s meet the new couple of contestants.
Here come Rachel and Silvan,
parents of five and grandparents to...
I’m intentionally not saying how many
so the audience won’t go “knock on wood”
and jinx the whole studio.
Rachel and Silvan Hasson.
There you go, that’s all we recorded.
Since when do you have this receiver?
They did this deal because of Meirav
that includes internet, phone, and the Tami 4
and they also got this receiver.
What, and let’s say I already had this receiver,
then what, how could I record?
I was filming, it was live.
So what, you don’t have to be home,
you can schedule a recording on the receiver.
No, no, no, it’s a new receiver,
I want to learn more about how to program it.
There’s nothing to program here, Dad, it’s not like the VCR.
So how does it record?
-What does it record?
What recorder? There’s no recording,
it saves it to the hard drive.
So where’s the disk that has the show?
Inside the receiver.
And how do you get the disk out after?
-From the receiver.
With a VCR, when you recorded something
you knew you were recording.
You could plan everything with the remote, you know?
You’d set the clock,
choose the time you want
to watch the show,
hit record...
Yeah, Dad, and how long has the VCR been broken?
It’s expensive, you don’t know how much it is,
there’s no technician in the country who knows how to fix
those VCRs, it’s not...
It’s a VCR with four heads,
four heads.
You’d put the tape in
and you’d feel someone inside
accepting it and not dodging.
Yeah, there was a little slot like that...
pulling the tape in and the door would close,
and then you’d hear four heads starting to rev up,
like some jumbo jet.
And if it broke down, you could
open a parachute that was inside the VCR
that would save it.
Laugh, laugh.
Say, did Rachel ask Alon and Manny
to bring the rest of the show?
Yeah, Manny has a DVD burner,
he’ll download it, okay?
They’ll record it on a disk, don’t worry.
Mom, happy birthday.
-Hey, sweetie, thank you, thank you.
And I’m so sorry
I didn’t manage to bring you anything yet.
It’s okay, it’s really not important, I don’t need gifts.
My gift for you.
Yeah, but it was important to me
to bring you something small and meaningful.
No, it’s really not important, not small or meaningful, really.
No, it is important.
I was already on my way to Azrieli,
and you won’t believe the crazy traffic,
we moved one meter, then went back two,
and tons of ambulances, police, fire trucks.
In the end, it turned out to be
some suspicious package on Maza Street.
I love you.
Okay, I’m going to order you
something online and get dressed.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
Wow, Dad, you were amazing on TV.
Yeah, yeah, there was this photographer
who told me that.
-Nice.
Where’s Shai?
He had a little mishap with a strudel in the car.
-Hope it’s not too bad.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Shayka.
What’s this, a gift for Rachel?
She’s tough when it comes to gifts, huh?
Where’s Mom?
-In the kitchen.
Shai, come here for a sec.
This isn’t the gift I was hoping for.
-Not really.
Why did you bring this poster here
after we agreed not to?
You agreed, I didn’t.
Okay, Shai, listen,
don’t you dare leave this here, okay?
Jump to the bedroom and think of a good excuse
and about mold.
I’ll be right back.
Congratulations.
Thanks, thank you, my sweet.
Thank you very much.
Congratulations.
-Thanks, beautiful, thank you.
Go to Shachar, dolls. Congratulations, Mom.
-Thank you, thank you.
Thank you.
I don’t understand why you insist
on working so hard on your birthday.
Seriously, why are you making such a big deal
about my birthday,
I’d rather celebrate all the other days of the year.
Okay, Mom. Stop it, come on, times have changed,
today’s sixties are like the fifties back then.
Where’s Meirav?
She’s probably stuck in traffic at the Google entrance.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Riki Ben Sharivan, did you bring the disc?
We did. Why, haven’t you seen it yet?
We’ve seen it, the main stars haven’t.
They were in the studio, didn’t know
how to record with the new converter.
Moshe, be quiet.
Okay, the disc is here, everyone’s here,
can we start the screening?
Give me the...
Mom, sit down, Meirav, come on, we want to start.
Silvan, come on, run through
all the contestants from the show,
we don’t have to watch everything,
just put on your part, I’m hungry.
Don’t stand over me, okay?
This is the remote for the video.
Are you going to stand over me for a long time?
Sit down.
Why are the signs in plastic?
-Because it keeps them fresh.
Please. Thanks.
Here, I'm running it.
You know if you press it again
it’ll run faster?
Times four.
So that’s times four in fast mode.
If you press it again, it’s times 16.
Times 30.
I don’t get it, why is it times 30 and not times 32?
Stop, stop, stop, rewind, rewind.
Why did you hit "stop"?
Now we have to run everything from the start,
you should’ve pressed "play."
Okay, okay,
I can run it, I have times 30 here,
What’s wrong with you? Come on, run it, run it, run it.
Stop!
No...
I see she’s twitching a bit
and I’m going downstairs to get your gift from the car.
But at least look at this one.
-Okay, fine, just quick.
Because they want to start the episode screening.
It’s not cheap either, it costs 159 shekels.
What? You paid 160?
-That’s its price,
they gave me a discount because they just opened the business,
they based their new software on me.
-How much?
I was the first one so...
Wow, that’s really nice.
-See?
What, like, you designed this?
-Of course you get it?
That’s exactly why they invented this software,
you just input all the details into the computer,
and it edits it for you automatically
with pictures and colors and all that...
They print it on high-quality canvas.
See? Canvas.
No, that’s really a nice choice.
So?
-So go down to the car and bring my gift.
Why?
-Why? Just because.
Because it seems to me, I don’t know how or why
that this gift will bring me disaster.
How did you get to disaster? It’s a gift.
Honey, listen for a second, you can’t go wrong with bedding.
I’ll make you a deal, okay?
Let’s ask everyone what they think about it
if they like it, then we’ll keep the bedding for ourselves,
treat yourself a bit, what’s the harm?
Okay, fine,
it’s only because I hate you.
-I hate you too, honey.
Sorry.
I’m just looking for a place to put it down.
Sure, sure.
-Thanks.
Rachel and Silvan Hasson, how many weeks have you been married?
Too few.
If you could, you’d marry her first.
I’d marry him again too.
But what do I need, I’m at the peak of happiness.
So let’s just settle on saying
you’re a long-time loving couple
back when there was a hole in the TV.
No, no, no, there wasn’t a hole in the TV.
But we used to watch a lot
on three and six on Jordan.
Well, with your permission
we’ll now go to 17 short commercials
and we’ll be right back.
17 commercials and a few promos and we’ll be back shortly.
How nice.
Dad, did you see the show? Really.
What, it was so beautiful, what you said.
Did you see that? They gave me a big round of applause!
I didn’t remember that from the filming, really.
Mom, where are you going?
-I need to check something in the kitchen.
Call me when the commercials are over.
No, no, no, what commercials? Fast forward, fast forward,
Don’t waste time, Silvan.
-Okay, okay.
You guys were really good, Silvan, really
Dad was sure you’d take the multi.
Thanks.
Dad, do you want me to fast forward from the device?
No, I don’t want to, I can fast forward myself, okay?
No, Dad, you’re on "pause."
How is this under pressure?
-Look, you pressed both lines.
Wow, I’m starving.
-Dad, just fast forward already.
I’m fast forwarding, I’m fast forwarding.
This is teaching me what pause means.
Kid, do you know how many pauses
I’ve pressed in my life?
Pause is teaching me.
Mom, is everything okay?
-Yeah, everything’s fine.
You’re filming the show.
-Yeah, for Gili.
No, no, no, not just for Gili, you’re filming the show.
It’s just that "bad TV adds five pounds."
And ages you by ten weeks.
Or the other way around.
-Yeah.
It’s also known that Lovdon and Kirshenbaum are 48.
Yoni Levy isn’t really pretty in real life.
And Riva’s husband isn’t doing so well.
Wipe your hands.
Hey, is that picture your gift for Rachel?
It looks cute.
Yeah, Dad always makes me buy
bedding or pots.
Sit down, come listen for a sec.
-Just a second, hold on.
Orna, come here for a minute.
-Where to?
You come too.
Come, listen, listen for a second.
-In a minute, just a second.
What, again with the stop now?
Okay, keep watching,
we’ll be right there, what’s the rush?
Hey, why aren’t you recording the shows
on the hard disk of the box?
Quiet.
Come on, Moshe, where’s the triangle now?
Wow, did you know that both Marilyn Monroe
and Anne Frank were born under Mom’s sign?
I wouldn’t call it luck, but it turns out.
It’s designed really beautifully, is this your husband’s work?
It’s amazing. What do you think, is it too dangerous?
No... I know.
On the face of it, it looks fine
but there’s always a risk.
I’m scared.
Thanks for coming back to us,
we’re with the wonderful couple Rachel and Silvan Hasson.
Are you ready?
-Yeah, yeah.
Just let’s not waste our help too quickly.
There’s no help here.
The questions are between gods or aliens.
I don’t know about aliens, do you know anything?
Gods.
-Gods.
Gods, okay.
Pay attention, the answers are...
-Yeah.
Shiba, Kal', Tabdarn' an Ibidira.
Any other possible answers?
-No.
No, because it fell on him from the first hit.
It is what it is.
So we'll go with the help, please.
-There's no help here, no help.
And the question is, who is the Indian goddess of death?
In a way.
It's fine, I know.
Kali.
Are you sure?
-Kali, for sure.
What, are you guessing?
-Not guessing, I know.
Stop the clock, stop the clock,
Let's see if Kali is the Indian goddess of death.
Correct answer.
And.
What, did you guess?
-No, I knew.
Where do you know the Indian goddess of death from?
Do you remember that thing in the living room
that you call a hunk of metal?
Is that Kali?
-That's Kali.
What, do you have a statue of Kali at home?
Yeah, yeah, one of my sons-in-law bought me
this for my birthday four weeks ago.
Happy birthday.
-Thanks.
What's this?
A birthday gift for you,
Orna sent me to buy it for you.
She stayed home sick with the kid.
You really didn't have to. What's this?
Rachel, open up, open up, there's an exchange note inside.
Phew
that's a
piece
What is this, an ashtray?
Also.
Oh, it's nice, it's retro.
No, no, not retro, it's from India,
it's a one-piece casting, one piece.
Hmm, Moshe.
Oh, that's Kali.
-Kali?
"Kali" in Hindi means black.
I once dated an Indian guy.
That's the Indian goddess of death.
It's beautiful, it's, it's...
It's full of life.
I knew you'd love it.
-Yeah.
She wanted me to buy you bedding.
Anyway, he's cute! I love him.
The hunk of metal?
-About Moshe.
I'm really sorry, Rachel,
I didn't know it was the Indian goddess of death.
That was the most expensive thing in the store.
Of course, in the everything-for-a-rupee store.
Come on, relax you two,
I'm not really into birthdays.
What does it matter, the intention is what counts.
True.
-You're sweet.
So, what's the verdict?
-Come here, come.
Although a statue of the goddess of death at home
isn't such a problem
but thanks to her you
are staying alive and continuing in the game show.
-Yeah.
Pay attention, the next topics are sports or clothes.
Clothes?
-Clothes.
It's the... never mind.
Sports, sports.
-Sports.
Let's go with sports.
-Sports is my category.
Why?
-Because I was the national runner-up
in the 400-meter hurdles relay.
Is that true?
-Yeah, it's true, there were only two teams.
But it's true.
-But it's true.
Okay, so the answers are, pay attention:
1994, 2009, 2008, or 1987.
The answers are really easy, what's the question?
The question is when did Hapoel Holon
win the national basketball championship.
Holon?
-Holon, that's a city in the area.
The State Cup was in 2009,
the championship was in 1994...
Wait, that's a trick question.
Because Maccabi Tel Aviv
actually lost to them in '94.
But to Galil Elyon.
What?
-2008?
2008 for sure.
-For sure?
Listen to me, listen carefully,
If that's a mistake, we're either out or we're falling...
What's it called? That quiz show.
Alright, it's final.
Final decision.
-Final.
So let's see if 2008 is the right answer.
Correct answer.
-!Shai
I can't believe it.
How?
That was the excuse for 2008.
-Excuse?
My daughter, Meirav, every year on my birthday
she can't manage to buy me a gift.
Mom, happy birthday.
-Hey, sweetie, thanks.
And I'm so sorry I haven't had time
to get you anything yet.
It's not important, honey, I don't need a gift,
you're my gift.
Yeah, but it was important to me
to bring you something small and symbolic.
It's not important, what, I don't need
something small, not symbolic.
No, it is important,
I was already on my way to Azrieli,
You won't believe the crazy traffic,
thousands of people walking in the middle of the road singing.
Traffic jams from here to Holon.
Anyway, I didn't understand what the fuss was about
So I asked some guy who actually looked pretty cute
and I wouldn't have minded being stuck with him, what's the deal,
so he answered me with a smirk
that Hapoel Holon fans
just won the national basketball championship.
I love you.
-I'm going to order you
something online and get dressed.
She's really creative,
every year on my birthday she comes up with
a different excuse for not buying me a gift.
Even though we don't need gifts, who needs gifts anyway?
Do I need gifts?
-Meirav, Meirav...
I love her.
I love you.
Dear Hasson family,
you've kept the million until now.
Because, because, because.
We're moving on to the next question, question number three.
Pay attention, and the topics are physics or music.
What..
No, no, no physics, not physics.
-Of course.
Music, music.
Are you interested in music?
-Yeah, definitely.
What kind of music?
We really love Middle Eastern music.
-Yeah, definitely.
Great. So the answers are:
Giuseppe Verdi, Paul Gauguin,
Richard Wagner, or Ida Boudel.
We're going to use a lifeline.
There's no help in this game show.
What's the question?
The question is, who wrote
the famous opera "Aida"?
We'll use a lifeline.
-No, there's no lifeline.
So, what did they say about the picture?
-Unfortunately, they were really excited.
I personally think it's a mistake.
So let's keep the sheets for ourselves,
we deserve it, right?
Okay, okay, we'll keep the sheets,
I just hope she'll like it in the end.
Hey, can we maybe change
the color of the sheets to something else?
Alright, come on, get out, get out.
So, what did you decide?
-We'll give it to her in the end.
Nice. So, you definitely came here
with a spare gift, right?
So?
-I want to buy it from you.
It's Giuseppe Verdi.
You know you can split the money.
To whom?
-Come on, we're out of time.
Giuseppe Verdi, final answer.
You know?
Remember that Manny and Alin got me tickets
to the opera Aida for my birthday?
-Yeah.
Well, you called it "the crazy thing
with the black woman screaming."
She really did scream a lot.
Oh come on, I didn't know the soloist
would be replaced when I bought you the tickets.
You've already made it, it's fine.
Let's see if Giuseppe Verdi
is indeed the correct answer.
Correct answer.
-Shai!
Giuseppe Verdi is the one who wrote Aida.
Well done. I'm wondering, Rachel, what would you do
without the terrible gifts you've received over the years
from the people you love.
-Yeah.
I love them.
I understand you have a birthday tomorrow.
I'm not thinking about it at all.
-Happy birthday.
If you win the game show,
it would indeed be a wonderful gift for turning 49.
She's not 49...
We're out.
-Yeah, we are...
You can't quit in this game show.
So we prefer to use the help we deserve.
You don't deserve help in this game show.
-Okay.
The categories for the next question
are IDF or Justin Bieber.
IDF.
-Justin Bieber.
What's the decision?
IDF.
-Justin Bieber.
So what question are we going for?
Israel Defense Forces.
The people's army.
IDF.
-IDF.
Great, the answers are, pay attention:
1972, 1948, 1956, or 1966.
Those are very, very easy answers.
Wasn't this question already asked?
-No, it wasn't.
No, because I just remember all the numbers.
-No.
The question is, pay attention: In which year was the law
passed to serve only kosher food in the IDF?
Is there such a law?
-Apparently.
Come on, Racheli.
-What...
Well, Racheli.
I told you, I told you we should have quit.
You can't quit in this game show.
So maybe we'll use our help.
-There's no help!
There's no help in this game show, Sufi.
Come on, Racheli, you don't have this time
some gift you got from some groom.
Related to this question?
I can't remember.
Okay, but time's ticking, guys, we need to decide.
Ten, nine, eight.
-Wait...
Seven, six, five,
Four, three.
1956, Sufi.
Why?
-I don't know.
Right after the commercials, we'll see
if this answer is the right one.
Okay, I'm rolling.
Oops.
Okay, Dad, let it go,
we don't have to watch everything, it's fine,
It's a shame you didn't quit at the peak.
Come on, come on, let's move on
to the Kiddush. Come on, I'm hungry.
Wait, wait, before the Kiddush
maybe we should move to the gifts stage.
Yeah.
-No, no, no gifts, really.
But Reuven really needs it, Mom.
Girls, gifts.
-Come on.
ﭏ\
ﭏו%
ציּ
א
ﭏו%
This is from us, a pot.
We saw yours broke, so here's a new one.
Wow, how nice.
-Crazy pot.
Wonderful gift. Thank you.
Congratulations.
-Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Alin thought of this. Mom, congratulations.
Thank you, thank you.
This is from us, Mom,
it's a wool blanket to keep you warm in winter.
How lovely, you didn't have to,
thank you, my sweet.
And this is from us.
-Congratulations.
What is this?
That's me, what a picture.
Look, Mom, look.
Look.
How beautiful.
How did you get this picture?
This is really touching.
It's on real painting fabric.
-Yeah.
They have a computer that paints it on this.
Because you just enter the birth date and name,
and it paints and creates it.
-What an idea.
Colors and all.
-Right?
And there are all kinds of categories,
like who else was born under your sign,
important events on your birth date,
what the economic situation was in the country that year.
They have what was invented in the world, famous singers, everything.
Let me see.
This is Shai's idea.
-Great.
Wow, did you know
that in 1948 the dollar was worth 0.20 mil?
What's a mil?
-It's a currency that used to be here.
How nice, even in '48
they introduced the first long-playing record.
Wow, that was really long ago.
Wow, everything here is from the year 1926.
Wow, May 14, 1948, the Brits left the country.
When were the Brits here?
-A long time ago, in the middle of the last century.
Were there Brits here? Why did they leave?
I can't believe, in 1948 a law was passed...
In the army, they only serve kosher food.
What a joke, huh?
Bring the gift, bring the envelope.
You idiot, just leave it.
And.
A bed
also
you.
A lot
I, you
The baboon.
-The baboon.
But...
I'm sorry, sweetie.
Mom, congratulations.
-Thanks.
I can't believe you gave her the sheets
after I got emotionally attached to them.
If you want, I can
buy you a set like that.
I just saw it on sale, 300 shekels.
What's up, what a joke.
-No need, it's unnecessary.
But what, you didn't get emotionally attached to them?
I just disconnected.
Like Jumbo.
I can't take it anymore.
You held on for a long time.
The little guy is here, Moshe! With the big eyes.
Yeah, the remote.
There's no help here.
What's the question?
The question is...
Maybe we should use help.
-There's no help in this game show.
Sorry, too much because I checked the package.
He wants the package open.
But...
Just drop it, enough.