Trust me, it tastes completely different
when you grill it. Totally.
Yeah, you already told me that.
At six in the morning, when you woke me up,
which is three hours early. And a half.
Fine. You'll thank me for waking you up earlier.
You have no idea how fast the good spots get taken.
What's the big deal? It's a picnic.
Does it really matter where we sit?
What’s that? The girls will hear more.
Mom didn’t mean to say it like that.
It’s really, really important where we sit. Very.
Yeah.
-We’ll have the picnic
at the usual Rosen family spot,
which is the perfect place for a perfect picnic.
-Oh, honey, I don’t want to tell you
but the success of the picnic doesn’t depend
on where we sit, but who we sit with.
In your case, that’s already a lost cause
because it’s with your family.
Okay, so I know it sounds weird
coming from me,
I’m a realist, but there are places
that have good energy.
Yeah. Where? In his bed?
-Also. And in the forest.
Every time we got to that specific spot
the fights would stop,
the exams would pause, and as strange as it sounds,
my family really functioned like a family.
Your family functioned like a family? That really sounds weird.
Alright, enough, sit down, really.
Don’t mess with my tradition.
I spent all my childhood picnicking
in the same spot, under those same trees,
and all my adulthood I’ll picnic in that same spot,
and when your daughters grow up and want to picnic,
they’ll know exactly where they want
to be pampered. With them.
Come on, let’s sing. "In the forest, in the forest, in the forest"...
Volanshnu, lanashnuyo
Enough. It’s Saturday morning. Come on.
Look at me, look at me and...
Okay girls, you remember
what you’re looking for, right?
A big tree with a heart carved on it,
yes, and inside it says "Shai"
and another name that starts with an Aleph. Got it?
So let’s go.
Come on. Can’t we do this here?
-You’re so funny.
I don’t think we’re heading in the right direction.
"I’ll go out to the forest..."
Want to do a cannon?
-No. No. Speaking of "I’ll go out to the forest",
who’s that cute girl?
Who?
-The curls.
When are you going to tell me what that Aleph is about?
-What Aleph?
The Aleph you carved next to your name,
that you had a heart that said "Shai",
what you told the girls not to tell me.
-How did I know I couldn’t trust them?
Worth it?
-Enough, sit down. Do me a favor, drop it,
that was ages ago.
-Yeah, of course it was ages ago.
Slim?
-No.
Are you ready to let me
focus on finding this place?
Blonde or blonde?
Enough, sit down, trust me that when we get to the specific place
even your questions will disappear.
Seriously.
-Peace and calm.
Do we need to go through passport control?
Adam, explain to her that this forest
is planted within the State of Israel.
She only knows Tel Aviv.
North of the Yarkon is Ramat Aviv
and the Golan Heights.
To her, they can give it back to the Syrians.
East of the Ayalon is the Palestinian state,
south of Abulafia, in Jaffa, that’s Egypt.
Not only is she left-wing, Pinchas,
she’s extra, extra left.
And do you know how hard it is to find in my size?
In a second, Dad will crack and tell you.
Was her name Eti?
No, and why aren’t you looking?
-Orit?
Mom, this game isn't fun.
-Okay, just a sec, he's counting to ten.
Olga?
-I'm pretty sure it was here.
If you guys were looking, it would happen faster.
I can't believe it's gone.
Maybe there was a fire here.
Come on, babe, enough. Maybe we should stay here? Come on.
-How's the vibe here?
You're wasting your time, I'm on fire with energy,
my chakras are wide open. It's unreal.
Based on your sarcasm, I get it wasn't here.
Wait, here it is.
-What, are you sure?
No.
-Shai.
Maybe it was on that hill over there.
Babe, listen, listen,
it doesn't matter where the picnic is.
I promise you, you'll have an amazing picnic,
magical, just like your childhood memories.
You'll enjoy it with your family,
you'll enjoy it with their family.
Just without Ivga.
-Her name wasn't Ivga,
and according to your divisions, it wasn't here either.
I wonder if Itamar knew where it was.
Come on, let's go, to the hill.
Alexis?
-No.
Orchid?
-Come on!
Addis Ababa?
-Sit down.
Angelina.
Because, because, how did we know?
Acne!
Babe, watch out on the turn.
-I don't get how you could stay quiet about this.
I didn't stay quiet. You saw I yelled at him.
You laughed, Itamar.
-But loudly.
Your son put a dead animal in my pita, Itamar,
a dead animal!
A sausage. Do you want me to cry?
A dead animal. You know how I
feel about that, right?
Okay, enough already, babe, alright? He apologized.
That's enough and... you caught it in time.
It's not like he killed the animal just for them.
It had been dead for a long time
in our fridge, babe.
Babe, babe, babe, it's slipping away fast.
Son, are you feeling okay here?
I think so.
-You think?
Whatever, son.
Great, so whatever, everyone feels
good or thinks they feel good.
Can we start eating already?
Yoohoo...
Wow, Alibo,
for a brief moment there was really good energy here.
Yoohoo...
-Yoohoo T! Yoohoo.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
Sh, very crowded.
I think you came in the wrong shoes.
So fix it, fix it.
-Adam, take off your stuff. Sit down.
Here?
Come on, I'll pack it up. Come on, we're moving.
He put the sausage in my face.
Okay, we got it.
The sausage, the sausage, the sausage, the sausage.
So maybe it's really time for you to stop
with that stupid pose of yours
and start eating like a normal person.
Okay, sorry. I apologize, babe,
I went a bit overboard. I'm sorry.
I knew it. No. I knew it.
That's why you didn't get mad at him, because you agree with him.
I'm not...
-I'm not talking to you.
I don't get what was wrong with that place.
-What is it, is Itamar there?
What, is he coming with Michal's whole family?
-Are you crazy?
So no.
I hope they don't settle down too close,
so we won't have to move.
No, they're going over there.
-Oh, thank God.
Can we start grilling?
Sho
9% and
and, yayom
a
Come help Dad light the fire, please.
I've been doing this alone for forty years, Riki.
I can manage by myself.
What do you care if he comes to help you
light the fire?
Nonsense. It's fine. Dad, is there fire?
Riki, did you pack a lighter?
-Yeah, but where is it now?
You brought the whole house, just not fire?
You've been doing this alone for forty years, right?
Since when do I pack anything at home?
-Oh, great. Whine about it.
I told you there are no good vibes here?
-Oh, look what I found.
Maybe we can find some good vibes in this.
Look how nice. Toh, toh, toh.
Ah, here's some good energy.
Shai, maybe you should go ask our neighbors for fire?
They seem nice to me.
Nice? You didn't want them sitting next to us.
-And they didn't sit next to us.
Which makes them very nice in my eyes.
-Okay.
I'm glad you came. I was really worried.
Hello, hey.
-You're late. Did Michal drive?
What, babe? Everything okay?
-I don't know.
We're just going to the bathroom for a sec.
-I need to go too.
Me too, me too.
-Come on.
Enough, Mom, we're not moving.
Look at the time. Here.
Hello.
Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom. Am I interrupting?
-Not at all. Go ahead.
I feel awkward, even a bit silly,
but do you happen to have fire?
Fire?
-Yeah, my mom...
Forget it, you won't understand.
-You'd be surprised.
There's fire. Yes.
-Is there fire?
Do you want those lighters too?
-No, no. Just fire. Fire.
Want something to eat?
Ar...
Small.
-Wow, my mom will kill me.
You know what, why not?
-Mom, get him a pita.
Maybe one pita. No...
Come on, babe. Take it. Here, smoke over there.
We're waiting for you.
-Okay.
Come on, what's up?
-Raz let me eat meat,
and Itamar didn't even yell at him.
-Wow.
And that's not even the point. I'm not his mom
and I know I'm not his mom
because if I were his mom,
he'd be spoiled, maybe even short, like Yanir Bari.
No, he has a smell from his shoes that you hate,
and I tell him, Raz,
there are so many creams and products today.
There are halablubim, there are za'atar seeds...
Okay, okay, Michal, let's move on, yeah...
-Alright, sorry. Never mind,
but every time there's an issue,
Itamar is right there by his side.
What do you want? He's his son.
-And I don't hate him.
Who?
-Raz, who else.
Every time he's not around
everything's fine between me and Itamar.
I have no problem with the little one. Anyway
I don't understand a word she says,
but the older one... I'm telling you,
I wish he would just disappear.
So what? Rosh Hashanah is just around the corner, huh?
What corner?
-She's not the brightest highlighter in the pencil case. What?
What pencil case? What is he talking about?
Oh, there you are. How long did that take?
What is this? Did they feed you?
It was great.
-What was it, schnitzel?
No, Mom, they're not the kind of people who make schnitzels.
Ah, Yemenites.
-Arabs, yeah.
Let’s move on from here.
-Come on, Mom, really. Let’s go, enough.
Arabs from Jaffa, totally Israeli.
-No, you’re right.
If we move now, they’ll feel it’s because of them.
You never know how they’ll react.
Thanks. Go ahead.
It’s not fair. You’d expect that after a few weeks
this family would already know me.
I don’t know, maybe you should stop
punishing Raz once and for all.
What do you mean?
-Punish him.
Like not letting him play his stupid video games
at your place.
You think Itamar will let me?
-What, he won’t let you punish him?
No, he won’t care. He’ll even be happy.
-So?
He won’t let me take his video game
because then Itamar will have to talk to him
and keep him busy, and that’s already punishing Itamar.
Come on, what’s up, girls?
They must have drunk a lot on the way, you have no idea.
I want some too.
-Come on, go with the flow.
Wait with the gas, Dad.
Give me that, give me that.
At least let me light a match.
We need twigs.
-What twigs? We need gasoline.
We need ones like these... come on...
Light ones like these.
-Let’s just use newspapers, enough.
We want to read them.
-The culture supplement?
Like anyone cares what’s written there anyway.
Itamar, newspapers are dangerous.
The wind will come and there’ll be a fire...
Maybe we can siphon gas from one of the cars?
They used to light ones like these over there.
Come on, so why didn’t you take?
-I thought we’d manage.
You’re not going back there, okay?
-What’s your problem?
I’m tired of your nonsense.
I’m going to get lights like those.
You see? If we were in the right place, this wouldn’t happen.
What are you talking about? It was here.
-Not at all.
I remember that table and those flies.
I don’t remember it being this hot.
Look, look.
Just because they come and go,
doesn’t mean they’re not okay, Mom.
Hey.
-Hi, hi.
Listen, I’m the brother of the... that guy who...
The bald one.
Yeah. Just me, I got my mom’s genes.
I hope just in terms of hair, but... forget it.
You wouldn’t understand.
-You’d be surprised.
Listen, thanks for the fire.
He just told me you have...
I don’t know, he saw some lights like these earlier.
Say, aren’t you the... that actor,
the one from that movie?
Yeah, yeah—
You know, in HD
you look clearer. Has anyone told you that?
Sea.
Sit, I’ll get you a light.
Thanks.
-Do you want to eat something?
A little.
-My mom will kill me.
Come on, fine.
-Mom, get him a pita.
Pita. Got it. Maybe one.
Come on, leave that for now.
Let’s eat and get out of here.
Like his grandma is any better.
Sometimes I think she actually
puts kebabs in my salad.
Oh, come on, help me, sweetheart, with the salads.
Is this potato salad?
-It’s mayonnaise salad.
So what’s in it?
-Potatoes, okay? Don’t be picky.
No, no. I meant this.
-These are super thin strips of pastrami.
It boosts the salad by twenty percent.
-Mom, really...
You didn't bring pickles?
This stuff is delicious.
Shai, why did you say they're Arabs?
It's that guy from that movie.
-Which guy?
That guy from the movie about Jaffa?
-Is that him?
I've seen that movie.
It's that young guy who keeps getting into trouble.
There are a lot of issues in that movie.
-I once had a thing with the director of that movie.
Adam, there are kids here.
-I'm just going to have a word with him.
Are you crazy?
-No, but I'm a bit hungry.
You realize that we totally messed up, that stuff they serve there.
Tell me, what's wrong with you? There are kids listening.
That's the one with her thing and that's the one with his crap.
There's a teenager here. He's getting all moody now.
Wait, where's Raz?
What’s going on? Raz!
What, he was here?
-Of course he was here.
Raz! Raz!
He disappeared.
Salaam aleikum.
-Aleikum salaam.
Shabbat shalom.
-Is that really you?
Listen, just seeing you makes me laugh.
What now?
-What?
Let me guess. You forgot to bring meat too.
-No.
Good! Excellent. Very funny. No, no, not that.
I came to talk to you about the movie.
-The movie?
Yeah, you're the one from that, right? The one from...
-Yeah, that's me.
That's it. Look, I'm not racist. Quite the opposite.
But, listen, the way you portrayed the Arab characters...
Come on, you're Muslim, right?
-I'm Christian.
Sorry.
-For what?
I thought you were Arab.
I am Arab.
-Arab?
Well, I mean a good Arab.
Not good evening. You're H., right?
I thought the mom was from the banuela.
From the big bowl.
Thanks, thanks.
Maybe a wolf got him?
Honey, we're not in Little Red Riding Hood's forest.
He should be around here.
-Do you think it's because I got mad at him?
How would I know? Raz!
-He couldn't have gone far.
You all have phones. Go look for him.
I'll stay here with the girls.
-And what if a wolf comes?
See what you did?
-See? All this could have been avoided
if you had just let me find the right place.
Okay, I want to split up now.
I don't think I know how to do that.
-Adam.
You and I will go together. Come on.
-Okay.
Raz!
'Rach
So tasty. I hope
you don't mind me saying Allah.
You all believe in the old one.
Say, didn't something happen at your table?
Probably something silly that will end in five minutes.
-Come on, go check.
Give me more of the pickles. Oh, from the sour ones.
What’s released won’t be returned.
Raz!
Okay, now that we're alone,
who was that?
-Azban.
Not leaving.
There was this Iris I came with when I was a kid...
You're lying.
-How do you know?
Human polygraph. Who was she?
Okay, the kid's in danger. We can't let a wolf eat him. Raz!
Raz!
-Because the wolf will eat you! Aha!
Ran away
Wow, Itamar, I feel awful.
-Come on, babe, enough.
I told you, I don't think
it happened because of you. Enough!
You don't get it, I said first
I wish he would just disappear.
Honey, do you know how many awful
things I've said? They never come true.
You don't understand that everything
we say has meaning,
even if we're not aware of it
when we say it?
Okay, babe, enough. I can't deal with your philosophy anymore.
I'm hot, my son's lost in the woods,
and you know what? Probably my fault.
-Okay?
Raz!
Ran away
Ugh...
Raz!
Maybe we should call security
to come rescue us?
Us?
You should've told me
you can't wear shoes like that.
Okay, um... listen,
I think we need to talk.
About what?
We really messed up, this sucks. Where is everyone?
They went to look for Raz.
Okay, I'm starting to heat up the food.
Need help?
-I've been heating food for forty years.
It'll be ready in five minutes.
Raz!
Ran away
And this too. Raz!
Raz!
And the fact that your mom shoved pastrami into the...
Well, it's pretty awful here.
It really is awful here. Good thing...
We went on a trip and broke the routine.
It really is here, here.
Does it seem to you like it got a bit cooler?
Ugh, what a silly thing I'm ruining
such a nice day, huh?
What have I been trying to tell you since morning, babe?
There's some weird energy here but... a good kind.
Sorry I acted like pastrami.
Here he is.
-Here he is.
Look at that, he's not even aware.
Where are you?
-Did you look for me?
Wow, babe, don't be mad at him.
He was just playing. So cute.
You're right. Come here, sweetie. Come on. Let's eat.
Wow, there's so much oxygen here.
Makes me hungry. Let's move?
The energy here is good, huh?
We should've had the picnic here.
Say, babe, is there a chance your tree is here?
No, no.
Alright, let's go.
We just need to find Adam and his baby.
-Nerds?
There they are! Come on, come on already.
The shleikler is cooling down.
No, I'm dying. Are you grilling shleikler?
No, no, it's really delicious here.
I promise you.
Shabbat shalom.
-Ah, salam aleikum...
Aleikum salam.
-Yeah.
Are you one of the guys over there?
Yeah. Maybe you happen to have some sugar?
Who goes on a picnic without sugar?
Wait, why don't you sit with us since you're already here?
Eat some shleikler with us.
-Sure...
No, no. My mom will just kill me.
She made a lot...
-I know exactly what you mean.
You know, nothing beats a picnic
for mother-son bonding.
Once, at a picnic, Shai carved a heart on a tree.
With the text "Mom."
Mom is the best.
No way.
-How did I know you'd laugh,
but you weren't in that specific spot.
The energy there was really, really good.
Honestly, for "Shai loves Mom"
you need crazy energy.
Tell me, where are Adam and that girl?
-Thanks. Thanks.
It's really beautiful here. Feels nice.
So... what did you want to talk to me about?
You know what, forget talking.
Babe, I'm so happy we're chilling.
-It's better than being stuck at home with them.
They can hear us.
-Where? He's got headphones on.
And the little one, even if she tells something,
her mom won't understand a word she's saying.
You left that girl in the woods?
-She saw that director guy showed up
for that picnic of that guy,
so she went over there.
-So you left her there?
I think that's more obvious
than "Look, it's not you. It's me."
Can we stop at a pharmacy?
Birdman.
-The woods drained their energy.
Yeah.
Honestly, the shleikler is really better grilled, right?
Now there's another place I know
that has really good energy.
Come on, let's go there.
-Oh no, where to now?
To our bed at home.
If you had been looking, it would have happened
faster, you know.
Babe, come on, maybe we should stay here?
-I can't believe it, maybe it got deleted.
Maybe we should stay?
-Maybe there was a fire here.
Damn it.
You did it on purpose.
-What breaks.
Give me that.
Please.
Just seeing you makes me laugh.
Ar...
I have a line here. Right?
Yeah, you need to say I came for the meat.
Can we stop at a pharmacy?
Orchid?
-Go!
Addis Ababa?
-No.
Igabibi Yakubu?
Entebbe operation?