Quiet ride today, huh?
Let's hope it's not the calm before the storm.
What are they doing?
-One's sitting and the other's drawing.
Go ahead.
-I’m done.
Wow, that's beautiful, honey.
Look, Dad, how pretty she’s drawing.
Wow, lovely.
-Lovely. You really draw beautifully.
Thanks.
-The genius girl.
It’s not "genius," it’s "genius."
It’s a title, like doctor.
You don’t say "doctora."
Honey, you know what we’ll do?
When we get to Grandma's, we’ll give her the drawing as a gift,
and then she’ll hang it on the fridge,
so everyone can see how beautifully you draw.
Sit down, sit down, honey. Why are you promising
the girl things you can’t keep?
What?
-My mom doesn’t like to hang drawings on the fridge.
It messes up her decor.
-What decor?
"The aesthetics of the fridge," she calls it.
You know how many times, as a kid,
I brought her drawings to hang on the fridge and she...
I want to see her not hang
her granddaughter's drawing on the fridge.
No, really, I want to see
her say "no" to the girl.
There goes the quiet.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Oh, Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, my darlings.
-Shabbat Shalom, Pinchas.
Shabbat Shalom, Shai. How’s it going?
-As usual, everything’s fine.
Riki in the kitchen?
-As usual.
Come on, girls, come give Grandma the drawing.
Oh, look who’s here. Hey.
-Shabbat Shalom, Grandma.
Shai, don’t call me Grandma, I have a name.
Oh, sorry. Hi, Riki.
-Hi, Shai.
Tamari and Michal are on their way here and Adam...
is bringing a new girl he says is serious this time.
Sure.
-Sure.
Dad.
-Yes?
As a kid...
were my drawings really that ugly?
Great, I told Mom
that one day it would come back to haunt us.
Who’s haunting? Just asking.
-Your drawings were very pretty, Shai.
They just didn’t fit the aesthetics
of the fridge. New one. Every week a new one.
I promised myself this time
I won’t even ask what her name is.
I don’t care if it’s serious or not. Not asking.
Who are you talking about?
-About the one Adam is bringing this week.
Why should I bother?
Next week he’ll bring a new one anyway.
Why should I even bother?
-For politeness.
At my age, there’s no politeness - at my age, there’s prostate
-Okay.
Look what we brought you.
Yes
a drawing.
Here.
The girl drew on the way and we thought
maybe you’d hang it on the fridge.
Oh.
-What happened? Is it not pretty?
No, no, no. It’s pretty,
and
it’s, it’s lovely. Really.
Well, then hang it.
-Where?
On the fridge.
Are you sure you want me
to hang this drawing on the fridge?
Yes, I’m sure, Riki.
-Okay.
I want everyone to see
how beautifully my granddaughter draws.
Okay. I’m already hanging it,
so everyone can see how... it’s, it’s clear.
Excuse me?
-What?
Mom says you were a wild one before the wedding too.
-Wild, wild.
You know Mom, she’s overdoing it.
How much?
-Forget it.
-Shai.
Dad.
-Shh.
Shh?
-There was a redemption, everyone called her Geula.
There was Tzipi, a sister who loved to give.
-No need...
There was Ruthie, a kibbutznik
who worked in the dairy and loved to milk.
Enough, Dad, enough, enough. No need...
-Wait, you haven't heard about Gila yet.
But I understood.
-You haven't heard about Gila who was a flutist
and loved her magic flute.
-No. Enough. Stop. Enough.
At least you can’t complain about Adam.
-Not complaining, just jealous.
What? What are they talking about?
-About me and the...
his prostate.
-Lovely. Sabbath delight.
Your mom hung the drawing on the fridge like a trophy.
-Really?
Lucky.
-The luck is all hers. All hers.
I’m going to check
if Mom needs help with something.
What? So it turns out my mom
does hang drawings on the fridge?
Turns out.
-So what, were my drawings too ugly?
Rivka, do you need something?
-I need a lot of things. So what?
Are you going to give them to me? No. Just look for a second.
-At what?
At the fridge.
-We’re not buying a new fridge.
At the drawing on the fridge.
-Oh, that’s Shai’s little one.
Let it go.
-What do you think of the drawing?
It’s a drawing by a little girl.
In an hour, you’ll put it aside
and in a week, you’ll throw it in the trash, Riki.
What do you think of the drawing itself?
Artistically?
-Yeah, Rembrandt, artistically.
No. Psychologically.
What psychologically? It’s a drawing by a little girl.
Come on, doesn’t the mom in the drawing look like a monster to you?
The mom? Rivka, let’s not get carried away.
It’s... maybe the girl didn’t mean it,
maybe we don’t understand?
-What’s there to understand?
It’s right in front of our eyes.
Drawn in panda colors on paper
on my shiny fridge.
You never know.
-Pinchas, I don’t want them to say
that the writing was on the fridge
and we did nothing.
What’s that? What do you see?
-Come on, give it to me, you annoying one.
I don’t know, looks like a cooking show or something.
-Cooking? Then why are there
a singer and half-naked dancers?
-I don’t know, maybe it makes the food taste better.
Shabbat Shalom.
Hey. Shabbat Shalom.
-What’s up?
Where’s Mom? Is there food? I’m starving. Mom!
Shh, what’s this? Is everyone already here?
-No, Adam hasn’t arrived.
I want to tell you something but only
when everyone is here. I’m so excited.
Why are you yelling like that? What happened? I was already worried.
Is there food? I’m starving. When are we eating?
When was the last time you came to this house and there wasn’t food?
I just wanted to be sure. Mom, I’m hungry.
Tell me, why aren’t you making him food?
Why does he have to get to this point?
It’s not healthy.
-How did this happen to me? What did I do?
Not enough, apparently.
Schnitzels?
-Yeah, son.
Since when?
-Since two weeks ago.
I found it by chance in the fridge and decided to serve it.
-Really?
No. When was the last time
you ate a not-fresh schnitzel in this house?
Okay, why are you being annoying? I just wanted to be sure.
I’m going to get a schnitzel.
-I’ll come with you because you won’t find it.
What’s up? Michali?
-Michali has something to tell us.
But she's waiting for Adam to come.
-You're pregnant.
I told Pinchas
that there's no way you gained that much weight.
You must be pregnant.
-I'm not pregnant.
What, I gained weight?
-No, no. Not at all.
What do you mean?
-Just in your body.
But this way there's proportion, with the head.
Because you have a really big head.
I have a big head?
Itamar, look. What do you see?
-What is it?
It's a drawing that Shai's little one made. Look.
I can't believe it. Since when does Mom allow
hanging drawings on the fridge?
No, not that. Look at the content of the drawing.
What do you think about the psychological stuff
hidden behind this drawing?
What, is that Shabi?
-I think so. What do you say?
The girls seem sad here. Did you notice?
-No, I didn't notice.
Shabi's teeth confused me.
-Yeah. A bit.
That's not good.
So, this lamp is done for. Done.
I hope you left me some schnitzels, yeah.
-Yeah, there's plenty.
Just don't finish them off. I'm starving.
I'm going back to the living room because Mom's on the attack.
Your wife is the target, by the way.
What can I do? I told her
not to look Mom in the eyes.
It's okay, it'll toughen her up.
-Or it might kill her.
What do you think? Should I say something to him?
-I don't know what to tell you, Dad.
So don't say anything?
-See? That's exactly
why I don't encourage
my kids to be creative.
-What, they don't draw at all?
They don't draw, don't write
and don't sculpt with Play-Doh.
I don't need them digging up stuff from their subconscious.
They should focus on practical subjects.
I do kickboxing, Pilates, and spinning.
And I go to Zumba three times a week.
Michali, honey, it's a waste of your effort.
It's a matter of genetics.
Your mom has a big head too.
My mom has a big head?
-It's okay. It happens.
What are you doing?
I want to join too.
-Aren't you too big?
You're right. I need a drawing from when I was little.
Really big head.
-My head's not big, Riki.
My head is normal for my body.
-Okay, Michali, okay. Whatever you say.
Itamar...
So, what's up, Shabi?
-Everything's fine.
How's the little one in kindergarten?
-Actually, she's great. Really. Really.
Yeah?
-She also loves the teacher...
Actually, this week they did some kind of
paper mache with varnish...
Great. And how are you two, with each other?
Do you talk? Do you play together?
-Of course.
What, what do you mean? Riki, what are these questions?
Just, just wanted to know. It's...
Tell me, did you clean the house this week?
-Of course. What kind of question is that?
Just, just wanted to know.
Honey, do you think I have a big head?
Of course, honey.
-What?
What... you always lift the seat
in the bathroom after you go.
That's what I call a big head.
-No, not like that, honey.
Physically big.
-What, my mom...
Forget it, her sense of proportion is completely off.
You're perfectly fine for your body, honey.
-Thanks, honey.
Are you done with that?
Michal, you dabble a bit in psychology, right?
Yeah, but I can't talk
about that right now. I'm saving the message.
Later, everyone.
-Yeah, yeah, sure, but look,
What do you think about this?
-What is this drawing?
It's Shai's little one who drew it.
-No way, I'm dying.
What?
-What, it's a really disturbing drawing.
The kid looks terrified.
-No, I'm going to call Shai.
No, no, no, wait, wait, wait.
We need to handle this very gently.
Damn, I wish I had my Barbie collection here.
That would really help me out.
She has a Barbie collection?
-Forget it, Dad. Just forget it.
Alright, I forgot.
You don't give the girls good whacks like that?
-Of course not.
Wait, are you telling me
you never lay a hand on them,
a flip-flop, a rolled-up newspaper?
-What are you talking about?
Riki, you really overdid it this time.
I don't hit my girls.
Okay. What happened? It's not shameful.
Kids can be really annoying at that age.
Itamar, for example, I wanted
to kill him when he was that age.
Just kill him.
-Yeah, but you didn't kill him. Right?
Right. I'm really sorry.
He still manages to annoy me.
K'
Mom `
.Batzay
Y
Mom, oh no
The pickles,
did you make them or are they from a jar?
See? Kill him. Just kill him.
Sit down, come here for a sec.
-They're from a jar.
Is it in vinegar or salt?
Itamar, please go get me a rolled-up newspaper.
See?
-Who is that? You and Itamar when you were little?
Before Adam was born. But that's not important.
Look here, on the drawing. Here, behind us.
Wow, a drawing.
That I drew.
ֵHere
You know, it looks a bit like the drawing...
Exactly. So I was a genius too.
So why didn't she want to hang my drawings?
Tell me, what are you, spaced out?
You know your mom asked me
if I hit the girls?
ֵBeni
Come on, I want
to finish this and go home. Enough.
So yeah?
-Shh.
I think they're listening...
-What?
Michal, you said you wanted to tell him something?
Yeah, babe, come on, let's tell Adam later.
What happened, babe?
-Yeah? Okay. Alright.
Wow, I can't believe it, I'm so excited.
So babe, you can. Come on, get to it, babe,
get to it.
-Okay, okay, alright.
I hope it's not another pair
of new shoes she bought
because that would really annoy me.
Rivka, let the girl speak.
-Thanks, Pinchas.
Okay, so like this. So as
you know, in recent years I've been...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Adam.
Meet Michal.
You told me she’s divorced but no, I didn’t connect the dots.
No, at that moment my sukkah's covering flew away. I'm exposed
and mostly dying.
-Babe, control yourself. Okay?
You didn't tell them, huh, B'la?
-Isn't it fun to surprise?
Very much, I'm Michal.
-Yeah, we know,
Michal Amadoreski. Hello.
I hope I remember. I'm Pinchas, very nice.
Is this a cooking show?
-Babe, Shai. His brother.
Big problem.
-What... what... what's going on?
Yeah, hey, hey. Adam, what's up?
I need to have a quick chat with you
in the kitchen, so if you could just...
Sure, go ahead.
-Come on.
Don't bother her too much.
-Why would we bother her?
What, are we animals? Come on, sit down.
Thanks.
-Sit.
No, I'm dying. You're dating Adam?
-Michal, chill out.
I read that you're dating the... the... son.
Pinchas, what's the kid's name?
-Is this a cooking show?
Hello, hello, hello. What’s this? What, are you a kid?
What, are you a kid?
-What’s wrong with you?
I'll tell you what I don't have.
I don't have a celeb dating us.
No. I don't have one. No celeb. No.
-What do you want?
Spill it, share, report.
What? What?
-Where? How? Why?
Give details, explain, give examples.
If there are pictures on the phone, it’ll be in the gallery.
You guys are nuts.
-Of course we're nuts. We're in shock.
Spill it!
-We met at a party, talked, went out.
No pictures.
-Liar!
I'm asking you, don’t embarrass me, okay?
Actually...
We wanted her.
With me it’s not a problem, but with Itamar...
you know him.
What about Itamar? Sorry, I'm the one who dated a celeb.
Yeah? The beauty queen of Ramat Gan is not a celeb.
In Ramat Gan, everyone knows her.
True.
Your hair looks really nice like that.
-Thanks.
Wow, I can’t believe we’re
just sitting here like friends.
Friends...
-Don’t mind her,
she doesn’t go out much.
Girls, can we have a little quiet? I'm trying
to watch dancers prepare lamb.
Pinchas, we have a guest here. Turn off
the TV. It’s rude.
Okay, done.
-It’s fine, you can leave it on.
I like this show too.
-So what...
Does Adam treat you well?
-Adam treats me really well.
Great. What do you do?
-Oh, Pinchas...
No, it’s fine.
-I’m trying to be polite to the guest. You asked.
You know, I’m involved in all sorts of things.
Yeah. But what? What? You wake up in the morning, what do you do?
Where are you going?
-I wake up in the morning and then...
Either I have meetings or shoots...
-Shoots. X-ray technician. Got it.
At "Maccabi" or "Clalit"?
-I’m at "Maccabi" and it’s really not related.
Good, nice, good job. Can we go back to the lamb?
Pinchas!
-No, I’m totally dying.
Don’t mind him, he’s a simple guy.
He’s from the village.
Do you think we can calm Mom down?
You made me laugh. Mom's in full-on panic mode.
Yeah, huh?
-Come on.
We're coming. Adam, Adam, check out this drawing for a sec.
What do you think?
-What is it?
This is Shai's little one who drew it.
The parents are stressed.
-Who’s that in the drawing? Is that Shavi?
I think so.
-The drawing is a bit scary.
A bit scary?
-Isn’t it?
The first time I saw it, I almost peed myself.
Because her hands are a bit scary, they’re like...
-Scary!
Edmika, your friend is lovely.
Just lovely.
-Right?
A celebrity, huh, Mom?
-Oh, Itamar,
I'm not that superficial. I can tell the difference.
She's just a wonderful person. Classy.
Not for you, but classy.
-Thanks, Mom.
Itamar, you finished all the schnitzels.
Everyone ate them.
-Get out of my kitchen. Both of you. Now.
Dad, the TV is perfectly fine.
I don't get what the problem is.
No, you know how Mom is with her nonsense.
It's not sharp enough, so she wants to replace the TV.
Speaking of sharp, how's Shabi?
No, I didn't get the connection
but Shabi's doing great. Why?
Just curious. After all, she's the bride,
I want to know if everything's okay
with her, with you guys. I mean,
if you're not fighting, say.
She's not taking it out on the girls, right?
Dad, only Stanley Fischer is "say." Got it?
Everything's fine with her, everything's fine
with me, and everything's fine with the girls.
What's up with you, Bgid?
-No, it's just Mom with her quirks.
So that's why you brought me here?
Amdursky's sitting in the living room,
and I'm here on a wild goose chase?
-That girl from Ramat Gan, is her name Amdursky?
I've already forgotten.
-Funny.
Wow, if I had known you were coming,
I would have put in a bit more effort with my clothes.
You look lovely.
-What, this? I just threw something on.
Michali, can you tilt
your head a bit to the right?
You're blocking my view of the guest.
-Mom, enough.
Your new hair is stunning.
-Thanks.
What hair? In the health fund magazine?
No, Pinchas, the hair with the little swimsuit.
Why would an X-ray technician pose in a tiny swimsuit?
I'm not an X-ray technician.
-Oh, are you in the internship stage?
Pinchas, you don't know what you're talking about?
Of course I know who I'm...
I'm not senile yet.
With Adam's girlfriend.
-It's fine, Pinchas. Nothing happened.
Where's the bathroom?
At the end of the hallway. Everything okay?
Of course it's okay. You know,
I need to use the bathroom sometimes too.
Run before it gets away from you.
-Shai. His brother.
I don't remember if...
-Shai.
Tell me, Pinchas, you really don't know her?
I didn't get it. Is she famous?
Pinchas, sometimes I ask myself:
Where did you find her?
Dad, it's fine. Guys,
she's a person. Just like us.
Just that she looks better,
much, much better.
You remember I'm sitting here, right?
-Yeah, honey, you look good too.
Hey, Michali, we're all here now.
You said you wanted to share something.
Oh, right. Okay, okay, okay.
What do you mean "famous"? What is she famous for?
Don't you see Michali
wants to tell us something exciting?
Oh, right. Sorry. Go ahead.
-So, like this, in recent years...
Do you think she's managing in the bathroom?
-I think she's managing.
No, really. Maybe we should check.
-Okay, can I? Just a sec.
Yes, yes—
-Okay, so like this, in recent years,
as you know...
-There you are, back. How was it?
Routine. Your home is lovely.
-Thanks.
Really, I keep telling
Pinchas we need to renovate
but he doesn't want to, he says it's not necessary.
Come on, come on, I'll show you the kitchen.
Give her a schnitzel.
-Okay.
You haven't had one like this.
-Mom...
Sit down, come to my parents' room for a sec.
I want to show you something.
I changed the sheets.
_Refreshing
Just in case you wanted to know.
So what’s she famous for?
Did she invent something? Did she win an award?
Is she an actress? A dancer? A host?
-All of the above, Pinchas.
You're really embarrassing me. Seriously.
After that, you wonder why I
don’t want to go out with you anywhere.
What’s going on?
-That’s what I’m asking you.
What am I missing here?
-I don’t know.
In your family, nothing
can surprise me anymore.
Except for Adam’s new girlfriend. She’s pretty healthy, huh?
Totally.
-Shai, be careful.
You said it.
-I’m allowed.
How sweet.
-I apologize for the...
I apologize for my family.
-Come on, Adam, don’t be stupid.
Besides, the warnings about your mom
were totally exaggerated.
No, really. She seems like a really nice woman.
Ah, I’m glad. Cool.
What’s this painting?
-Oh, sorry.
I hope I’m not interrupting.
-No, not at all.
Say, whose painting is that on the fridge?
It’s Shai’s daughter’s.
-Oh.
Are you telling me?
Here you are.
-Oh my.
Shai. Shai.
Sh.
Okay, is everyone here?
-Yeah.
So can I finally announce?
-Go, baby, go.
Okay, so after three weeks, I finally
finished the art therapy course.
Wow.
-Wow.
That’s really wonderful news.
-Thanks.
So what, Michal, are you studying something?
-Actually, no one knows about it.
But I have a bachelor’s degree in psychology.
D.
-Wow, wow.
Speaking of psychology, can I
talk about the painting on the fridge for a sec?
Of course. Nice, huh?
-Look, there’s a problem here.
The painting is cloudy and dark. The kids are small and crying.
The dominant figure is dark and big
with long nails and sharp teeth.
I’d say the mom in the painting
is kind of... a monster.
I’m not saying that.
That’s what someone with a
bachelor’s degree in psychology says.
My sweet girl, who’s in the painting?
Grandma Raanan.
It’s not that you don’t paint well, sweetie,
it’s just that Grandma doesn’t like
to hang the painting on the fridge
because she thinks the fridge
looks better without it.
It’s called “fridge design.”
What does she call it?
Fridge aesthetics.
-The aesthetics of the fridge.
You’ll understand that when you grow up.
Yeah, you paint just like
Dad did when he was your age.
Of course. Because you had the same model.
It also doesn’t leave room. I’m speaking from experience.
You can live with it, honey.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Pinchas.
Shabbat Shalom, Riki.
I’m not Riki.
-Isn’t that Riki?
Painting. The daughter...
-The daughter... the girl painted at kindergarten
and we thought she... that it...
-No, she painted this in the car just now.
Right, why am I changing the setup?
So what, Michal
-Amidorsky.
Are you learning something?
Your mom hung the trip on the fridge... the trip.
Your mom hung the drawing on the fridge... sorry.
Schnitzels?
!Shai
-Oh no.
None?
-No.
Okay
let's take a break
there's nothing.
Fine, I just wanted to say.
-You confused her.
Hey, are there schnitzels?