What’s this? Look at all the police cars!
-Good thing they're going the other way.
What’s good? They’re headed towards my parents' place.
The good thing is we’re not going to your parents'.
There’s no traffic towards my parents'.
-Really.
Well, who knows, maybe it’s some
police conference or "Police Day."
Friday night? What, are they doing Kiddush?
"On the sixth day, the heavens
and the earth and all their hosts..."
Who knows, maybe something happened, God forbid.
Ron.
Bar
!m
.Room.
n
ROVl M 'bo'
Did you know my dream used to be to be a cop?
-Really.
I even learned Krav Maga
to disarm someone with a gun.
Sounds like a nightmare to me.
-Why?
The police have come a long way
since the days of Officer Azulai.
I don’t know why. I can’t picture you
in a police uniform. It’s funny.
I think if you were in the police,
they’d give you your own district,
District Sh'.
-Very funny.
Soon I’ll stop you for insulting a public servant.
What, I insulted you, babe?
-Just a little, yeah.
You can get out of the car
since all the streets are empty now,
the alleys are all yours.
He’s running over there.
Did you see anything?
-"Lighter," here "cigarette,"
"Lighter," here "cigarette."
We urgently need fire.
I repeat: we urgently need fire.
Wow, what tension.
-What nonsense.
Things like this only happen on TV.
-No, it’s not nonsense,
it happens in real life too. Read the papers.
Tell me, those shows,
are they based on reality or TV?
It’s really intense.
-What do you mean?
What’s this? Who are you?
-Don’t move!
No, you see I’m not.
-Quiet.
Be careful.
Leave him alone!
-Quiet! Sit down.
What are you, a thief?
-No, I’m not a thief.
Quiet. I don’t want to hear a word.
Any suspicious move from you,
I’ll blow everything up. Got it?
Be careful, I’m telling you, be careful, I’m warning you.
I’m sure everything’s fine.
-Yeah. Sure.
What are the odds this is related to my mom?
-Exactly.
Look at me, look at me and...
Sali, do something.
-What do you want me to do?
He said quiet so...
I don’t need help, thank you very much. Quiet now.
Mr. Thief, do me a favor, take whatever you want,
just let us go. Look, it’s time.
First of all, I told you, I’m not a thief.
I wasn’t focused.
I’m between jobs right now.
-Ah, right.
Now be quiet. If you listen to me,
everything will be fine.
How will it be fine? It sounds
like all of Israel's police are down there
!Interpol too! And the FBI...
You want him to blow us up?
The instructions are as follows: if the police come in here,
you don’t give me up at any cost. Got it?
-Got it.
For you, I’m part of the family.
Then everything will be fine.
But if one of you sings...
-No way...
I’ll blow everything up. Is that clear?
Clear.
-Clear.
Great. I’m glad you accepted me into your family.
Well, you don't choose your family.
Shh...
-What shh?
What, are we just going to sit here and wait for the police to arrive?
We can have dinner.
Mr. Gabb... uh... between jobs.
Excuse me, hello.
It's Friday night. I really, really would like
to make Kiddush for Shabbat.
Hands up! You're surrounded!
What is that? Who is it?
-Not that... sorry, TV.
What's going on? Why do they always say to come
early and then everyone is late?
That's Shai. He never shows up late.
Come on, really, Rivka.
-Shai wouldn't leave me alone like this.
Rivka, you're not alone.
-Okay, I need to go,
so if they're not coming, I'm eating and leaving.
Adam, you're not a street kid. Even when there's a meal,
the whole family sits together and eats.
-Let him eat and go.
Maybe he's in a hurry?
-Shabbat Shalom!
Oh, Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Already creating a fuss. Where have you been?
-No, everything's fine, everything's fine.
We're sorry for being late.
There were just so many police and checkpoints.
Okay, let's eat. Adam's in a hurry.
He has to leave the house.
Hurry or he'll lose his mind.
-What's the rush?
On Fridays, there are only flowers in the streets.
I'm going to tidy up.
-What's the rush?
I was invited to dinner.
-The pretty one...
Someone's parents.
-Since when do you go to someone's parents?
Forget it, bro, we're talking about a family
sitting on so much money
that sometimes Shari Arison babysits for them.
Wow...
Get a grip.
Good morning. There's so much police outside. Did you see?
Why didn't you tell me there was someone here?
Hey, who are you?
-He's the reason all the police are downstairs.
What do you mean? What's going on?
-This is Merav, our daughter.
She lives here. This is Mr. Thief.
Why? Why like this? He's not a thief,
he's between jobs.
-So who are you?
I have a feeling they're going to come through here,
checking house by house,
so for this purpose, if the police come to check,
I'm your friend.
-Friend?
Merav, that's only if the police show up.
-Then I'm going to take a shower.
No showering, sit here in the living room and be quiet.
-What, is this a kidnapping?
Sit here, I'm telling you.
-I'm sweating like crazy.
No way I'm staying in the living room like this.
-Sit!
What is that? What did you do?
-A tranquilizer dart.
What?
-It's just a tranquilizer dart.
And she'll be okay?
-Yeah, she'll sleep for about ten minutes,
after that everything will be fine.
Where do you get something like that?
Okay, I'm going to call,
tell my parents Shabbat Shalom
and check that everything's okay.
Okay, everything's ready. Can we start?
This is the last time there are delays.
The schnitzels are getting cold! People are getting heated...
Okay. Enough, Rivka. I think the message got through.
It got through, but maybe it didn't register?
There are areas around the globe
where the reception is a bit problematic.
Speaking of problematic, where's Shabi?
-She's calling her parents
to check that nothing happened and to say Shabbat Shalom.
Can’t we wait until after dinner?
It's fine, she usually calls
before dinner, she doesn’t want them to wait.
Oh, so they don’t wait.
Okay, fine, we’ll wait.
Alone.
In the dark.
-Exactly.
Excuse me for a moment.
"Who loves Shabbat..."
Who's that from?
It's from Shai, our daughter.
Okay, you can answer normally,
no need for extra words.
And no sharp movements.
Put it on speaker.
Hello.
-Hey, Mom, what’s up?
Everything’s fine. And you?
-Everything’s good,
we’re here at the parents'. They’re waiting for me for Kiddush,
I called to wish you a Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
Is everything okay? Because when we drove here
we saw a lot of police cars
heading your way. Did something happen?
No, no. Everything’s fine here. It’s completely quiet.
Meirav, hang up.
-Okay. Alright, Mom, we’ll see you tomorrow.
Shai, there won’t be any mishap tomorrow.
What happened?
-Nothing happened.
Okay, so we’ll see you tomorrow.
And give my regards
to Shai.
And warm kisses to Riki.
-Okay.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Bye.
What happened?
-Very strange.
She sent kisses to your mom.
It must have slipped out. Regards and kisses go together.
No, that’s not all.
-Shai, do me a favor,
my mom is waiting alone, in the dark.
She also said there won’t be any mishap tomorrow.
-Why? Is she sick or something?
I don’t know. Shai, honey, it worries me,
but forget it, don’t make a big deal out of it,
your mom is already upset.
Does anyone have any arrangements
before we start Kiddush?
No, no, we can start.
"On the sixth day, the heavens and the earth
and all their hosts were finished..."
One-way street. Great.
He won’t be able to escape from here.
No problem.
-"Cigarettes," here "lighter,"
"Cigarettes," here "lighter."
I don’t want any smoke coming from the area.
Repeat, no smoke. There’s permission to open fire. End.
What happened here?
Mr. Thief, is she waking up?
-What was that?
He shot me with a tranquilizer dart.
-What?
How did you let him do that to me?
He took advantage of me? Dad, I’m your daughter.
What did he do to me? Did he touch me?
How did you let him, Dad?
What... you won’t tell me where to get something like that?
Who is it?
This is my daughter, Orna.
-You can answer.
Same procedure. No unnecessary words, speaker.
Hello.
-Hello, Mom, Shabbat Shalom.
What’s going on?
-Everything’s fine. Shabbat Shalom.
How’s Dad?
-Everything’s fine.
Great. Okay, see you tomorrow.
Orna, I didn’t arrange for mishap tomorrow.
What?
-So we’ll see you tomorrow.
Send my regards to Moshe
and warm kisses to his mom.
-Bye.
Because
"Yachin
Great.
Who's that?
That's my son, Manny.
Same procedure: no messing around, Shabbat Shalom, speaker.
Hello.
-Hello, Mom.
Hey, Shabbat Shalom.
How's it going?
-Everything's fine here.
I'm not doing any messing around tomorrow.
-What?
Send my regards to Alon and warm kisses to his mom.
Okay, bye.
-Bye.
Alright. So, who’s this now?
My daughter, Efrat.
-How many kids do you have? So...
Hello.
-Hello, Mom.
Efrat?
Yes.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Everything's fine here.
What, a lot of money?
-A lot.
Those who don’t know what to do with it.
-What do you mean?
For example, they have
a special and exotic dinner
with all sorts of fancy dishes.
-You know, I'm really worried.
What, because of the messing around tomorrow?
-Yeah.
I should be the one worried,
I was counting on the messing around.
She's a good girl, trust me,
so what are you eating at her exclusive dinner?
I know... I think you'll understand.
Yuck.
-You don’t say yuck about food.
You don’t call food yuck.
-It's really weird, I'm telling you.
Maybe something happened?
-Nothing happened,
I'm sure everything's fine.
She's probably just a bit tired. What...
I'm worried.
-So when do you need to leave?
Don’t be late. She’s from a family that
doesn’t like tardiness.
Turns out the dinner was canceled.
It's nice that all the kids are calling for Shabbat.
Yeah, we have good kids.
I was born in prison.
My parents are from two different prisons.
What a gut-wrenching story...
What did you do that everyone’s chasing you?
-I broke into the safari.
Who's that?
-That's my daughter, Shavi.
What, do you have so many kids
that you accidentally called two Shavi?
Same procedure.
Yeah, Shavi, what's up?
-Mom, are you guys mad at us about something?
No, God forbid.
-So everything's fine.
Everything's perfectly fine.
-So why isn’t there any messing around tomorrow?
Oh no.
Shavi, Dad and I are
watching an action movie on TV.
See you tomorrow and...
Yeah, and don’t... don’t forget kisses for Riki.
Okay.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Momma. Bye.
-So, everything's okay?
No, not at all. I can’t
figure out what's wrong with her.
What did she tell you?
-She’s not saying anything,
she says there’s no messing around tomorrow and that everything's fine.
That’s it, no explanations.
-Do you want me to call them?
No, I want to go there.
Now?
-Of course.
But you can’t. What do you want,
for my mom to go on a barricade?
My dear, I don’t care if the barricade goes on a barricade.
My mom’s not feeling well.
I want to go check what's going on.
With what excuse?
-Just tell her the truth. What excuse?
Tell her they called and there's some
issue and she can't hear well,
We're going to check.
-What issue?
That we're faking tomorrow?
Come on, really, what can't she hear?
Oudi, tell her my mom sends her kisses.
Okay. That really doesn't sound good.
-Ah.
That's it, I'm not taking any more calls. Got it?
You said Shabbat Shalom to everyone.
Except for me, I didn't call.
But I'm already here, so there's no point in me calling.
I'm not calling and they're not calling.
I'm sure at this point
your parents are happy.
He's insulting me.
Leave it.
Who is it?
-Police. Please open up.
Say "wait."
-Wait.
Remember, it's just a regular Friday
and I'm your daughter's boyfriend.
Open up.
Wait, what's your name?
-What does it matter now?
Ehud. Open up.
-Wait. Ehud what?
I don't know? Ben, Ehud Barak. Okay?
Come on, come on.
-And how long have we been together?
Is our relationship serious? Is it going somewhere?
I think it’ll be easier for me
to explain to the cop why you're sitting.
Please open up.
Good evening.
-Good evening.
Have you seen anyone suspicious hanging around here in the building?
No, no, not at all.
We didn't see anyone. No one.
Do you have something in your eye?
-No, my eyes are perfectly fine.
Gentlemen, we're dealing with a cunning criminal,
very dangerous and low-life,
who has broken in several times
to the safari in Ramat Gan and stolen exotic animals.
We... we trust you, the police.
We trust your sharp instincts.
This is my new boyfriend,
he just came to meet the parents.
Ehud. But I call him Oudi.
We're getting married in the fall.
Good evening.
-Good evening to you too.
Well, sorry for interrupting,
have a nice and quiet rest of Shabbat
and if you see anything suspicious, call 100.
There's no doubt we'll call.
And good thing too.
-Thanks.
I told you the news
would worry even your mom.
I think you're just being hysterical. It's nothing, no faking.
It's not the faking, idiot.
Why are you calling me an idiot?
-Because you're an idiot.
What idiot? Friday night, my mom's freaking out,
and you're taking me to your mom's
just because she said there's no faking tomorrow?
What, does that seem normal?
Like, like
the fact that your mom's freaking out
seems totally normal to me.
Look at that, they're really
sending more forces over there.
Really, maybe something happened?
-I think there's a checkpoint there.
Maybe it's a terrorist on the run.
-They would have announced it on the radio.
Come on, and they didn't announce anything.
On the other hand, they should have announced
that there's no faking tomorrow too.
On the third hand, they should have announced that you're an idiot.
Did you see how naturally you told the cop
that you're my new boyfriend?
Meirav, you wouldn't really want to
be in a long-term relationship
with some prisoner or criminal.
No,
not that I think you're a criminal. Yeah.
In some cases, it can even be good.
He's in jail, you're at home,
no fights, no headaches.
I get that your wife gives you a lot of headaches. Huh?
No, no. You didn't understand what I said.
I was speaking in metaphors.
I always dreamed of being a hostage of a kidnapper like you.
Pinch me, babe.
-Hey, have you ever heard of "Stockholm Syndrome"?
What, what do you want?
-Stockholm Syndrome.
It's a syndrome where the hostage falls in love
or, in our case, falls in love with the kidnapper.
All she wants is for him to kidnap her!
For an unforgettable experience.
Do you want me to help you make a better meal here?
I don't know where you're getting
this syndrome from,
but from now on, be quiet.
-Fine.
He's definitely hiding here! Someone missed them.
Listen, the police chief is on his way
and his daughter loves the safari.
I need to give him smarter answers.
He's "connecting" on the way
or "matzot."
And closing y like
I want you to find that dirty ashtray
at all costs.
What’s going on? Why is there a police command center here?
Wow, wow, wow.
You can't enter. This is a crime scene.
What do you mean? You're blocking
the way to my parents' house.
I need to do laundry.
-You can't go in.
There's suspicion that the escaped criminal entered this building.
Escaped criminal? Armed?
We don't know too many details,
but we don't want to take unnecessary risks,
if you know what I mean.
-Of course I understand, I'm not stupid.
I got it too.
Look, she's not answering.
-She's not answering?
My mom isn't answering.
What’s this? What are you doing here?
-We called to say Shabbat Shalom,
Mom said there's no meziluf tomorrow.
It seemed strange, so we came.
She told us there's no meziluf either.
Hey, Orna, Moshe, and Shai,
what's going on here? Why is there police?
Mom told everyone there's no meziluf tomorrow. Did she tell you too?
Yeah, that's why we came.
-There's a criminal in the building.
Excuse me, are you all from the same family?
-Yeah.
And you all came because of the meziluf?
-Yeah!
Meziluf is a type of food.
Really great detective. Awesome.
All the cigarettes burning in the area,
has anyone of you come across... meziluf?
Sir, the tracker... the detective,
it's not meziluf day, it's tomorrow.
Usually, there's one every Saturday, and she told us there isn't,
so that's suspicious.
-What’s suspicious or not suspicious
is my job. Okay? I have an idea.
I need a volunteer.
Moshe... Moshe, move.
Tell me, have you heard dogs?
Yes or no?
You said to be quiet, so we're quiet.
-Okay, now we can talk.
Yes or no?
-It's the neighbor's dog, Gliksman.
Gliksman is the neighbor, not the dog.
They went away for the weekend,
and I promised to feed the dog,
so he's probably hungry.
-I'm hungry too.
Maybe you can let us do a kiddush, for heaven's sake.
Alright, hide the microphones
and set up two cameras for you,
in case one breaks.
Babe, you don't have to do this.
-I always dreamed of being a cop.
Ready to go live.
I feel a bit clumsy with all the...
These microphones and cameras.
Kind of like Channel One.
I hope the sound quality
and the response will be better.
Me too.
-Alright, let’s go. Good luck.
Just remember, you’re only
our eyes and ears out there.
Don’t do anything stupid
like trying to take him down yourself.
Of course not! What am I, an idiot?
I haven’t really had a chance to do Kiddush at my place.
I’ve always dreamed of family and Kiddush,
that Friday night vibe.
I never really got to experience it.
-That’s really sad.
Well, here you go, now you get to.
You’ll hear Kiddush and eat proper food.
See? You’ll get used to
loving my parents.
Meirav... Kiddush.
"On the sixth day, the heavens and the earth
and all their hosts were finished."
Same procedure.
Who is it?
-It’s me, Shai.
Shai?
-Shai is my son. His.
Another one? Open gently.
If not, I’ll blow everything up.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Son... his.
Dad, Mom, Shabbat Shalom.
Sister.
You see, everything’s fine there.
-Yeah, and who’s that?
That’s the sister’s fiancé, right?
Meet my new boyfriend, Ehud Barak.
Which Ehud Barak... is it, Ehud Barak.
Move
the
9)
Shvu
/שׁן. 'י'
Is he dangerous?
-Not more than the stuff we found in his car.
Get it?
Adam!
Everything will be fine if we act wisely.
-That’s what worries me.
Does anyone know why he chose
to come to Mom and Dad’s place?
Maybe because of the food.
-The food smells amazing.
Yeah. Can we please have Kiddush?
-Yes, yes, yes.
"On the sixth day, the heavens and the earth
and all...
-Cut it short.
Sabri Maranan-
-L'Chaim!
What’s that? What did you shoot me with?
Don’t worry, it’s a tranquilizer dart.
It wakes me up.
That’s it, let’s go, he’s neutralized.
Get into the apartment and stop him.
It wakes me up.
-Oh my God...
My eyes are shaking from him.
Kudos to your husband. Now I just hope
I can break this suspect during the interrogation
and find out where and to whom this was meant.
Don’t hurt him. He’s not that much of a monster.
I have a feeling I have some very exclusive and exotic info for you.
Where is he?
Honey, honey, are you okay?
He’s sleeping. Sleeping-
shnann, how I worried.
Did you set off a false alarm for them, huh?
False alarm red!
And for all those who were worried, there’s a false alarm tomorrow.
-And!
Alright, now that everyone’s here, let’s do Kiddush.
טוב, עכשיו, כשכולם כאן, אנחנו נעשה קידוש.
"It's Friday, and the heavens and the earth..."
Dad, you've done this already.
-Oh, really?
Boy Royal
Mo.
(House
n
e
Sabri Maranan.
"Sabri Maranan."
-Cheers!
Where is he?
Honestly, I think the Israeli police
lost a model officer.
Wow, babe, how did you handle him? What a waste of time.
What’s this? They say you broke his rib.
I think I deserve an apology for the "idiot."
Honestly, yes. You're really a hero,
I'm sorry, and I love you.
Hello, Mom.
-Shame on you, you and your bride,
for getting up and leaving in the middle of a meal.
You left the kids
alone here, in the dark, in such a catastrophic situation.
What was so urgent?
Mom, I'll tell you later what happened.
-Is someone dead?
No.
-Then I'm not obligated to listen.
This is not how a son who loves his mom behaves.
This is how an idiot behaves.
-It's chasing you.
We're almost there.
You know that if we went this week
to both your mom's and my mom's,
then next week we have a free Friday.
You think so?
Idiot.
I'm warning you! I told you to be careful. Be careful.
District Sh.
-Very funny.
What, you’re insulting me, babe?
Soon I'll stop you for insulting a public servant.
Right, what, you’re insulting me, babe?
-Just a little.
Mom called, said...
Good morning.
Excuse me.
Are you asking something?
-No.
Excuse me.
Who is this?
This is the sister's fiancé, right? Ehud Barak.
One more time without the sneeze.
She says there’s supposedly no mishap tomorrow
and everything is fine, no explanations.
What did she tell you?
-That's what she said,
what you said last time, in the last line.
What an idiot I am.