Okay, I can't talk right now,
I'm driving. Bye.
What do you mean? Rotem's mom
told me the teacher yelled at me today?
Yeah, today when I picked up the kid.
Why, what happened?
-Just, I was a bit late.
Oh, how late is "a bit" today?
-Five, six minutes.
It was super busy at the turn by the traffic light.
The teacher said you're a liar.
Dads aren't called liars.
-And liars aren't called dads either.
How late were you?
-A quarter of an hour.
Wow, God, you're the most
irresponsible person on the planet.
That's not true, Rotem was there and no one came to pick her up,
so the teacher gave her to me.
And I waited until her dad came to get her.
Alright then, so you're the deputy of the most
irresponsible person on the planet.
He also got a letter.
-Right.
A letter?
-I put it in my pocket, forgot about it, because of the teacher's yelling.
What letter? What's it say?
-I don't know, I didn't open it.
Open it, see what it is.
"Dear parents, hello.
I regret to inform you that your child has lice.
We ask that you address this issue urgently
and no, your child will not be able to attend kindergarten.
Regards, Ortal the teacher."
No way.
Girls, girls, don't get too close to each other,
each on her own side.
But we're playing quietly.
-Alright, each in her own section,
don't get close. Put on some music for them.
Too bad we don't have "Nehama the Louse."
We don't need it, we have enough lice of our own.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom, Shabbat shalom.
As you mentioned, Shabbat shalom.
Mentioned?
-We mentioned.
Look how every Shabbat everyone
shifts the time however they want. We mentioned.
Where are the guests I love
to give the biggest hugs to?
Come here.
-No, no, Mom, no hugs today.
Why not?
-Because the guests have guests in their hair, lice.
It's nothing, it happens to everyone, everyone has it,
it's probably from kindergarten.
Yeah, all the little pests they bring in
from kindergarten and school.
I wonder who the first pest was
that brought the pest to kindergarten,
that's what's interesting.
-Who? The son of the importer of the lice shampoo.
The daughter of the one who brings the combs!
Girls, go to the balcony.
Did you put something on them?
No, what, just now, on the way here
in the car, we found out they have lice.
Did they announce it on the news?
-No, Dad, we got a letter.
To the car?
-No, in it, it was in my pocket...
Okay, that's not important. In it,
now we need to find a pharmacy on duty,
buy the shampoo, and I'll comb them with the fine comb.
Okay, forget it, Mom, I'll do it at home.
I remember, back in my day, they used to take a jar,
they'd put in like a third vinegar,
a third oil, and a third lime.
A louse wouldn't come out of that alive.
Neither would a person come out of that alive.
Sorry, there are some more sophisticated treatments now.
Yeah, and the lice are more sophisticated too.
-Are you talking about lice?
Didn't Mom tell you Ofer is coming today?
Ofer?
-Yeah, surprise,
someone can come for Friday dinners
from my side of the family too.
Of course.
-Yeah, he wanted to meet the family.
And you want to give him lice.
Come on, why are you making such a drama?
What, it’s just a few lice
on the girls' heads.
It’s not even a permanent settlement yet,
just a few trailers on some isolated hill
and they’re still illegal.
What a pain, I’m already itching.
Itching? You haven’t even touched them.
What’s with the itching?
It’s psychological.
-Psychosomatic.
Psycholiceomatic.
Okay, enough, don’t upset her, she’s stressed.
Come on, let’s handle this before her boyfriend arrives, let’s go.
What, are you going to bring them the treatment?
I have a brilliant idea.
-What?
Why don’t we ask Manny and Alin to bring it?
They’re probably on their way.
So, who’s this Ofer?
-She met him online.
Nice, so if he’s coming to visit them
this is serious, huh?
-Probably.
What, am I hearing some doubt?
-No, of course not!
Mom.
-Okay, look, Moshe! This isn’t right.
If it’s that serious, why is she keeping it a secret?
I don’t get it, she lives here,
you’ve never heard of him?
Well, since I’m her mom
she probably doesn’t tell me.
Alright, I’ll check it out, okay?
I’m itching all over!
Maybe I’ll send Shai to buy shampoo.
No, it’s too late, I’ll do something else.
What, a grandma remedy?
-Yeah, but just so you know, it smells a bit.
I don’t care if it smells
as long as they don’t have lice
and it doesn’t spread to me.
Okay, I’ll make the mixture,
let’s hope Meirav’s Ofer doesn’t smell it.
Hey, do you know which website
she found him on?
Which site did they meet on?
-Online, what, do I know about websites?
Where did my successful daughter
find her suitors? Online.
Listen, back in the day, you had to put in effort, you know?
If you wanted to date a girl, it was a project.
If you put in the effort, you’d fall in love too.
Today it’s easy, it just happens,
it’s nothing, it’s... it’s no big deal, you know?
Like this, for example, the...
What do you call them? The hooks on bras,
what’s that?
Back then you had to invest.
There were those hooks, remember?
There was a hook like this and a hook like that.
The hook
Silvan, Silvan, Silvan,
that’s too much information.
Oh, that’s too much information? It’s more...
The internet isn’t too much information.
Not at all. The newspaper isn’t too much information
and the gossip sea isn’t too much information.
What do I care, tell me, for heaven's sake,
what do I care that Bar Refaeli
has problems with Leonardo DiCaprio?
Who even cares?
Now it turns out he’s in love with an actress
who’s in a movie with him, you know?
Her, listen closely, he met her
before he met Bar Refaeli.
But they talked about marriage, right?
-No, no, those are just rumors, rumors.
Forget it, it’s pointless there.
They talked about...
It's a mess, huh? This internet thing is a mess.
Hey, what's up with Avi? Why isn't he answering?
Now it's ringing.
Shabbat Shalom.
Wait, wait, wait,
stop the girls, don't let them play together.
Is he here?
What happened? Why not play together?
-Your girls probably have lice.
Girls, go to the balcony.
-Oh no. Hey, again?
Enough with the lice. I'm really asking,
if possible, let's not talk about it.
Tell me, Meirav, what did I hear? Today
some guy is coming to meet the family?
Ofer. That's why I don't want
you to talk more about the lice,
there are way more interesting topics
we can discuss.
Besides, how do you know
a guy should come to me?
Your wall on Facebook... is full of graffiti.
And we heard your blow dryer
from the room, working on turbo.
Because your girls have lice.
So if a few happened to jump on me,
I burned them with the blow dryer.
Tell me, what... how's Ofer? What's his status?
Job, bank account,
you like him, he likes you more,
spill some details.
Hey, he's coming soon, chill.
And Manny and everyone, no questions about what Manny just asked.
A test of a good, warm, healthy family,
and he doesn't have lice.
-What lice?
And cumin.
-Cumin?
Have you ever seen a Persian with lice?
-No, not really.
The lice don't like the smell.
That's true.
Well, Mom, that color is awful.
-Well, the color isn't really our problem.
Look, you wash the girls' hair,
you comb it with the fine comb,
then you wash it with my shampoo,
and you quickly perfume the shower.
Now go. Hey, come on. No time.
What's that smell? You know Ofer is coming.
Come on, stop making a drama out of everything.
By the time he gets here, it'll fade away.
Alright, I'm going to the girls.
Talk.
Talk about what? What does Mom want to know?
Tell me, how come
no one has ever heard of this Ofer?
When did you meet?
-Yesterday.
And you already invited him?
-He wanted to come.
Serious guy.
-Of course.
What, where did you meet?
In some forum.
-What forum?
"Want to start a family? Join us."
What, are those people who gave up on getting married
and want to have a kid alone?
I protest the use of "gave up"
but something like that.
I don't get it, so he's coming today
to audition for our family?
No one has ever had lice, you heard?
Did you tell that to the parents?
-I know what I'm doing.
If the parents see they're being tested, they'll freak out,
then he'll fall in love with them and maybe with me too.
What are you doing to yourself? Tell me,
you realize he's not looking for a bride, right?
Is that what you want to be, a single mom?
I'm sure I'll convince him
to stay, don't ruin this for me.
So what, Dad, excited?
-What do I have to be excited about?
Because of the groom.
-Leave it, what's there to be excited about?
Nothing new here, believe me,
it's the same fifty guys registered
on those fifty dating sites.
Believe me, all this internet
is a thousand fake people.
They talk to each other like it's all made up.
Why should I even get worked up? You get it?
No, you're right. Every pot has its lid,
even a pressure cooker.
I don’t get it. Come on, tell me, please,
They just met yesterday,
And now he’s already coming to meet the family. What the...
Something smells, right?
-Yeah, yeah.
Do you smell that?
-Could be he’s ugly.
Ugly?
-Maybe he’s limited in some way.
Maybe he’s blind, maybe he has one leg.
Maybe he’s cross-eyed? Like this.
He could also be a certain kind of crazy.
Moshe! It stinks here, I’m telling you.
Yeah, we already agreed with you.
-No, no, here, here, in the living room.
Open up, air it out.
What’s that? Is someone dying in there?
-The lice.
Alright, I’m off to meetings.
What, you’re done?
-Almost,
You need to leave the stuff on their heads
so the active ingredient starts working.
Active ingredient?
-It’s a lice thing...
So, how does it work exactly,
the stuff you put on my girls' heads?
If the stuff doesn’t kill the lice,
then the smell drives them away.
What lice? Who has lice?
Just a few lice on Shai's girls' heads.
You don’t need to make a big deal out of everything.
I’m going back to the shower.
What, you left them there alone?
I had to breathe a bit.
-I can’t believe it.
What lice? You’re not worried about my girls getting infected.
It’s fine, Mom’s taking care of it.
-But why here?
Because, well, I didn’t have time at home,
more like I didn’t know at home,
I found out on the way here, during the drive.
I’m on my way here?
Did the kindergarten teacher stop you at the intersection and tell you
or was there a sign saying "Caution, lice on heads!"?
Well, my Shai got a letter from the teacher
and forgot it in his pocket,
he just showed it to me now.
Great, the main thing is you gave my Moshe
the royal title "the idiot."
You didn’t give it to him, he earned it honestly.
Well, in the meantime, your Shai is threatening the throne.
The smell is better.
So, what, what are we talking about?
Oh, Orna told me someone is coming tonight
that Meirav is dating.
Dating him... she went out once,
and he’s already coming to meet the family.
-How nice.
There are stories like that about people
who from the first moment say, that’s the one,
I want to meet her parents now.
And.
So it was decided that this poor guy is either ugly or limited
or cross-eyed or crazy.
I say he’s a fool.
It would be cool if he’s a fool.
Every family needs one of those.
You guys don’t have one, and that’s actually fun.
You know, everyone together
makes fun of him, laughs at him,
the family fool, right there.
Man, if a fool comes here,
you guys are going to explode.
Boy
you know
the new shoes I bought,
they come with a computer in the sole.
It checks steps, calories, and blood pressure.
Probably from the excitement of a fool coming here
it started beeping.
Oh, here it is, right now.
Just like the news.
Nice.
Yeah, second floor, bye.
That's him.
You don't have to knock here, you can just come in.
Hi, Meirav, hello to the whole esteemed family,
Nice to meet you, I'm Ofer.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
How polite, huh?
Nice to meet you, I'm Rachel, Meirav's mom.
Shai, her sister, her husband.
-Two.
This is Manny, Meirav's brother,
His wife!
This is Orna,
Orna, her sister, and this is Moshe, Orna's husband.
Nice to meet you.
And this is my dad.
Nice to meet the head of the tribe.
Not even limping.
-Excuse me?
Sit, sit, it's fine.
Am I smelling cumin?
It's not from the food, it's from something else entirely.
-Very good.
Udi, did you check?
-What? About what?
About what I told you to check.
When I was chatting with your daughters and Hachmon.
What's wrong with him?
Meirav will kill me if I tell.
Yeah? And what do you think I'll do to you?
Well, he doesn't want to start a family.
-What do you mean?
Okay, what's that smell?
Which streets are we talking about?
About Superman in the living room.
She met him in some forum
for people wanting to have a kid
outside of marriage.
I don't know, she thinks
she can train him or something.
Or
'or
Why are you belittling her? Maybe she can succeed.
The odds are against her.
-Why do you say that?
Maybe she'll meet someone
who will be with her for who she is,
for who she is, for how she is,
somehow.
So what, Ofer, you said?
-Yeah, Ofer Katzir.
There was a president named Ephraim Katzir, you know him?
-Yeah.
Yeah
yeah
The defense for Israel?
-Nut.
Ofer, tell me, please, what are you doing now?
Just for general knowledge.
-Dad!
It's fine, totally understandable.
I work at "Tal" company,
Rom Ton, we developed advanced recording software
for ambiances
and we're about to have a big exit.
And in the big wave of layoffs, they left you with the car.
I wasn't in the wave of layoffs,
I'm the CEO of the company,
and we've always been profitable,
even in tough times.
From her side, 3?
-Jeep.
Oh, a jeep, a jeep is good, a jeep is very good.
It's expensive but it can
stand on sidewalks, that's good.
Am I smelling cumin?
Because when I was little, my mom put
something in my hair with cumin against lice,
It doesn't matter.
Hey, Ofer, just for general knowledge,
does your family have any history of mental illness?
-Maybe.
It's okay, it's legit to ask. No, we don't.
Silvan—
Ladies, spread out,
he’ll think we’re gossiping about him.
It’s not gossip, it’s exchanging opinions.
Alright, enough with the exchanges.
I'm going to call her.
So how are you at soccer?
-I watch sometimes, here and there.
So would you call yourself a soccer idiot?
Meirav, come to the kitchen, come help out.
-Sure.
Excuse me.
Let’s just say I’m more of a basketball person,
I play with my buddies every Tuesday.
You’re welcome to join.
-I’d love to but...
I’ve been out of shape lately.
When I say lately, I mean in the last twenty years.
No, I have to stay in shape
to stay in the unit,
there are no compromises there.
Silvan, I called you over here.
-Yeah.
I think I figured it out.
What’s wrong?
-Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
-Did you notice he has an accent?
Ofer Katzir has an accent?
-Accent? What accent?
Just a slight one.
I think he’s a spy.
What? What?
Spy, what?
-Spy, mole.
He wants to get citizenship
or forge documents
!He’s "blending in to gather information.
What information could he gather from us
besides the recipe for the mezilof?
What’s this? What’s this whispering about?
What?
-We don’t want our Meirav
to marry some...
Mavchuch and then we won’t know how to get out of it.
What Mavchuch? No way!
He doesn’t even want to marry her,
all he wants is to have a kid with her.
Yeah
in
the
mor
ning. `son.
.to
be
So he’s here to check us out.
We’re under review, we’re a family under review.
He’s here to check us out.
-Yeah, yeah.
So listen, I suggest we treat them with respect and suspicion.
Look, it’s like the matchmaking back in the day, remember?
They’d take two people, put them together,
tell them, meet each other, start a family,
and believe me, some wonderful love stories came out of it.
!Also some really tough cases of domestic violence.
.Give it a chance.
Come on, give them a chance,
Okay, let’s talk straight, what are you doing here?
Didn’t Meirav talk to you?
-Yeah.
You came to meet our family, behave! Accordingly.
And she didn’t tell you about the kid.
-You have a kid?
No, it’s something we want to do.
With Meirav?
Yeah, it’s a bit harder for me to get pregnant.
And you just want to have a kid with her.
Yeah, I’m her partner, Roy.
I’m telling you, I’ll make it happen.
Alright, good luck.
Listen, he looks great
and everything seems fine.
So good luck to you, I know?
I'm rooting for you too.
-So nice that you both like him.
Your opinion means a lot to me.
He also looks like a good gene pool.
-Yeah, he looks athletic.
Plus, he seems to have money.
-And he's sensitive too,
That's always how it is with gay guys, they're sensitive.
He's gay?
-Yeah.
But not for long.
-Oh.
So...
How did you meet Meirav?
-In the "Want to Start a Family? Join Us" forum.
And that forum,
is it on a regular site?
-What do you mean by "regular"?
Ofer, come here for a sec.
-Yeah, I wanted to talk to you too.
You didn't really explain to them what's going on.
-And you felt something was off?
Did you have a negative impression of my family?
-No, of course not! They're lovely but...
But do you want to have a kid with them or with me?
We, we want to have a kid.
Sorry, we're just passing through.
-It's fine.
Ten minutes to Kiddush.
I hope you're hungry.
You don't have to worry. She cooks great food.
Shai, there's something you don't know.
-Moshe, just drop it.
So, do you eat spicy food?
I've got something really spicy,
none of these Ashkenazis can handle it.
Come, come, come, sit next to me, come.
What, Mom, did you know?
You should've guessed the moment he
came out smelling like cumin.
There are very few men in the world who can tell
the difference between the smell of cumin and turmeric.
So wait, Meirav plans to have a kid with you
and then turn him straight?
Poor thing.
We need to save him. Her.
You see? I only have one little plate.
It's very expensive.
Meirav, are you coming to help serve?
-Of course.
Let's go.
So what, Ofer? Ofer, Ofer.
Are you planning to live together?
-Live?
Why, where do you live?
-In the center.
You have an apartment in the center?
-Not mine, I'm renting for now.
Rent these days is sky-high,
why didn't you buy an apartment?
We're planning to buy an apartment later.
Trust me, the best thing is to have your own apartment
in your name, registered in the land registry.
The best.
For now, we're good like this.
You’re still young and beautiful, so...
So what, are you... are you planning a wedding?
What's up with you?
Maybe you're engaged, right?
No, no, we thought about having a wedding
but it's not the most important thing,
what really matters is that we love each other.
Love?
-Very much.
Wow, how did you manage to keep this
a secret from everyone...
Well done. I admit, well done.
The secrecy must be Moshe! Who just wants to
be natural about it.
Honestly, it's not secret at all,
everyone who needs to know knows.
Look, look! I always, always
Dad finds out last.
Hey, what's up? Aren't we eating today?
Your dad wants to get to know your Bambi a bit better.
Why do you call him Bambi?
-Bambi, Bambi is a fawn.
Bambi. Why didn't you tell me?
I might have a chance for family.
And a dream to win the fawn over to my side,
so why ruin it for me? Why?
I wanted to ask you another question.
The apartment you’re moving into together,
will it be nearby
or are you going far from here?
-Why do you ask?
I'll explain.
Personally, I think
the farther, the better, you know?
Keep some distance from the parents,
give them a little peace, it’s good for both sides.
I'm actually for... for being close to the parents
because it helps both sides.
Hello.
Sorry, that's a mistake.
-It's not a mistake, it's Roy.
Roy?
-Roy, my partner, I call him Short Roy.
Because
you have a partner
you have a son—
Oh
oh
You have a partner?
Ofer, what’s this surprise?
Roy.
Wow, nice
how they clean
so much! You really went all out.
Meirav, please go to the kitchen.
Sit, sit, please.
He has a partner.
I can't believe he did this to me,
he invited his boyfriend here?
What, he didn’t tell you he has a partner?
I don’t remember, maybe at first,
when I was still surprised he’s not ugly,
not cross-eyed, not crazy, and not stupid.
That’s how it is, Meirav,
take down the pillows
so he won’t be surprised waking up
with too many expectations and rashes.
What am I doing?
Son, you wanted a guy, now you have a boyfriend.
-One and a half,
He really is short, this Roy.
-Great, celebrate.
Okay, forget it, I’ll sort it out for you, it’s easy, my treat.
Come on, Dad, will you do the Kiddush?
Yes, Kiddush.
So what should I say now, a woman of valor or a man of valor?
Everything okay, sweetie?
-It’s burning me.
It’s okay, the main thing is it doesn’t itch anymore from the sores.
Sores
sores
"On the sixth day, the heavens will turn over the earth..."
So in the end, the sores chased them away, huh?
That was my idea.
Yeah, but it’s thanks to me
that I forgot the letter in my pocket,
so it’s actually thanks to me.
Fine.
What happened, girls, are you itching?
It burns.
Look at the letter, until when is the girl suspended from kindergarten?
No, it just says "We request
to address this matter urgently
and no, your child will not be able to attend kindergarten."
Check the envelope if there’s a date or something.
"To the parents of the girl Rotem Gabatz."
"להורי הילדה רותם גבץ."
What?
-The letter isn’t even for our girl.
I’m telling you, if they go bald
it’s only because of your irresponsibility.
Or maybe it’s in the genes.
Let’s just say I’m more of a basketball person.
Try to get past the knee.
Every Saturday someone moves, moves...
Just one more minute of the...
Who? That guy’s son who brings the shampoo...
Sorry, the importer’s son.
I wonder who the first nutcase is. No...
I hope they’re making it in the loopers.
Did you put something on them?
I just found out, in the car.
What’s wrong with Dad? What’s wrong with Dad?
What were you laughing at?
-How he ran away.
It’s funny, right?
-Sorry.