Why aren't there many cars on the roads?
Because it's too early for humanity
to be awake at this hour.
In short, all evening the check was in my bag,
and I'm dancing, feeling great,
I was so excited I forgot to put the check away,
you get it?
What, you guys made it? Wow.
Alright, come on, turn off the...
Because it's not proper to talk on the phone
in a synagogue on Shabbat.
Bye, babe.
You guys are seriously happy people.
When a boy is born in your family
it's a celebration that lasts for weeks.
The birth, the celebration, the circumcision, celebration,
Then synagogue, then a meal,
Then the redemption of the firstborn—
Tell me, how many celebrations can you have
for this little kid
and so early in the morning?
Okay, fine,
I think the synagogue is right here on the right.
You think?
-Yeah, I'm not sure about that,
I haven't been here in weeks.
Can't you call someone?
-Who can I call?
Everyone's at the synagogue, they turned off their phones.
Do you happen to remember the name of the synagogue?
-No.
The street name of the desired destination?
-The...
No, I don't have that.
Well, if everyone turned off their phones, call Moshe.
Alright, looks good on you.
Orna turned it off for him.
-So for Meirav,
But don't call, just text her
that you have someone to introduce her to.
What a smart aleck.
None.
A lot.
Look at me, look at me and...
Bullseye.
Thank you, thank you very much.
It was so much fun at the synagogue,
I always say? Only at happy occasions.
Just a shame someone from the kids
threw crystal candies at my head,
blew a fuse in my brain.
-Yeah, yeah.
Do you want me to make Silvan a Google Mogel?
Yeah, yeah. Go make it, go—
Congratulations, it was lovely.
-Thanks.
Shai drives slowly,
and I wanted to get here earlier
to check if I picked my room.
Congratulations.
How's it going?
Here you go, sorry for the delay.
Come on, what a whine, you’d think.
Why didn't your parents come?
My dad's not feeling so well.
His dad's not feeling so well.
Alright, I'm going to Orna, to help her in the kitchen.
Wishing you good health and prosperity.
What's that?
-He's the grandfather, so people come to ask him for blessings.
But that's why he lost his voice this morning
so I'm helping him and speaking for them.
Why didn't your parents come?
Dad...
He fell off a chair yesterday.
What do you mean? He was sitting on it and it broke?
He stood on it, wanted to reach some vase,
complicated story.
What happened to him?
-Nothing.
What do you mean they're not coming? We're late.
Hey, what happened to Dad at the synagogue?
What, you didn't see his Torah reading?
Suddenly he disappeared.
-He didn't disappear, he ignored us.
What is this?
-It's Google Mogel.
Why is it like this?
You couldn't find an egg, so you used carrot juice.
Give me that.
-Oh my God.
So, how much did you end up putting in?
What, for Manny's circumcision? Like we did for Efrat.
Why?
No, no, we put in the same as we did for Efrat.
Look at Alin, how she came
to the synagogue in a red dress.
To the synagogue - only dots.
That's it, have you lost it?
Orna, come switch with Aunt Chava
with the bourekas,
I'm already tired.
-Yeah, Aunt Chava.
What?
How come I didn't see you with all your size?
Yeah.
Congratulations. How do I say it? Only in happy occasions.
-Yeah.
Did they hit you with the candies?
Congratulations.
-Thank you so much, thank you.
It's not right to let them throw
crystal candies and lollipops,
it's not right, look.
Congratulations.
-Only in happy occasions.
Only in happy occasions, only in happy occasions.
Tell me, what do they want from me? The kid's not mine.
Congratulations, do you remember me?
-Of course, how could I forget you?
Who is this?
-I have no idea.
Just because I know everyone, it's a huge family.
Where is she? Did you see her?
-In the kitchen with Orna and the bourekas.
K'
Lahuh '
and Ran
in
Yoy% ֵbL־
Shabbat Shalom, Shai.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Amen and amen.
-Stay healthy, Silvan.
It's okay, it's fine,
it's fine, it can happen to anyone,
don't get so worked up.
Hello.
M... and give and the newborn...
Whoever blessed our ancestors,
Who's the dad?
-Sperm donation.
May he have a long and healthy life.
Amen and amen.
-Amen and amen.
He also says amen and amen.
Amen.
-Come on.
Where are the parents?
My dad, he's not feeling so well,
he caught some annoying virus, really cranky too
that causes fainting.
There you are.
-I...
Well, you won't believe it.
What, are the bourekas gone?
-No, what bourekas?
Listen, it turns out we put in more money than Orna and Moshe.
So what?
-What do you mean "so what"? That's not nice.
Think about what Manny will think?
What will Manny think? What, you're his sister,
you gave him a gift, you didn't do anything wrong, right?
Besides, maybe what Orna and Moshe gave
is less than what the others gave?
I didn't think about that, I'll check it out.
Hi.
Are your parents here?
-No,
My dad, he has...
Bleach poisoning.
-He drank bleach?
He didn’t drink it, he inhaled it more...
But it’s a long story, it’s...
Where’s the bathroom?
-Over there, over there, over there.
Sit down.
Listen, Sali...
Hi, Rachel.
-Hey, hi, Riva, good to see you. How are you?
Not much.
He says get well soon.
-Thanks.
Viable seed, God willing.
Tasty?
Yeah, tasty.
Want a bite?
-No, thanks. I just ate.
What a funny guy.
So, do you come here often?
-No, it’s my first time.
What a crazy coincidence.
Why, is it yours too?
-No, I live here,
but it’s wild that we’re both here in this place.
I’m pretty sure we’re not related.
I’m not mistaken, right?
No, we’re not related,
I wouldn’t forget someone like you.
Meirav, very much so.
-Nice to meet you.
Meirav.
-Wow, that’s crazy.
Meirav, I need to talk to you.
Tell me, sit down, do you know Yoav?
-No.
Good.
Very much so, Yoav.
Hey, very much so.
-Sit down.
Listen, I really need to talk to you, urgently.
But wait.
-Okay, fine.
No, it’s fine,
I’m going to get more bourekas anyway.
Excuse me.
It’s out of jealousy, right?
What’s wrong with you? He just
went to get more bourekas, relax.
More relaxed than this and I’ll be in Jerusalem at night.
Listen carefully, I checked,
I don’t know him, you don’t know him,
not mom, not dad, not Moshe,
not Aunt Hannah or Uncle Yitzhak.
The only one who knows him is the army friend
of Alin’s cousin.
I need to talk to Manny.
Wait, that’s exactly what I wanted to talk to you about, Manny.
Tell me, how much did you give them in the end?
What do you mean? Mom and Dad put in for me.
I’ll pay them back, of course,
but generally, I put in what all the sisters put,
like usual.
Did you talk to Orna?
Yeah, like all the sisters put in.
-Like usual.
Of course, what, if there’s no coordination
it can reflect very poorly
on the favorite sister.
What? Yeah, yeah, of course.
Here comes the chosen Yoav back from the kitchen.
Excuse me, excuse me, Orna, Orna.
Shai, what’s up with Dad?
-He’s suspected of having meningitis.
God forbid.
Not a strain
_they’re alive
But don’t worry, there’s another tray in the oven,
ready in ten minutes.
Just Shai, do me a favor,
go call someone to replace me.
Because I'm going crazy here.
Sali, I know it's really frustrating
but don't let it ruin the fun.
I'm sure no one noticed.
Everyone laughed, everyone.
No one laughed, no one.
Here are the proud grandparents.
Hey! At the synagogue, it was so funny.
What was so...
So glad you came.
Thank goodness for family events,
otherwise we wouldn't get to meet.
I can't stand her.
He says he loves you all very, very much.
Even this morning he said
he loves you all very, very much,
those were his last words.
Congratulations to you too.
Lots of joy and all the best.
-Thanks, thanks.
There you are, I've been looking for you all over the house.
I'm looking for someone to replace Orna with the pastries.
Forget that for now, I have something more important.
More important than pastries?
Honey, listen carefully and focus,
we need to change the check we gave to Manny.
Change what?
-What you heard.
We need to lower the amount on the check.
I talked to Meirav, she coordinated with Orna,
it turns out there's a general way,
and we're not on track at all.
And I don't want to be the sister
who puts a bigger amount and makes
the rich sister look bad.
Fine, whatever you want, honey, it's your brother.
Alright, so now you're going to Manny
and you're changing the check with him.
I have no idea what, why, how much. Find an excuse,
get the check.
-Why me?
It's okay, Sali, it'll be over soon.
One quiet corner in this house.
-Hey, Rachel, hey Silvan.
What do you want now?
I thought maybe since I'm close,
a little blessing from Grandpa to the groom.
Are you crazy? Don't you know he lost his voice?
Oh, the silence hasn't passed yet?
Not yet.
-Oh.
So give a blessing in pantomime.
Finally alone. Come here.
Look, Sali, it's totally natural, really,
you don't need to feel bad about yourself,
it's completely normal to lose your voice from excitement.
No, no, no, that's not true, what are you talking about?
No one...
No, no, no one noticed.
Let the honor begin.
And enjoy.
Another.
Show some respect! Ahhh...
More, more respect.
More.
Enough, Sali, it's natural to get emotional. Enough,
in a few hours it'll pass.
Come on, come on, enough, enough.
Enough. Come on, enough.
He's not family,
he's Alin's classmate's cousin.
He was in the army, he has a dog.
I wouldn't believe you about them. Ugh.
From...
Because, you know...
Listen, I really don't feel like it,
but he had an issue with the check.
Because it turns out Shani gave you a check
from a book that was in her bag that got lost.
Then she found it
but forgot she canceled it.
So no...
By chance, I have a new checkbook here, so I...
I'll exchange it.
-Sure, sure.
Awesome.
From...
From a guy.
You know
b-l-y
That's it.
-Thank you very much.
I love celebrations.
I always say, only for celebrations.
It's a shame they didn't throw marshmallows, licorice.
Hey, is there a chance you could give the kid
your car keys?
-No.
No, not that I have anything against it,
we just need to go to my parents' later,
my dad isn't feeling too well.
What's wrong with him?
-He...
Had a follow-up visit,
they wanted to give him antibiotics through an IV.
The bourekas have arrived, sorry.
Look at Alin and Manny, on cloud nine, huh?
-Of course they're on cloud nine,
they got 200 dollars from Efrat,
she sent them from America via UPS.
What?
-You know, from that company, U-P-S.
Say?
Poo-aah
Wuu l'
Yeah. And what do you call that together?
Oops.
-Here you go.
What do you say, she sent them 200 dollars?
200 dollars.
Wow, that's nice.
What is that? How much is 200 dollars?
Oops.
A lot, a lot...
Shai, come here.
Why?
-Come here for a sec.
It turns out Efrat sent 200 dollars.
-So?
So what? I’m not ready to be the stingy sister.
I could put in more but I put in less
because of the coordination and what's customary.
Which apparently isn't customary at all,
if you send 200 dollars via UPS.
Don't you think you're exaggerating a bit?
I don't understand what difference it makes,
it's just a gift for your brother
and his wife for their little boy,
your sweet nephew, right?
-No. What matters is that I don't look bad.
So now you're going to Manny and you're
exchanging the check for its original amount.
When?
-Guess.
Orna, is there a chance you could give me
your car keys?
Do you think?
I've been waiting an hour for someone to come replace me.
Now you’ll go in for him right away.
Do you think?
-Oh, yeah?
You know what? Instead of bourekas
I'm serving childhood photos of you.
Move!
What?
Yeah, Shai. Thanks a lot, Sabta, perfect timing.
Listen, it’s really not my thing,
but it’s actually, surprisingly funny.
The check I wrote, the pen, the girl gave it to me.
So what turns out now? It’s really funny,
the pen is one of those magic pens
that disappears after a few minutes.
Disappears?
-Yeah.
So it’s pointless to write a blank check, you know,
the bank won’t find that funny.
What a thing, let me see.
-No, what’s there to see?
Sabta wants to say goodbye.
What?
-What’s up?
The check, it’s written.
Thanks.
Goodbye...
-Is everything okay?
What’s up, Dad, how’s your voice?
The voice and everything is just fine, it’ll pass in no time.
See you.
He says a lot of livelihood and blessings.
What’s this, you’re translating them all day?
I’m not translating, after so many weeks with them
I know exactly what he wants to say.
Wow, good for Efrat, right?
She sent them 200 dollars.
Mom, what’s he saying? I don’t understand.
He says it’s not that she sent them 200 dollars
but that she owed Alin
100 dollars from her last visit.
What does that have to do with anything now?
I don’t understand what he’s saying.
What did he say? I didn’t get it.
What’s there to understand? On her last visit
she swallowed the card at the ATM
so Alin lent her 100 dollars, that’s it.
Oops.
Okay. Shai.
-And if you see him, tell him
it’s not nice that he spreads
all kinds of lies about his dad.
He’s not spreading any lies,
his dad really isn’t feeling well.
What, you wanted a bourekas?
-Meirav!
Sorry, I finished them all.
It’s okay, just make another tray.
-Where to?
Where to? To Tavor.
-I’m not doing that.
Everyone even laughs at me for burning salad.
Salad!
Burnt!
How can you...
-Exactly!
Enough, Zizi, Zizi, enough, I’ll do it.
Ah, 'Naf', I see you’re managing.
I wonder if Yonatan is still here. Yonatan.
Shai.
-What now? I’m making bourekas.
I understand and I’m sorry
but we need to break the check again.
But I already changed it.
-Right, but we need to break it again.
What break it again? I’m making bourekas.
Honey, what’s going on with you?
At first, we brought a nice gift,
you asked to make it smaller? Fine,
then you asked to make it bigger, also fine,
now you want to make it smaller again?
-Yeah.
Why?
-Because it turns out Efrat owed Alin 100 dollars
and that’s not part of the gift,
So it turns out I'm putting my sisters in a bad light again, you know?
Forget it, I'll make bourekas at home.
Alright, son...
Aunt Chava.
Ohhh
Can I please have your car keys?
-What?
Mmm.
What now?
-Listen.
No way.
You know what, forget it,
Just give me that check.
I'm writing you an open check here
and a pen that works,
I'll call you with the amount
as soon as your crazy sister gets her act together.
Goodbye.
-Goodbye, Bulshoi.
Yeah, Dad, hi.
Hello, Shayka, we’re back home,
can you pass me Shabi's dad?
-Sure, no problem.
Silvan, here, my dad wants to say congratulations.
Son, he’ll say it, they’re waiting.
Hello.
Hello?
Hello, hello, hello.
Alright...
Dad, he can't really talk right now.
So pass me the lady.
-Please.
What’s this, he doesn’t want to talk to you?
-Why wouldn’t he want to talk to me?
Maybe he’s upset you didn’t come,
they get upset over everything.
Sensitive, sensitive.
-Hello, Pinchas.
Riki, she can hear you.
Hello, Racheli. Hi, how are you?
Everything's fine. Tell Riki
we weren't offended that you didn’t come,
we just really missed you.
I heard you fell, not on us.
-Not on you, on the table.
I got on a chair to take down a vase from up high
and then I fell and hit my head on the table.
Nothing serious, just a few small cuts.
-I.
Just a second, hold on.
That’s it, Mom, we’re leaving.
-Alright, sweetie.
Have a good week.
Thanks.
Bye, Dad.
-Bye, bye, bye.
Yeah, Pinchas, I’m with you. Everything okay with you?
Yeah, yeah, all good.
But then, while in the ER, I fainted
into the cleaner's bucket with bleach
and inhaled too many fumes.
-What are you saying...
Turns out there's this health organization of fainting people
that’s going around all the hospitals now.
At least they figured out what it is and you’re okay?
-Of course I’m okay,
they gave me an antibody shot.
And did the shot help?
-Of course it helped,
just in the syringe of the antibody shot
there was a tiny bubble,
so they took me for a CT to make sure
that bubble didn’t reach my head.
The test came back normal, I hope.
Mom.
-Just a second, hold on.
Alright. That’s it! Mom, we’re going.
Yes, yes.
“Yachin Y...
Have a good week, congratulations.
-Good week.
Congratulations, sweetie.
-Bye, Abalia.
“Yachin, yes.
Yes, Pinchas, I’m with you.
Totally fine.
There was a concern about meningitis.
But the dean came out, as you say in your place,
Knock on wood, knock on wood, hamsa, hamsa, hamsa.
We don’t say that here,
But I get what you mean.
So lots of congratulations, and again, we apologize.
Thank you so much, Pinchas! Feel better, lots of health.
Say hi to Riki. Bye.
Oh my, we’re leaving, it was really nice.
-Bye.
I organized what I could in the kitchen.
-Shabbat shalom.
Is everything okay?
Thank you so much, Marinka, thanks.
-Thanks.
Silvio.
I have no words.
I’ll talk to you tomorrow, bye.
Thank you.
No problem.
You drove me crazy with that voice of yours,
you’ve been driving me nuts all day.
No, no, it’s passing, it’s passing.
Okay, I need a bourekas.
What? Yoad is Tzvika the cross-eyed guy's son?
Wow, poor Meirav.
Alon's brother?
What are you saying?
What does he have on the way, "Dad's bourekas"...
Do you remember if "Miriam's bourekas" is open on Shabbat?
Well, may he have good health.
There's also that guy from TV.
Alright, babe. Let’s go, bye.
There’s a problem.
-What?
You won’t believe it.
What now? Aunt Chava is there more than us?
No, Alin's brother.
Come on, we need to go back.
-No, we don’t need to go back.
Of course we need to, what do you mean "don’t need"?
-Don’t worry.
Promise this is the last week?
-Yeah, I already know how everyone is fat.
So here, I’m calling Manny.
Too bad I didn’t leave the whole notebook with him.
See you.
He said lots of blessings and livelihood.
What’s that?
I’m sorry. Bye.
Again, again, from the beginning.
From the beginning.
There was a little bubble in the syringe that went to my head.
And they took me for a CT to check that...
They had an air bubble in the syringe
of the antibodies, so they took him for a CT
to make sure the bubble didn’t reach the head.
Okay.
What are you saying, Alin's brother.
What a weirdo.
What does he have on the way?
-No, no weirdo, what...
Yeah, I don’t know what’s wrong with me.
Can you swap Grandma Chava with the bourekas?
I’m already tired.
What’s this, Grandma? You’re an aunt, honey,
why on earth would you say Grandma, honey?