Rosh Hashanah for me is...
It's family, it's...
It's home, it's...
-the best show in town.
Way more stressful than "Big Brother,"
way more wild than "Survivor."
And way more exhausting than "The Hall of Fame."
But it's okay, I've gotten used to it and...
I even enjoy it.
Sometimes.
It's, it's, it's joy,
It's a big joy to host the family.
Happy New Year, everyone.
Yeah.
So what, a derby, huh?
-What derby?
My parents against your parents.
Honey, why against? Really,
It's a family, social, friendly holiday gathering.
I hope you're mentally prepared for this, yeah?
Because it happens every few months.
Okay, every time it hits me again.
Which grandparents are we visiting today?
Today, honey, it's both grandpas
and both grandmas, all together.
The whole clan.
-What's a clan?
A clan is a lot of warm people making a fuss.
Funny.
I don't get why we always need these
summit meetings during holidays
and the extravagant meals.
The atmosphere is so tense.
-Is there an accident?
No, for heaven's sake, there's no accident.
Not yet.
Sorry for the really bad connection,
but do you happen to know where your parents are?
Another hundred meters at the turn, turn right.
It's not at this turn, it's at the next one,
I remember it very well.
You and your memory haven't been
on the same page for weeks, Pinhas.
Yeah, well, then tell me, where should I turn?
If you had listened to me earlier, you wouldn't be asking now.
So now make a legal U-turn
at the nearest roundabout, take the second exit.
Mom, you're really G-P-S.
Excuse me, I'm way better than GPS, right?
Yeah, but you can turn off GPS.
Don't worry, I'll be turned off in the grave.
How do you always end up at the grave?
Let me surprise you,
in the end, we'll all end up in the grave.
Mom, it doesn't matter what they talk about,
rising fuel prices, revolutions in the Middle East,
in the end, we'll find ourselves at your funeral.
And sooner rather than later.
-Left.
No way, there's no left turn here,
do you want to kill us?
Okay, so now make a legal U-turn
at the nearest roundabout, take the third exit.
If you had listened to me, you'd already be in the middle of the Kiddush.
Or the Kaddish.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom...
-Happy Holiday.
Happy Holiday.
Happy New Year, Happy New Year.
Happy Holiday, Happy New Year.
Mom, what a dress.
-Thanks.
Well, where are your parents?
They're on their way, I don't know where.
Do you think they still remember the way here?
Yeah, the truth is they really haven't been here for a while.
Yeah, we all forgot what it was like.
-It was tsimmes.
What?
'B', come on, enough already.
I'm really happy and excited
that your parents will be here with us.
It was Rosh Hashanah!
A holiday...
Very important.
It symbolizes beginnings,
It symbolizes new starts.
And as we know, every beginning has an end.
And every end has a beginning.
-Grandpa.
Every evening has the morning that follows! And then! Afternoon.
And then we have evening again
and then we have night and the watch...
Soon quietly for the third time.
-Grandpa.
I asked about the family.
So could you wait a minute
because I was just about to talk about the family.
We talked about morning, we talked about night, about the watch,
Which watch was I?
Now you confused me, please.
Why aren't Shai's parents coming?
-Mom, it's still early,
What do you need them stuck here in the living room for?
You're right.
They say that...
You don't choose your family.
But personally,
if I had the choice,
I would choose exactly the same family,
just like it is.
Mom!
Mom, where are you?
Well, with slight changes but really slight.
Mom!
That was a joke, a real joke.
Are you here?
Can we erase the last part?
Hey, Silvan,
Wouldn't you prefer to skip all these holidays?
I gain at least ten percent every holiday.
Are those ten percent from your knees or your belly?
Oh, I would skip all these holidays,
There's just too much family overload, you know?
It's like a pile of holidays all together
when each holiday separately... it's really a disaster,
It's something! There's nothing to be done.
All you have to do
is just set your time back
and hope with all your heart that in two hours
everyone will leave already...
To that, they'll go, they'll all go home.
Just to be clear,
your parents are very, very welcome here.
-Of course.
We're just talking hypothetically.
-Yeah.
Also about skipping the holidays,
we're only talking theoretically, right?
-Yeah.
Because look at me, what,
do you see me skipping any holiday?
I'll be honest with you,
I can't imagine you skipping at all.
That's what I...
Do you remember Shai's brother is coming, Adam, right?
Keep that in mind?
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom, babe.
Shabbat shalom, my sweet.
And here’s mine.
-What... white.
I'm dressed for the holiday, yeah.
-Fits perfectly with the table.
If Adam is coming,
then I need one more chair and one more plate.
Is Shai's brother coming too?
-Yeah. Why, what's the problem?
There's no problem, quite the opposite, it's a big problem.
I meant it! I dressed up for Rosh Hashanah.
-Really?
I need to change the whole concept.
-Meirav, Meirav, relax, Adam is family, okay?
Do you remember what happened the last time they met, at the K?
The concept stays the same, holiday.
Excuse me, I'm disappearing from here
and forget you saw me like this.
Meirav gets anxious during the holidays,
so she feels the loneliness more intensely.
It's okay, Mom, sooner or later
she'll find the one who's right for her.
Yeah, sooner or later it won't happen.
It's not good for man to be alone, right?
This man is exactly the one I need.
I have a strong feeling it's him for a long time.
He has everything I need
in a life partner and vice versa,
He doesn't have anything I don't need in a partner.
Shabbat Shalom.
Have a good Shabbat.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-What a fool I am.
Have a good Shabbat, Silvan.
What's with this camera? Are you filming?
What, do you have stage fright?
I don't have stage fright,
I have a fear of light, music, and everything.
The girl needs to submit a project
at school about the family.
The whole family needs to help.
She asked if she could
come film some family stuff here.
Of course, what’s the big deal? There's family everywhere today.
Sure, sure, go ahead.
You see? So you can film whatever you want.
Your parents won't mind?
-No, no, what...
Not at all. They don't care about anything.
By the way, Moshe googled a bit about your dad,
I didn't know he was the Minister of Justice.
He's not.
-What do you mean he's not?
Pinchas Rosen, right?
That area looks familiar to me.
Should I call Shai?
I'm telling you, my mom will get mad.
Son, honey, if you don't call, she'll get mad too, right?
That's your mom. It's like playing
Russian roulette with all the bullets in.
She'll get mad.
Come on, just call now.
I'm driving, what’s that?
Hello, Dad.
-Yeah, we're on our way, Shai.
Don't talk without a hands-free,
it's a 1,000 shekel fine and points.
-Okay, okay, hand me Mom.
Shai, I told you a thousand times,
don't talk to Dad while he's driving.
Did I say it or not?
-You said, you said.
He refuses to switch to hands-free.
Ask them where they are.
-Mom, I just wanted... where are you?
We're in the car, where else could we be?
They're in the car, where could they be?
Yeah, but where's the car?
Where's the car located?
-He insists on knowing where we are.
Adam, try to read a sign.
We don't recognize anything here.
Not the surroundings, not the architecture,
We're not used to coming
to these parts of the city at all.
Oh, what, did you get lost, Mom?
No, no, Shai, it's this place
that got lost, not us.
I have an idea, bring me Adam.
-Okay, hold on.
Take Shai.
Ah, bro.
Bro, thanks, I really owe you one.
You can bring them.
-Are you sure? You can still change your mind.
No, forget it, we've kept them waiting long enough.
It's family, in an hour and a half it's over.
Wow, how did I not notice, oh man,
well, what a fool I am, bye.
What? What did you not notice?
On my phone. There's GPS.
Why didn't you say anything?
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom.
Shabbat shalom. Everyone, please pay attention,
How come she said Shabbat shalom
and not Shabbat shalom like all of you?
Please.
Why specifically?
Because you...
Me, when I met Mav,
I don't know what it means
that he comes from a family like that...
With a lot of people.
You mean a lot of people.
-No, sweetie,
A lot of people like a centipede.
When are your parents coming, Shai?
-What?
Yeah, they're on their way, running a bit late, they had some...
Confusion on the way.
Oh man, I'm starving.
Wow, and there are all those blessings beforehand.
Hungry.
Family is like a stew,
but for Rosh Hashanah, not for Passover.
You throw a ton of stuff in a pot,
put it on low heat,
and in the end, something comes out of it.
When you choose to start a family with someone,
you bring your family into the mix,
the one you grew up with,
and he kind of brings his family.
And really, you know, everyone comes from different backgrounds
from families that God forbid, we don't want to know troubles.
And together you want to create something
really new, a new family
that's like a better version
of the previous one he came from.
Happy holiday.
-Hello, happy holiday.
Happy holiday, happy holiday.
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom and sweet.
Shabbat shalom, Shabbat shalom, it's been a while since we saw each other.
Happy holiday, Shabbat shalom.
-It's been a long, long time since we saw each other, yeah.
Happy holiday.
-Shabbat shalom.
Do you remember Meni and Alin?
-Of course.
And Orna and Moshe.
Come on
`let's go
It still gets to me.
Meirav, hello, how you've grown.
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom.
I'm really happy we have the chance
to come here, to the Hasson family,
and celebrate the holiday with them.
Holidays are always a wonderful time for gatherings.
Here, we are always welcomed warmly
and in every gathering like this, we learn something
about you, about your customs,
it's so exotic.
Rachel, this is from me,
Not from me, from me.
Really, you didn't have to.
I know, but I never
come empty-handed.
We're a close family, we don't need gifts.
But it's not a gift, it's Moshe! I made it myself,
Surprise.
If you made it, then it must be... great.
Great.
-Great, yeah.
Why don't we sit down?
Come on
The truth is, I really love the holidays,
Especially I love visiting you during the holidays,
Because the food is so flavorful, so enticing,
But honestly, all those spices of yours
raise my blood pressure a bit
and then I have to take Oksar-Plus
and it makes me pee a lot,
running to the bathroom every five minutes is not...
So eat the bulletes.
-Oh, those little ones with turmeric?
I, I like that, it's citrusy.
But I have to take the Restromicin
and it gives me a bad smell in my sweat.
The sweet chicken?
-Sugar, I have to take Globen half an hour before
and an hour after Glucophage.
The salad?
-Salt, it raises my blood pressure,
again Oksar.
The plus is a big deal now,
I have to run because of the Oksar.
No, no, no, it happens to her a lot.
Welcome.
Welcome everyone,
We have a night full of blessings and good things.
We have a fish head,
may we all be the head and not the tail.
Pomegranate, may our merits increase,
Apple in honey, may we have a sweet year.
-Amen.
Date, may they end, beet, may they disappear, carrot, may it be lacking.
Why, what.
-May our enemies and haters be cut off.
Is there no lettuce missing?
For the Yelafetu.
We have everything, we have everything, ladies.
-Just kidding...
Dad, need a reminder?
-No, I remember on my own,
It looks like tsimmes but it's spicy.
Ah, Yelafetu...
I still remember the first time I came here.
So you’re all together,
after Sabri Maranan we say cheers.
But that time I was shocked,
I thought we were drinking.
With us, it’s not like that, it’s much quieter.
"And on the day of your joy
and on your appointed times and at the beginning of your months
you shall blow the trumpets over your burnt offerings
and over your peace offerings
and they shall be
for a remembrance"
Sabri Maranan-
-Cheers!
Every family has its own holiday dishes.
For half a year, for example, I wait for the Mahlata.
First, you need to chop half the amount of meat,
all the fat from the lamb and the kidneys
needs to be mixed with half of the mixture of all the vegetables.
Then you need to stuff the intestines with the mixture...
Is it okay if we continue after the food?
-Yeah.
These are bulletes, this is pakala,
these are spinach leaves with lamb meat.
And this is the Mahlata for Rosh Hashanah.
These are stuffed intestines with meat and lamb fat.
If you eat this and sit quietly for a moment
you can hear your arteries constricting.
Highly recommended.
Wait, but it must be spicy.
-Barely.
By your standards, yes, Dad.
You ate Mahlata, drink juice.
If you put them on the table next to each other
the food we make in our family
and the food he makes,
you can really see the difference right away,
in color, in smell, in texture, in stability.
Yeah, and I'm not saying which is tastier, okay?
You know, everyone has their own taste, that's totally fine.
But when it comes to food,
they're more into boiling and soaking
and for us, food is more
about frying at different depths.
Rachel, if it’s not too rude,
can I bring what I made now?
And
um.
Shh
-
Bring me the black box.
-Yeah, yeah, I'm on it, hold on.
What did you make for us this time, Riki?
Be patient, Silvan, it’s a surprise.
I know, gefilte fish.
-Just wait.
And it’s not gefilte, it’s gefilte fish,
with a soft "g."
What is it?
-You won't believe it, it's my first time,
I got the recipe from the internet, it’s from carving.
-From drizzling.
Drizzling for Rosh Hashanah?
We just...
We just don’t usually
make drizzling for Rosh Hashanah.
Riki is creative.
Can I have some drizzle?
-I’ll put some on for you.
I want some too.
-Me too.
It probably won’t taste as good as yours, Rachel.
My recipe is very secret.
Can I have a piece too?
For your first time, it turned out really tasty.
Different.
What’s happening here today
is nothing compared to what happened at Passover
at Moshe's parents'.
Did I do something wrong?
-No, everything's fine.
We just don’t usually
make drizzling for Rosh Hashanah.
So there’s no need, you can return what’s left to the kitchen.
Okay, she didn’t know.
Come on, she had good intentions.
Mom, I’m begging you, it’s a holiday evening,
let’s get through this peacefully.
You don’t do something like this, you just don’t.
Even if it turned out gross...
No, sorry.
Can I have another piece?
-You can also...
Is it spicy?
-It has raisins, sweet potato, and sweet carrot.
This way I’ll be a family of two,
but not from my parents, just through Shai.
Funny, right? Just an annoying anecdote.
So what’s a guy like you doing in a place like this?
I’m just waiting for the holiday to pass.
Why, aren’t you enjoying it here?
Not at all, I still need to go out with friends tonight.
Can I join?
Not this time.
You always say "not this time,"
when will "this time" actually be?
Someday.
So you’re saying there’s a chance.
Slim.
-But there is.
No.
Really, what a heartbreaker.
-But there is.
"To the creator of a plot, to the creator of a plot
grant him forgiveness at the time of the act."
Again.
"Oh, creator of tales, oh, creator of tales."
Lithuania, my homeland! Cheers to health in the government.
"It's bad to only know a person you've lost."
The kids have no right to speak here!
I love Yeshiva more.
Our Father, our King.
My dear, my dear.
Our Father, our King, our Father, our King.
Because we have no deeds.
Do with us...
But it's a mess.
-You don't have many choices,
You have no choices. Either you do like me,
look at the clock, wait an hour,
In another hour, they're leaving here, Kivivi...
Or next year, you bring her to
her house, her food.
I'm sorry, but with all the good intentions,
I can't wash food.
In the end, when everyone says,
wow, how fast time flew,
It was so fun, such tasty food.
Come for the holiday, Shabi... of course, we'll come for the holiday, Shabi.
Thank you so much, it was nice to be here.
'Cause
It was nice.
-Really.
Great that you came.
-Yeah.
We really enjoyed the understanding.
-We enjoyed it too.
Thank you, it was lovely.
Here’s the carving tool.
They finished everything, that means it was tasty.
Come on, really, we loved the moves.
Okay.
-Thanks.
Bye, Pabchas.
-Adam, come on,
We already loved the moves.
-I’m coming.
And Adam, think about what we talked about, okay?
I thought about it and dismissed it.
Buu
Yabuu
Bye, see you later.
B' Buu
Bye.
-Hello, hello, bye, bye, hello, hello.
That's it, enough.
Riki, I wanted to say well done
for the fight you had with Rachel
over that carving you did. Really, well done.
I wanted to prove once and for all
that we, in our community,
when we want, we know how to make
both migdas and chraim.
And even carving. Right, Adam?
Adam?
Baradam.
She nagged him all night, that fall.
Riki, we reached Highway 6.
-Why do we need Highway 6?
I didn't want Highway 6, I want home, to peace.
Bar.
Peace. You only had a back
Did we reach the grave again?
Just so you know, your mom was really not okay
with what she did, with the mezilof.
Why, she made a big effort
for bringing hearts together.
Okay. You know, honey, that in our house
mezilof is a very sensitive point.
I hate to say it
but she made a very tasty mezilof.
Grandma Riki's mezilof was tastier
than Grandma Racheli's mezilof.
Honey, if you say that one more time,
you're moving in with Grandma Riki.
Why are you presenting it to her as a punishment?
You want, honey? In a second
you’ll also move in with Mom Riki.
Why, what did I do?
Here, see? Even for you, it's moldy.
She said "goodbye" and not "Shabbat Shalom."
Yeah, do it again.
Sweetie, go to the kitchen.
To the living room.
Starting to fly like in cartoons,
veins bursting, soul at home,
magic hour outside, the sky's watching you
and God says to you, Manny, I love you.
And then you sit with it and sniff it
and something comes out of it
that’s not at all what you intended in the first place.
Something comes out,
but what comes out is the result,
that’s not what we gathered for,
so if a dog goes to a stone and washes itself somewhere...
I told him, improv a little...
MasterChef.