Dude, this is cool.
You know it’s also a GPS, right?
It can save you a ton of time on the road.
I don’t need a GPS, I can drive on my own.
And leave me the phone alone, do me a favor.
-Okay, come on, babe,
I just want to see if it’s a guy’s
or a girl’s voice saying,
"Turn right," "Turn right."
Sit down, do me a favor, leave it alone,
it’s new. You’ll mess it up.
Fine, I won’t mess it up, relax.
I have the instructions here, I’m doing what it says.
But it’s not about what’s written.
You wash the washing machine
exactly like it says, right?
The technician said it happens to everyone.
And the streamer?
-I’m not to blame it doesn’t say "delete" on it
like all the normal devices.
And the alarm clock?
Just because your mom gets mad when we’re late, it’s not my fault.
Want me to tell you what all these instructions are for?
So there’s work for all those technicians
who come to your house
and act like they don’t understand
how you didn’t fix it yourself.
Huh?
-What did you do? What did you touch?
Chill out, God. What’s wrong with you?
I updated it a bit, it’s just that...
It switched to Norwegian.
-What?
No, everything’s fine, come on,
I’ll fix it in a second.
It’s just Norwegian.
-What?
Norwegian, Norwegian, okay?
It switched to Norwegian. What do you want?
Chill out, I’ll sort it out.
Tell me, does "valg" mean "choose" or "delete"?
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Happy holiday.
Happy holiday, the boys are already coming.
What holiday and what happy? Why did you have to touch it?
Enough, babe, I said I’m sorry.
So what? You said sorry,
does that cancel everything?
In the spirit of the holiday?
-It’s not a holiday in Norway right now.
Okay, enough, enough. I have the instruction sheet here.
Give it to me,
I’ll fix it for you in a second.
-You’re not touching that! You messed it up and now you’re inheriting it?
My connectivity fees are crying from the ground.
-Fine.
Don’t touch it.
-Okay, fine, come on, you’re just being cranky,
I get you and it’s not from that,
it’s from all these holidays
where every other day is Friday and the boys are always
with their families at all kinds of meals.
It’s family "overdose,"
who wouldn’t get annoyed by that?
I’m not annoyed by that, I’m annoyed that
you messed up my phone.
She’s annoying him again.
-I can relate.
Does she annoy you too, Shani?
Did she forget where to put the socks?
No.
-Then no.
Pinchas, why are you blaming me?
I clearly remember you put it
in the decoration box after the holiday.
I’m telling you I didn’t.
You put it there!
-You did!
You don’t have to be so cranky.
Just so you know, you don’t find things when you’re angry.
Enough, you don’t fix things when you’re angry.
Hello, happy holiday.
-Happy holiday, Riki.
Happy holiday.
-Happy holiday.
It’s been a while since we saw each other.
-Two days.
Mom, what’s the deal with the leftovers?
-On Sukkot evening?
No, I thought maybe
he survived the break-fast meal.
Yeah, I don't know who made those meals.
Shai, go set up the sukkah,
Dad took it down from the attic.
Well, let me fix your phone in the meantime.
-Don't touch it.
I'll sort it out quickly
and fix the phone without instructions.
"We'll grab iron rods fast
to build a sukkah in five minutes..."
So what...
What's new?
Since Saturday?
Do you need me to help you in the kitchen?
-Yeah.
No, it's not here either.
What is it? What happened?
Riki can't remember where she put the garlic press.
It's the same thing every year.
I clearly remember Pinchas packed it up
last year.
-You.
Okay, fine. Even if you don't find it,
it's not a big deal, I'll make decorations with the girls.
And the mess?
-No glue.
Just scissors, a stapler, and old magazines
-Okay.
On the balcony.
You don't have to be so stubborn.
We have a garlic press, we're using the garlic press.
Why are we keeping all this stuff?
When was the last time we used this?
What even is this?
I, I remember,
it's a gift Itamar gave you for your 56th birthday.
Yeah, but what is it?
-A device, how should I know.
It's a nose hair trimmer.
-Oh.
In the hallway. That's exactly what I wanted to talk to you about.
Here it said "choose," "and go,"
so later it's in the back...
Right?
-Well, what's up? Did you come to look for the instructions?
No, I forgot the sugar.
-Okay, you won't believe what's happening in the kitchen.
If it's not schnitzel, I'm not interested.
I'll tell you three things.
Your mom, your dad, and a nose hair trimmer.
-Got it.
Looking for the garlic press?
-Yeah.
And if it's in your dad's nose,
there's a chance they'll find it too.
Oh, my mom can be so stubborn.
Right, lucky she didn't pass that down to you.
Just bring the phone already!
-No.
But I know how to fix it,
I saw in the instructions.
Not giving it to you. Go find something else to mess with.
Okay, fine, then I'll go
make decorations with the girls for the sukkah.
Make sure there are instructions.
-Funny.
Very funny, I'm cracking up.
Hello, happy holiday.
-Happy holiday.
How's it going?
Heh
What’s this, we didn’t see each other two days ago?
-Because,
I'm just happy, that's all.
What's with the magazines?
-Decorations for the sukkah.
Oh, how nice, so do you want to...
Yeah, honey, maybe you should go with Shani
to really make decorations for the sukkah,
in the meantime, I'll grab some schnitzels, something.
Sukkot, no schnitzels. I've been through this.
I totally forgot, the days got mixed up for me.
So honey, do you want to make the decorations together
for...
Babe, I need to go with Shai to build the sukkah.
Just like when we were kids.
Remember how we used to build the sukkah together?
-Of course.
You held the nails.
I hammered them in!
-For sure.
So now it’s a sukkah for life, much safer.
Definitely.
-Let’s go.
Oh, decorations.
-Decorations.
Is it over there?
-No.
Pinchas, I think you need to
prepare for the worst:
There’s a chance we won’t find the garland.
-It’s Sukkot,
and the garland is part of the Sukkot tradition,
I’ll find the garland
even if I have to search until Hanukkah.
And if I find the sun, I’ll put
it aside so you don’t pack it too.
You don’t have to be so grumpy.
Besides, it’s kind of nice to find some of the stuff here.
-Thanks.
We already found the thorn! Nice is not it.
Oh, look, there are pictures
of the kids when they were little.
Wow.
Itamar!
And Adam,
such cuties.
Hey! What a cute family back then.
What happened that it all fell apart?
-Do you need help, Riki?
No, you’ve helped enough already.
I don’t need instructions, it’s a sukkah for life,
what do we need instructions for?
For inspiration, okay?
-Fine, okay.
Come on, quick, while Michal is there.
Wait, tell me,
what’s with this sudden isolation vibe?
The kids went with Smadar to the Maldives,
Michal finished studying and has time
and she decided to spend that time with me.
And that’s not good?
I volunteered to build a sukkah with them, right?
Uh-huh.
-Uh-huh.
Ugh, I thought we were in decoration mode.
It’s okay, don’t worry, they’ll soon give up searching.
Gross.
So what? You’re without kids now, huh?
Sounds fun.
-I wish I could live like this forever,
I’m telling you, I’m just happy.
Really?
-Yeah.
Look, honestly, after Itamar
supported me so nicely in my studies
and was such a considerate husband, giving me time alone
and living with the fact that his wife is a student,
he deserves to just
accept me 100%, right?
Yeah. I hope he knows how to appreciate that.
-Of course.
It’s not just the restaurants! The museums and clubs,
I mean, it’s the most fun, don’t get me wrong,
but the main thing is just the time I have! with Itamar,
24/7, I call it "Itamar time."
She calls it "Itamar time."
-Wow, you’re really into it.
And it’s not that she drags me
to all the museums, restaurants, clubs,
I suffer from it, don’t get me wrong,
it’s that I have to do it with her 24/7.
Tough, tough.
-And why do I deserve this?
No, Shai, why do I deserve this?
What, I was a model husband,
I gave her time to study,
time for herself, to be a student.
I was happy to come here, Shai.
I miss my kids, you know.
Take comfort in the fact that you can call them.
At least she didn't break your phone.
What, Shani read the instructions
and thought she understood them?
Oh come on
just come and
I'll sort it out for you without instructions or anything.
You know what the problem is
with today's technology?
Everything's too accessible, too available.
Back in the day, if you needed something,
you needed a toolbox,
you needed a screwdriver, you needed a Phillips,
you needed a hammer.
Today, you just have to touch it.
So what you're saying
is that if a screwdriver was involved,
then Shani wouldn't have broken my phone at all?
No, Shani would have broken it anyway.
I have no technical knowledge.
Who put up the shelf in the living room?
Oh, the one that's a bit slanted?
It's not crooked, it's designed. Don't be a smartass now.
So, what's the size of their storage?
Do they really need that clutter?
I thought we could do some decorations.
Come on, you want to mess with the Rosen family?
Will this get me out of doing Passover here?
Only death frees you from obligations, not Passover.
Energy generation
I.B.
create
B.K.
okay, A
I'm going to make chains on the balcony.
-Alright, I'm coming with you.
I think I managed to connect to help,
Jay is a...
Hoolap, hoolap...
And now what?
Do you understand Norwegian?
Who is it?
-Shai, it's Adam.
Your brother is here.
Great.
-Are you coming up?
Wait, wait, tell me, are those metal rods down there
our sukkah?
Yeah, but they're coming down, looking for the instructions.
What instructions? It's a sukkah.
-I'm on my way.
Who was that?
-Adam.
How are you guys? It's really late.
-It's fine, it's ready.
There aren't many boxes left.
Didn't I tell you it's not there?
I'm here with the food.
Grandma, what do we eat for Sukkot?
For Sukkot, we eat festive food,
but it has a secret spice.
Do you want to guess what the secret spice is?
Turmeric?
-Cumin?
No. Who raised you, girls?
The secret spice:
Sugar.
-Sugar?
Boy, what?
ﭏ נניּרע
אונ')
Does Mom know? Go, go, go to Mom,
go help her a bit with the decorations.
Where are the phone instructions?
That's it, Shani took the instructions
because I told her I could do without.
What?
Come on, what's going on?
-Good, come down and help him.
We're coming, we're coming.
Oh, is this it?
Are you from Adam?
-Yeah.
Come in, come in, but we're coming back soon.
Shai, nice to meet you, I'm the...
Do you think I should call
Itamar, see what's up with him?
Okay, relax, he's in the sukkah,
give him a couple of minutes of peace,
I think he'll appreciate that.
I want to go too.
-Come on, sweetheart, let's go.
I want that too.
-Bring it to her, let her set it up.
Okay, but all the way.
Not like that.
-No, no. You're cutting it too thick.
She doesn't do it all the way,
It's not the same loop size.
-Alright.
Come on, they're ruining it for me.
-Michal...
Girls, come downstairs to help Dad with the sukkah.
And Dad will be back soon, okay? I'll be right there.
-What the...
Great, now it's ruined.
Ohh
'Ohh
I'm from Adam.
From Adam.
Hey, happy holiday, I see you've met already.
-Yeah.
Tell me, what's up with the sukkah downstairs? Is it ready yet?
I went up to look for the assembly instructions.
Oh, instructions, I thought there was a size guide.
Yeah. By the way, enjoy the new phone.
Did you see the sukkah assembly instructions?
-No.
Mom.
-Adamika, where have you been? I was really worried.
Mom, did you see the sukkah assembly instructions?
Oh, I remember where I put them.
-Where?
In the box with the grill.
Pinchas will bring it soon.
-Okay.
Ohh
Pinchas!
Tell me, doesn't this new phone have an "app" for how to build a sukkah?
There is an "app" like that. It's in Norwegian.
Hey, Adam.
Hey, happy holiday.
-Hey, does Itamar need me?
No, no, no.
-Are you sure?
No, no, it's fine, Shai is already keeping him busy
scaring him with the hammer.
Tradition.
Meet her.
Ohh
'Ohh
She's from Adam.
-Oh.
Is this the last one?
-Yeah, if it's not here, I have no idea.
What's here?
-No, that's not it.
I remember you put it there.
At the end of Sukkot, you packed it and put it away.
Bingo.
-Got it? Did you find it?
The extension cords.
Why do you need an extension cord?
-What do you mean "why"?
I'm going to throw them from the balcony
to turn on the grill.
First, find the grill.
What happened?
Itamar hit my finger with a hammer.
-I missed the nail, what happened?
What nail?
Enough, come on, let's go to the kitchen.
What hammer? What nail?
This is a sukkah for eternity, no need to hammer anything.
What did you do there?
Honey!
He needs ice.
Margarine.
-What margarine?
Right, margarine is for burns.
He needs white-
_What white? What white? Is there more white?
Bring something.
Here, I have a diet one.
Oh, oh, this is nice, it's cool.
There's a lot of fruit in this.
And you’re okay, honey?
-Yeah, honey. I'm fine, sweetie.
What happened?
-It's not that easy to build this, Dad.
They tried to stabilize the first part in the parking lot.
Isn't it supposed to be the simplest thing in the world?
No, honey. Look, we already have one battle injury.
Stabilize what? Once you put it together, it's stable.
-Alright...
What's this?
-A diet-based pear.
What a bunch of losers.
-They say "not successful."
Why, what's the logic?
-Never mind.
But overall, she's right.
-Oh, really?
Yeah.
-So come on, let’s see you do it.
No problem. With one finger, easy.
But you’ll make chains with the girls.
No problem. With the other finger, easy.
-Great.
What, are you going with them, honey?
-Only if it's okay with you, honey.
Of course, honey.
Are you sure?
-Of course, honey.
Okay, honey, be available.
Okay, the girls are on the balcony.
-Sure.
Bye, honey.
-Bye, honey, bye.
Big problem, Shai.
Ohh
I'm from Adam.
I'm going to look for the garland in the bedroom.
If anyone asks, I went to help the girls.
Okay.
Great, girls.
-Great, girls.
Not great.
I think the yogurt got a bit warm.
Did you see that? Did you see? It's like a tank top.
The only way to solve this is
to give her more than she expects.
Tell me, have you lost it? It's a week until the finals.
Not bad, you can't really feel the diet.
Want to taste?
With fruit.
Want?
-Don't come near me at all.
Ah, there you are.
Pinchas, what did you do to me?
As if turning my kitchen upside down wasn't enough,
now you’re doing the bedroom too?
-I'll help you organize.
Yeah, and we both know very well
that you won't actually do it.
So?
-So. It's gone, it's gone.
It's okay, Pinchas, the girls made decorations,
so there won't be a garland.
Decorations aren't the same, that garland
was always with us
and made the prettiest sukkah, the kids love it.
Pinchas, the kids aren't kids anymore
and the kids of the kids would prefer
to have iPhones hanging from the ceiling.
And what about Independence Day?
-What's Independence Day got to do with this?
Oh.
-What?
-Where is it?
In the bathroom cabinet.
The garland?
-Yeah. That too.
I put it there after Independence Day
because I didn't want you to take out
all the boxes every time.
It makes a huge mess and I need to organize it.
No, it's not here.
-What size was it?
The size of a phone's instructions.
Is it here?
This... I’m sure she hid it for me.
Do you think they’re done assembling?
-I think so.
Honestly, I didn’t think they’d do it.
Just to challenge them, they can handle anything.
Good job, Shai.
A base touch, with my finger in the yogurt.
I think I messed up.
Somebody.
That was really, really...
That’s it, the girls just finished.
Whoa.
I found the last sock.
Who keeps something like that in the shower?
Wait, wait, hold on. How did you finish so fast?
Everything there was crazy, did you check out the poles?
Whoa
Listen, I’m jumping home to change clothes,
I’ll come back to pick you up later, is that okay?
Whoa
Alright, everything’s ready, we can go downstairs.
We need to take things down.
No one goes down empty-handed.
This is a sweet broccoli pie.
Honey?
Are you getting it?
-Yeah.
Come up, Mom will put white on you.
This is a sweet zucchini pie.
-You too, Riki.
Honey?
Did you happen to see the instructions for my phone?
-No.
It’s sugar, sweet.
Why, is there unsweet sugar, Mom?
Hey.
-Hey, did you see the instructions for my phone?
I’ve got cool curls on my head,
Diet.
Have you seen Itamar?
-No.
Honey, do me a favor, take this downstairs.
-What is it?
The beef in sugar.
-You think?
Honey?
Did you happen to see the instructions for my phone?
No, sweetie.
Honey?
Honey.
-Honey, where have you been?
Honey...
-Come on, I’ll go with you.
I couldn’t find you, I’ve been looking for you all the time.
Honey.
"Shlomit, the doll, a sukkah
lit up and looking good
that’s why she’s busy today
and it’s not just any sukkah
lit up and looking good
Shlomit, the doll, a sukkah of peace"
Alright. Friends, friends, before we start
I just want to say something! About Dad.
All the chaos today with the sock
was just Dad’s way
of telling you he really loves you.
Come on, Dad, light it up.
Happy holiday!
You should know that the dads really loved
the combo of Sukkot and Lag BaOmer together.
Lucky the fire department got here fast.
-Of course, what do you expect?
They also liked the pizzas, to be honest.
I swear I saw your mom
trying to sprinkle sugar on the triangles.
Okay, babe, I'm sorry for being cocky with the phone.
But I need the instructions, so...
Please give them back to me.
Apology accepted, but what do you mean
"give back the instructions"?
From where you hid them.
-I didn't hide the instructions from you.
What's that burnt smell?
The girl tried to save some decoration that fell from the sukkah.
So throw it away, she's out cold.
Fine.
I think I found your instructions.
Here you go.
-Okay, chill out,
I'll try to check something here!
!I'll sort it out, it'll be fine.
Wait.
Here.
Like this.
Like this, like this, and Lag, yeah.
Here, here, choose a language.
Oops, oh.
-What do you mean oops?
Come on, it came out in Russian.
-Blah.
Sukkot holiday.
-No, holiday agent...
No, but, but...
Why do I need instructions?
-For inspiration,
Okay?
-Okay.
Not great.
It's not like she's dragging me to all the museums...
What's the list?
Museums, restaurants, clubs,
I'm suffering from it,
don't get me wrong, but it's...
To all the museums, restaurants, clubs,
I'm suffering from it, don't get me wrong.
Bosses...