Oh no.
-What’s going on? What happened?
The brat.
-Saharuf?
No, I forgot to bring Itamar his "Bari."
The phone?
-That’s not good.
Alright, son, just bring it to him next week.
Are you crazy? That’s his "Bari."
What do you want? Just come back home and take it to him.
No, I’m not turning back,
he’s already on his way to your parents'.
Fine, okay, he can wait a few minutes.
Alone.
Yeah, alone, what could possibly happen?
With Itamar, anything can happen.
You have no idea what disasters
he’s caused and will cause.
When they set up an inquiry committee,
they’ll find out that in the Passover Haggadah,
it was him who sold the goat to Dad.
Alright, so what do you want?
I’ll take the girls upstairs to keep an eye on him
and you go get him his "Bari."
Hey, is there a chance you’ll come back
and I’ll go down with the girls to Grandma’s?
Yeah, no problem, babe, sure.
He has.
I’ll go back home, you go down with them.
Look at me, look at me and...
Hey, babe, don’t you think you’re overreacting a bit?
Not at all.
What happened? It’s just your brother,
why do you always make a mountain out of a molehill?
It’s funny, come on.
What “come on”? What, what, what could possibly happen?
I can already see myself if I come back,
I see you two holding each other by the throat.
The Hasson family test, oh, you forgot about that.
Alright, I can already see myself searching, like a detective,
where it all started, what happened,
only to find Itamar sitting there, smiling.
I think you forgot who you married.
Half an hour, babe.
-Go, take your time, what’s the problem?
Half an hour.
-Alright.
Good luck.
-Thanks.
You know!
That I loved you.
-Yeah, there was a rumor about that once.
Benon, at home.
Are you hearing what I’m saying?
It’s only fair that you and Mavi be partners.
But you’re not willing to be my partner.
-Why are you interfering?
She’s his sister, she can interfere.
-Enough with this behavior, that’s enough.
I want to be part of the group too.
Rachel, you knew all this, right?
I didn’t know anything, what do I know about these things?
He has a little kid.
-They have a little kid, aren’t you ashamed?
Whatever, Menachem, whatever.
Just give me the "Bari," let me go.
Pull over, turn off the engine. What’s going on here?
Your wife’s crazy family. Has nothing to do with me at all.
Not your business. Listen to me carefully,
you’re not moving from here and getting nothing
until I understand what happened,
where you were and what you did.
Shh_
Your mom and my mom are the same mom.
-Okay.
What happened here?
-What happened here? A world fight, that’s what happened here.
By the way, did you notice Alin’s shoes,
how disgusting they are?
Sit down, can you calm down and explain to me what happened
and start from the beginning, please.
Okay, okay, so you took them downstairs.
Because you wanted Itamar and me to not be here alone,
by the way, he showed up right on time today,
did you notice that when he's without his wife
suddenly his watch works, right?
Sit down.
-What?
Dude.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Come here, my sweet.
What's up?
-Shabbat Shalom. Yeah.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Hey there.
Do you remember Itamar?
-Of course I remember, how could I forget?
I already apologized, right?
-Yeah, yeah.
Everything's been forgotten and forgiven a long time ago.
Come on, come in. Why are you shy?
Where's Shai?
He went to get your son,
he forgot him too.
What a fool.
What, are you here because he was scared to leave you alone?
Why would he be scared?
-I don't know.
Come on, who's scared? Nobody's scared.
Come on, I'll cut you a piece of mezhalof.
-Oh, tasty.
His brother, that's my family, right?
Watch your nonsense.
Stop it. What, are you a kid? Come on, sit down.
So from what you understood, Itamar's coming into the kitchen
for a piece of mezhalof.
-Yeah.
What does he want?
-His phone.
So why don't you give it to him?
-Because I want to know what he did.
So he ate the mezhalof and didn't like it.
What do you mean? Who said he didn't like it?
He threw you some comments, said something inappropriate.
He didn't say anything. Who said he didn't like it?
So what’s everyone fighting about?
-I don’t know.
I don’t understand these things.
I can't believe he didn't like the mezhalof.
He told me it was really tasty.
It's very tasty, uh...
-How nice.
Very.
So what's up? How are the parents, the kids?
Your wife?
-She's good.
I heard she got her license.
-Yeah, yeah, she had to
because she started studying
and I'm not driving her to class every morning.
Yeah, sure, sure, sure.
And how's business?
You know how it is in business.
-No, I don't know, what...
I don't understand these things.
-Yeah.
Hey, did you see the Mercedes outside?
Purple. What kind of car color is that? Who buys a purple car?
Your wife.
Wow, Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Who is that? He looks familiar.
Shai's brother.
-Itamar.
Itamar.
Enjoy your meal.
-Thanks.
Isn’t he the one who broke up with you at the hospital?
Yeah.
What is this, an interrogation?
-No.
Just a few questions.
What happened? I feel guilty.
Please sit down, what’s wrong?
Relax, don’t stress.
Rachel told me you talked to my brother.
What, was that not allowed? No one told me.
He actually seems like a great guy, your brother, just so you know.
What's wrong with him?
-Everything's fine with him.
I want you to tell me everything that happened from the beginning.
So here’s the thing.
Where are we going to get 350,000 shekels now?
Don’t worry, babe, it’ll be fine, son.
We can manage like this, we can wait on the renovation.
I don’t want to, I don’t want to wait anymore.
Do you mind not starting with that
until after you’ve met my brother?
So just say it.
So here’s the thing.
So what, the Mercedes outside is yours, huh?
Yeah.
Great color.
You’re making a lot of money, huh?
-Come on, Moshe, enough. What?
No, it’s fine. You know, we’re making a living.
Why not? Cheers, what, I’m just curious.
Don’t you want your daughter’s husband to have a Mercedes too?
What do I know? I don’t understand these things.
So what, Itamar,
what do you do, if I can ask?
I’m an entrepreneur, real estate.
-Real estate is really hot these days, huh?
All the tycoons are in real estate now.
Where are you building?
I’m not building anything, I’m an entrepreneur.
Where’s the money from?
-Come on, Moshe. Enough, it’s not...
I had a few successful deals in Varna.
Where’s Varna?
-By the Adriatic Sea.
Where’s the Adriatic Sea?
Okay, Moshe, forget it, it’s really not that great.
For every successful deal, there are plenty that fail.
And
Of course, of course.
-Yeah.
So what are you working on right now?
I have an office that deals with organizing
groups for purchasing agricultural land
that will eventually be approved for housing.
I’ve heard about those approvals.
You make a lot of money, huh?
-Come on, enough, let him eat, that’s enough.
You know, every deal has
its chances and its risks.
Right now, for example, we have a plot
that’s up for sale, something near Givat Ada,
it’s just waiting for final approval.
You realize that right now a dunam is 13,700,
but once it gets the approval,
it’ll jump to at least 350.
What do you say?
-Yeah.
But Moshe,
not every deal is a good deal, there’s risk.
Of course, of course.
-Of course.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Come on, are you done playing detective?
Let me get out of here already.
-Not yet.
At least let me check if I got any messages.
After that, I’ll get back to you.
Did you call me?
Itamar, give us a moment.
Can you explain to me what happened from the beginning?
So here’s the thing...
Who loves Shabbat? Mom and Dad
Who loves Shabbat? Grandma and Grandpa
Who loves Shabbat
Me.
You.
-And you.
Almost the whole world.
Who loves to eat mezilof?
Me!
Not from this beginning.
I was on the balcony, Moshe shows up, at the conference,
closes the door
and asks me for money!
Manny, can you lend me some cash?
-No problem.
So what, I heard you talked to my brother.
'Right?
He's a really nice guy,
he and my son have a lot in common.
Owen...
-Why Owen?
I don’t know if you know,
but my grandfather, may he rest in peace,
was offered, along with his friends,
to buy twenty dunams of village land for an orchard.
Where that tall tower is, at the city gate, that one.
But my grandfather, poor guy, was a naive man, you know?
By the time he and his friends managed to gather the money,
then Chafif, one of his friends, his best buddy,
Eliezer Chafif,
he just cooked him on the whole deal.
He went to the land registry, signed as Chafif, and took off.
And stole the whole deal right under his nose, you get it?
About his pride in that tower,
it's "Chafif Towers," over there, at the city gate.
It used to be "Hasson Towers."
Silvan, are you telling the stories
about your grandfather's orchard again?
Tell me, come on, would you
buy an apartment from a contractor named Chafif?
Enough, come on, let him eat.
Eat, eat, finish the mezilof,
I have plenty of business stories for you.
Get out of my way already.
Chafif, Silvan.
Don't you dare say that name again, got it?
Chafif, he tells me.
He's completely lost it. He has a kid, a new baby,
and he's wasting my money like I don't know what.
Our expenses have gone up and Sivan is not a baby,
he's a growing baby, he eats, he needs toys
and we want to go on vacation, it's crazy.
What did you do?
-I lent Moshe some money.
Without asking me?
-Why ask you, babe? It's Moshe.
No one else is seeing that money.
It's family.
-It's not family, it's Moshe!
Oops, sorry.
Anyway, did you see that Sarav Av! Alin
!he's bummed about it.
So I decided I'm going to talk to him.
Sorry, I don’t want to interrupt
but Shai, I'm talking to you as an adult,
I’d like to please leave here.
No.
What happened?
-She got upset that I lent Moshe money.
And you gave it to him?
Tell me, what are you, crazy?
Don’t you remember the problem he has?
Put 250 shekels on "Maccabi Afula."
Put 400 shekels on Rexi.
שים לי 250 שקל על "מכבי עפולה".
שים לי 400 שקל על רקסי.
Put 1,600 on Tel Aviv,
23 degrees, partly cloudy to clear.
Here.
No way, I'm sure it's not for gambling.
Tell me, what are you, a fool?
So why is it if it's not for gambling?
Moshe!
They don't appreciate me enough in this family, Shai.
Why do you think that?
They won't let me fit in,
they're holding me back from growing.
They feel threatened by me.
Everyone here is closing deals
and exchanging info among themselves
like it's nothing, without explaining what's going on.
Wow, great.
Are you ready to explain what's happening?
I'm going for it, I want a dunam.
What, are you talking about the Givat Ada group?
No, no, no, no. Forget it, you don't want that.
Yes, I do.
No, no. Moshe, seriously,
I don't even have final approval for that group yet.
Just drop it.
I'm serious with you, Itamar,
you can trust me in business—
3,700, deal, I'm in.
Write down my number.
-I don't have a phone right now,
my "berry" is with Shai. That's why I'm here.
I'm writing yours, zero five...
Here.
We'll talk on Sunday.
So what, Itamar, mixing business with pleasure?
Buying a group, I hear.
Soccer?
-No way.
My office organizes buying groups.
Very nice.
I never understood what those groups are about.
They're businesspeople getting together
to buy properties together.
What do you say?
-Yeah.
I'm all for businesspeople
and property arrangements, of course.
So, how many friends are in each group?
It varies, it can start with three friends,
a few dozen, a few hundred,
a few thousand, theoretically endless.
And practically?
Right now, there's a guy in the group with sixty members.
We're mainly talking about friends with money?
I really hope so.
So, are there special acceptance rituals
for these arrangements?
No, all you need is to have money.
Very nice.
-Very nice.
What's the success rate?
Tell me, did you know
that Moshe had a gambling problem?
Of course. What, didn't you know?
It got really weird.
Bro, I'm a bit short on cash,
can you put that on "Hapoel Usfiya"?
can you put that on Lassi?
Bro, I'm a bit short on cash,
put that on Be'er Sheva, 30 degrees hot and dry.
Here.
I checked, it's really not for gambling.
-So why did he need the loan?
That's exactly what I asked them.
-What?
Tell me, Moshe, why
did you need the loan?
Manny, what's up? Why are you stressed? I'll get back to you.
I'm stressed? Remind you of your problem?
You didn't even know you had one.
What problem, Manny? I'm not betting anymore,
I haven't touched it in weeks.
I swear, I won't even do small bets.
Until I check it on Wikipedia first.
Moshe, you're not answering me, just say "yes" or "no."
Do you need that money to gamble?
Manny, I swear, I care about you,
with girls, I'm done.
I was weak, but now I'm strong.
Manny, this is a deal,
a financial deal, a real opportunity,
You put in 13,700 today. Soon
you'll have returns, at least 350.
A financial deal?
-A real one.
Listen to me, Moshe,
If I hear you touched that money to gamble,
I'll come down on you hard
with all my weight. You hear me?
No need, Manny, I swear, my word as Moshe Katz.
Can I go back inside?
I'm sorry, I have one more question for you.
I can't concentrate
when your brother is making poodle faces.
Maybe give him back the phone.
-I don't want to.
What do you know about Moshe's deal?
-What deal?
I don't know anything. I don't understand these things.
Can I go back inside?
-Okay, fine.
Thanks.
What's good for Nochi Dankner is good for Moshe Katz.
She's not lying, you know?
She really doesn't understand anything about this stuff.
Itamar, I want to talk to you.
Alin, I need a moment, but...
Rachel, I'm on my way to...
Sit down, don't be rude.
I want to get in on a deal for about ten acres too.
I thought you didn't understand this stuff.
-I don't, but...
My bank manager, my fund manager, and my accountant,
they know a lot about this, so they'll
talk to you on Sunday, okay?
Yeah.
Good, run, run, before it slips away.
I heard you were seen
saying to Shani that she's rude?
Maybe, I can't commit to that.
Meirav.
I don't remember.
What do you want to know?
Why did you tell her she's rude?
Sit down, I need help.
-What happened, babe?
I need a sum of money.
-Why, what happened?
Okay, you heard there's a
group of single men with money and assets.
So why do you need money?
-Entry fee.
Alright, how much is it?
-13,700 shekels.
How much?
It's an exclusive group of friends
made up of very private businesspeople.
Are you crazy? What, are you opening a brothel?
Were you even listening to me?
-I was listening, I'm not giving you that money.
Well, great.
So I don't get it,
are you joining this group or not?
No, thanks to Esther,
but your lovely brother agreed to help me.
Let him burn in hell.
Itamar was in the bathroom.
Itamar, I thought about it.
When I think about things
I think them through.
I also know that alongside the sting, there's honey
and your honey might not be my honey,
but for you, everything's business.
It's clear to me that for me to join
your lovely exclusive group,
I need to pay a laundry fee of 13,700 shekels.
What’s also clear is that money
will be worth a lot more in the future.
So here’s the deal, I’m making a one-time offer,
that you lend me the 13,700 shekels now,
and in the future, when that honey comes in,
I’ll give you, pay attention, 50,000.
Nice, right?
You want me to give you 13,000 shekels, basically?
How sweet of you.
-No.
You see, Shai? Not everyone’s a fool like you.
But, what’s your name?
So from what you’ve gathered so far, Moshe asked me for money,
Meirav asked you for money and then my brother,
and your mom has a fund manager.
If you say so, Sherlock Homeless.
So the shouting isn’t because of Itamar.
I told you that from the start.
It started with me after he talked to Moshe.
So, what did he say?
-Everything’s fine, nothing to worry about,
he got a tip about a good deal,
some buying group,
something! from some private businesses, something! like that.
But you know, it’s Moshe,
you can’t understand much from him.
Seriously, private businesses.
That sounds familiar to me this week.
Wait, are you talking about money?
You can’t talk about money on Shabbat
and you don’t mix money and family.
Rachel, do me a favor, stop getting involved.
I’m not getting involved, I’m not getting involved.
Well, what I did manage to understand
is that today they’re buying for 13,700
and when the compromise happens, it’ll be worth at least 350.
13,700?
-Yeah.
That amount sounds familiar to me too.
Shai, you can relax.
Trust me, it’s not for gambling, okay?
Alright, fine, got it, not for gambling.
But I hope you’re going to
get something from that at least 350.
What?
-No, are you completely crazy?
Don’t you get that with the money you’re giving Moshe
he’s going to get rich off your back?
Moshe!
What?
Come here, come here.
-What?
Tell me, you said in the end it’ll come out to
something like 350 at least, right?
At least.
Great, so tell me, am I supposed to get something from that
or am I just here to be your ladder for thieves
and wait for you behind the wall until you come back?
Why, why thieves, why talk like that, what.
Why did Moshe take money from you?
-He didn’t take, he borrowed.
But what, he wants to cut you out of the profits.
That’s exactly what happened to my grandfather.
Exactly.
They’re cooking you, Menachem, they’re cooking you.
You see, Shai, not everyone’s a fool,
there are those who are willing to help.
Manny, why are you talking like that?
You asked me for a loan, you said, no problem,
there’s a problem? No need. Well, that’s great.
He won't give it back to you, I'm telling you,
he won't give it back, you'll see.
Alin, just relax, okay?
-You shouldn't interfere at all.
Well, it's better to have a close friend than a faraway love.
Who's interfering?
-What happened?
You'll wake up and find
"Katz Towers" by the city gate.
My husband lends money to idiots, that's what happened.
You asked my brother for a loan?
-What loan, no way,
just an initial amount for investment, that's it.
And Manny just wanted to check.
Listen to what I'm saying
this is about you and me being partners.
But you're not willing to be my partner.
-Why are you interfering?
She's his sister, she can interfere.
Enough with this behavior, that's enough.
-I want to be part of the group too.
Rachel, you knew all this, right?
-I didn't know anything,
what do I know about these things?
They have a little kid.
-They have a little kid, aren't you ashamed?
Chill out, Menachem, chill out!
So all this mess, it's not because of Itamar?
No, you didn't listen to me at all, did you?
You see? Here, please, thank you, sit down,
I told you, it's not my fault at all,
it's your family's fault,
something's wrong with your family.
Yeah, they're messed up.
-No, they're crazy.
Nuts.
-No, it's a total loss.
Total loss.
-They need hospitalization, I'm telling you.
Give it.
-What?
Fun. What? It's my knee.
Take.
-Thank you very much.
Go home, go.
Ugh.
-What now?
I thought it was because of Itamar
so I could have solved it.
He would have apologized, everything would have been fine.
So, what now? Why are you making a big deal?
My family, they heat up
just as quickly as they cool down, okay?
It's not like your family.
Sorry, I just wanted to say goodbye
because I'm leaving, I got this.
And thanks for the hospitality,
it was really very...
Every time I meet this family
I say you have a family that really...
there's nothing like it,
really, all the... have a good week and salam.
Moshe, you see? Here, I got an email.
The Givat Ada project fell through. No approvals.
You see? I told you, that's how it is.
Oh, and Rachel, so I probably won't need
to call your fund manager,
so thanks and sorry.
So, have a week...
Good.
What do I know?
I don't understand these things.
It was fun today at Grandma's.
Of course, it's always fun, we love Grandma and Grandpa.
No, because everyone was screaming.
I told you that Itamar alone is trouble.
You should have kept an eye on him.
Yeah, and you should have
not forgotten about his knee.
Sorry, did I tell you or not to keep an eye on him?
I know them! I said it.
So you told me, so you told me, so what?
And now I'm telling you that next week
my sister Meirav will be at your parents' house.
No.
-Closed.
What, you don't think you're overdoing it a bit?
What, I came here, surprised you?
-Not at all, not at all.
This is my family, right? Watch your nonsense.
Of course.
By the way, did you see that woman's husband?
How gross are they?
Sit... that woman?
Sit!
Oh, right, this isn't for gambling?
So if it's not for gambling, what is it?
What is it?
What happened?
-Now it's Avi, I don't know...
Were you even listening to me?
Sit down, that's your name,
you're not getting that money from me,
Are you hearing me?