Look, I managed to connect through the phone,
I can see the little one.
Honey, this doesn't feel right to me.
What's not comfortable?
You can see exactly what they're doing, so...
Look, they're watching TV.
Do you know how much that costs through the phone?
I don't get it, I really don't get it,
How does it help me now that you can see them?
What, we're gonna get a massage and I'll just watch the kids?
What, are you out of your mind?
Everyone's putting cameras for the babysitter these days,
It's a no-brainer.
It's crazy not to do it.
I know her. She's a sweet girl, she's a soldier,
She's Mordechai's daughter from the vegetable stand.
We just need to check her out, that's all,
This way we'll be more relaxed next time, right...
It's not like I'm taking her, I'm not taking her.
She'll stay with your parents
and they can babysit the babysitter.
I really think it's genius.
Yeah, it's genius,
a genius.
Tell me, Mr. Genius.
If it's just you and me alone in the car and the kids aren't here.
Why are we hearing this?
Eli, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
What’s this, where are the girls? You came without the girls?
I told you, Shai wants us to check the babysitter.
Yeah. Shabbat Shalom.
I thought Dad and I would babysit, right?
Right, for the babysitter.
I set up a security camera at home
and it films the living room and streams straight here to the computer.
So I just need you to keep an eye every now and then.
No, I didn't understand, I didn't understand.
You're filming your house?
No, it's not you, it's him.
I told you you're not normal.
Shai just wants you to watch
so we can relax when we leave her.
But you don't have to worry, she's a lovely girl,
she's, you know, that one, Gila's daughter.
From the vegetable stand?
The vegetables, the wife of the vegetable guy? I didn't know.
What a sweet girl.
What, is it not enough what they did to her mom?
I'm saying it for the second time, it's not you, it's him.
And what did they do to her mom?
Pulling her hair without receipts.
Why didn't you bring the kids?
What am I supposed to do now,
follow the poor girl's daughter?
Seriously, what, am I a spy?
Come here.
What’s this, isn’t that the baby monitor for the little one?
It requires a password.
I don't want to peek.
Dude, it's just to keep Shai calm.
We're coming back in two and a half hours.
Fine, whatever.
He's in the room, not feeling so great,
The problem came back.
You know, that issue with R...
I heard the bell is working again.
I told you could've
We have enough babies here.
Good morning, princess,
Good morning.
Is this all that's left of the drizzle?
Sali.
Do you really have to call with that thing?
Why don't you just call me?
That's it.
I heard more people came in.
Can I know what you guys are talking about over there?
Shai and Shani arrived,
No, I can't go to the living room if I want to.
There's no way you want to.
Rachel, I have...
I have a request for you.
Don't talk to the kids about the...
About my medical issue.
Not everything needs to be known by the whole house.
It's my body,
It's my privacy,
I don't need the whole world
This is my private space.
Okay, I promise not to tell anything,
Your private stuff.
Not even about the test.
Hey, it's working.
That's Bar, their babysitter.
Sit down, it's working.
She's watching TV with the girls in the living room.
Good. Great, babe, come on, can we go now?
Does it have sound too?
Witches only exist in fairy tales.
And dwarfs?
No, I can't believe you guys are peeking at people like that.
No, it's not us, it's him.
Babe, come on, we're late for the massage.
But...
Help me in the kitchen.
Good quality, right?
Shabbat shalom.
What's that? What do you see?
Shai and Shani are peeking at their babysitter.
That's Bar, she's a soldier,
she's the daughter of that guy from the veggies, that girl from the cheeses.
Wow, that's Bar, Tsahi's sister from the checks.
Veggies, cheeses, and checks?
She has a nice family, a good family.
Oh man, if Tsahi from the checks...
No, no, no, it's not us, it's Shai.
I'm fine with it, I...
I made a little mistake.
Turns out he doesn't want anyone to know that his...
No, he's stressed about the test.
So do me a favor, don’t tell anyone I told you, okay?
Sure, of course.
Believe me, you're right, these days you never know.
Alon, we need to put one too.
Who would put a camera like that in their house?
I'm the only one taking care of your kids.
Shabbat Shalom.
Hey, what's this?
They just sent me the kid who's guarding a cat.
Shai installed a camera for his babysitter.
Whoa, criminal! What did she do?
So far, not too much.
I once dated a private investigator,
I think he was a private investigator.
Working.
Okay, Orna, I want to talk to them for a second.
Honey, I'm talking to Orna for two minutes
because I don’t want to be late for the massage.
Just a reminder, that's why we hired the babysitter.
Alright, alright, just make sure everything's okay.
Okay, move a bit, let me see too.
Hey, see? It works, I fixed it.
This is your part, the part of me that stayed in the living room.
Now Rachel can hear you without the bell.
What’s that?
It’s the baby monitor for Shavi's little one,
Rachel took it out of place.
Feel better, Silvan.
What you’re doing isn’t right,
I think you don’t know how to respect.
Come on, enough, enough.
Respect her, it’s her wish.
It’s just a test.
What, why do something like that?
You need to be careful, and it’s good he’s being cautious,
it’s just a camera.
Rachel.
Oh my God, no way. What now?
Rachel!
You hear me, right? I told you.
Oh, poor thing.
Anyway, turns out Mom told me
he’s a bit embarrassed about the whole thing,
and she told me before he could tell her.
Anyway, don’t talk about it.
No, no, no, sure, of course, of course.
I’ll just tell Alon not to tell my mom.
Rachel!
You told them.
Why? Why? Why did you tell them?
Why?
What am I talking about?
I’m asking you nicely,
and you go and tell the whole world. Great.
I don’t understand what you’re talking about.
Let me tell you what I'm talking about,
I heard.
I heard it here.
That he needs privacy,
that he needs to be careful,
that I'm... I'm not...
I'm not who I used to be, I heard it here,
and that's why the check-up.
Sali,
I don't know what you heard, but...
I swear to you, I swear to you
what you heard is about Bar.
Who's Bar?
Bar, Gila's daughter from the eyebrows and Mordechai from the veggies,
she's the babysitter for Shai and Shani now.
So Shai is filming her with a hidden camera
and he's doing some kind of check-up with the camera.
Are you happy?
What, have they completely lost it?
That's Nissim's granddaughter from the oranges.
Maya, Maya, what's wrong? Why are you crying?
Bar, I want chocolate milk.
First, calm down and don't do anything stupid.
Wait, okay?
Call my mom, I want in. Wait.
I can't believe it, she's not giving the girl chocolate milk.
Sit down.
Don't you see Maya's hysterical?
What happened?
Oh, oh, oh,
Moshe, honey, come help me in the kitchen for a sec.
But he's on the phone with hysterical Maya.
Do you think he's in love with someone else?
And did he do something with her? No way.
Who did?
What did he do to her?
Moshe, what did I ask you?
Right, I asked you to install
because he's driving you crazy with the bell.
Oh boy.
So you installed it.
But the other way around.
The other way?
Instead of us hearing him,
he hears every word we're saying.
Oh, oh, oh, what do we do?
Go into his room and switch the parts.
Sure.
Does he want you to meet?
So that's it, honey, he broke up with me.
Wow, honey, I'm sure, that's the saddest thing ever.
You'd think, what a hysteria,
he totally wants to leave her,
of course you can come hang out with me for a bit,
in exactly one minute I'll wave to you from the balcony.
What do you mean she can come?
Come on already, I'm waiting for you, bye.
So who wanted chocolate milk?
Me!
And who wanted it first?
I
You see, you coward, she is bringing them chocolate milk.
I knew it, I knew from the moment
she loves him, and at this age, it’s just suffering.
Are you telling me?
She said her friend is coming in two minutes.
Did you do something about it?
Did you do anything about it?
Silvan, Rachel asked for it to be the other way around,
I’m asking you, leave it as it is.
So I can hear what you’re talking about, okay?
But she asked me, she insists,
I’m not feeling good about her.
You want to feel bad about me?
Go over there and turn it on, please.
Hello.
Come on, let’s think about a song, let’s go, let’s go.
Here comes her friend.
Hey babe, don’t worry, everything will be fine.
Tell me, are you okay with what’s happening there?
Yeah, what could happen?
Don’t you understand I’m missing my massage?
The friend is here.
Come on.
But you can see her heart is hurting.
Ben, pay attention to the movie.
But it’s boring.
I know, but my friend Maya
So maybe you can go to the playroom
and I’ll come later to put on a movie for you, okay?
No, I’m not okay with that,
call her.
I don’t know what to do, Ben,
I thought that...
I thought we’d always be together,
I don’t think I’ll even manage to talk to him.
I, it’s a miracle.
Shh... you’re interrupting.
Please.
If you tell him you’re pregnant
No, I would never do such a thing.
What a shame.
No, her boyfriend left her, she’s not pregnant.
Babe, can we go already?
Ben, come here for a sec.
Leave it, Ben.
Can’t you see you’re interrupting?
Listen, your mom asked me
just that, after she already told Orna
and Orna asked me not to tell anyone,
just that, I already told it
so keep it a secret.
It’s fine, I didn’t tell anyone.
Babe
Why are you whispering?
To your dad, the baby monitor
but I got confused between the parts,
and now he won’t let me
and that’s the part that listens.
Listen, that’s not what’s important right now.
What I told you about my dad...
No one can know.
Rachel!
Enough with the bell already,
This, this,
What are you guys talking about over there?
Can you come to the living room?
You told them, I know you.
I didn't tell them.
Can you come to the living room?
No, I'm not coming to the living room.
That's it, I'm not coming.
So enough, stop with the bell.
No one is talking about you, enough already.
So now I have a babysitter to deal with.
Girls, do you want to watch a movie in the room or the living room?
And do you want a movie plus popcorn?
Yes.
Alright, popcorn.
Come on, can we go? Right now?
Ugh, it's so hot.
Why did you only set up one camera?
Mary, come here for a sec, I want to talk to you.
Come on, babe, the girls are watching a movie,
Come on, we've already missed the massage,
at least let's enjoy the spa facilities.
Okay, I gotta go,
I really don't think so.
So tell him to come up here.
Okay, I'll call him.
Alright, I guess I gave up on the spa.
What did I tell you about Dad? I didn't know it was a secret,
so don't tell him you know about the... this and...
The tests are tomorrow.
And don't tell anyone else, not just Dad,
just don't talk about it, okay?
Is that why you brought me here?
Tell me, what, are you crazy?
You only think about yourself, broken Maya.
What did I miss?
I can't believe you, when?
That's him.
How did it happen so fast?
Mary, I'm glad he's here.
Whoa.
Okay, we're going home.
Wow, he's handsome.
Seriously, he really is handsome.
Okay, I'm going to watch a movie with the girls in the room,
you can feel at home here.
This is my house!
Babe, come on, you're breaking my heart,
he's lying, I can spot those a mile away.
I need to get this off my chest.
I need to pee.
Hello, calm down, you're talking about my daughter.
Shai, just so you know, it looks really good,
I got this from a friend who does industrial espionage.
It's nothing, you have this flexible tube.
And at the end, there's a camera attached.
And you can adjust the camera.
You know, zoom in, zoom out, all that.
And you can even get into every tiny little hole.
You don't feel a thing, nothing at all,
You can really move it in all directions and everything.
But this one is simple, it only has one angle.
And then a kiss.
That's it, I'm done peeing.
Hello.
Yeah, Sali, I'm coming.
Moshe, didn't you say you fixed this?
But it's closed.
It's not right for my daughter to see something like this.
Got it?
Come on, let's give them some privacy,
Let's go to the room, I'll play with you.
Give me that, give me that.
I'm struggling too, I'm sad, understand me.
So come on, at least let's take a break,
I don't believe in breaks.
In these moments, I think like Meirav.
Listen, sit down, she's finishing the babysitting today
and we're not calling her again.
Okay, so we'll meet here in a week.
Please, Shai, come on, give her another chance,
we'll pay for the spa next week.
We'll also pay the babysitter.
What now?
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
I can relate to that.
Come on, what's going on?
Everything was fine, sweetie.
Okay, I think I'm gonna head out.
Talk to me when you leave here.
Okay, I have about an hour and a half left.
I'll talk to you when I'm done.
Fun,
the next one will be joyful.
Okay, what time is it?
It can't end like this.
What do you want, this isn't a reality show,
who’s there?
What are you doing here?
That's it, Maya and I broke up,
I told you.
It's okay.
Can you help me?
Are you sure that...
Come on, see for yourself that no one talked about you.
I don't know what to do,
I love Maya too! Maya loves you too,
it's hard.
I know.
But what we have is stronger than anything.
Sit down.
Wait, I'm going to check on the girls in the room.
Her mom.
Come on, let's get home now.
Come on, come on, come on already,
Because of you, I'm missing the best part, come on.
Great spy camera.
We need to call Shai,
You think so?
I couldn't do it with them in the room, that's not right.
But I'm almost done.
I get you, you're pulling a trick with Maya, huh?
-What what?
Are you going to post this on Facebook? YouTube?
What are you talking about?
Alright, bye.
It's fine, no big deal.
Let's sit! Later's good.
Bring that.
Great, it's fine, he left,
She's with the girls in the living room, she's crying.
No, she's really not okay, really.
Really, really not.
No, I'll talk to her and I don't care about Mordechai.
Wait, wait, wait,
Mordechai from the veggies is Shaul's brother.
Come on.
Come on, what is everyone trying to tell you?
So we can't really be mad at her.
Look how she's crying,
Look at this poor girl sitting in the living room.
Honey, I'm running away.
I see her, enough.
Pay her more.
Don't cry.
That's it, I don't think this is going anywhere.
Alright, that's it. Manny, home.
Bye.
What is this, nothing happened after all?
Dad, since when are you here? Everything okay?
I've been here the whole time and everything's fine.
Really. Have a good week.
Come on, should we get moving too?
Have a good week, honey.
Okay, I'm in my room.
Sylvia, love you.
Have a good week.
You see, isn't it better that you're here?
Mom, Dad, Bar is sad.
We can see that, I mean.
Is everything okay?
We got here a bit early so...
Thanks.
Bye.
It's really good they're not mad at her.
Did you pay her more? Of course.
Great, at least that's behind us.
Come on. Come on, sweeties, come on.
How nice he forgot to turn off the camera.
It's not nice to peek.
All day it's fine to peek,
like all day you weren't spying on us,
they're talking about me, saying things about me, you told them.
See, fact is, no one knows anything.
What a scene this whole "Had Gadya" thing is, huh?
What?
Shmonee told me before Alon asked him
before you told her not to say anything
that Silvan told her about his test.
Honestly, yeah, you're right.
Come on, grab a pillow, babe.
I once dated a criminal investigator,
can we pick up from here?
Give me that thing, uh...
what's it called?
Babe, did you turn off the camera?
Crap.