Dad, play it again.
Tell me, don’t they get tired of hearing
that song over and over and over?
And you don’t get tired of watching soccer?
-What are you comparing?
What do you care what they listen to?
As long as it’s quiet.
Is this quiet? I can’t
listen to that song anymore.
Then stop it. Let’s see you.
-What do you think, I don’t have the guts?
I don’t know.
-I’m stopping it.
Stop.
There. I stopped. Girls, I’m sorry
but Dad’s sanity is at stake.
I really hope you understand
but Dad is begging, enough with that song.
Oh, it’s quiet.
-Wait.
I need to pee.
-I want a little sister too.
Play it again.
Got it?
-Yeah.
It’s quiet.
Look at me, look at me. And...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-So, where have you been? I was already worried.
Come on, come on, girls, come on.
Sit down.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Why are the girls half-naked?
-Because it’s hot outside.
But that’s not modest.
-Riki, they’re kids.
Okay, okay, why are you getting confused? What did I say?
That she dresses her daughters like whores maybe?
Pinchas...
-Meet her, this is...
When do we eat? I’m starving. Is there schnitzel?
No, wait, wait, hold on a second, before the schnitzels.
I have a surprise.
-Oh no.
How nice. Are you pregnant?
-No, no, no.
This is the ultrasound video.
What do you mean, Dad?
-No, it’s...
Why “what do you mean”?
Why did you bring this
when I told you at home not to bring it? Right?
So you took advantage of the fact that I have
a small bladder and when I went to the bathroom...
Bam!
-Come on, enough. Enough.
Come on, Michali, what’s the surprise?
-So, I won the trial.
Wow...
-And I got the video.
Great.
-Awesome.
Congratulations.
-Someone filmed me once too.
I thought about suing him.
-No, no...
No, it’s our wedding video.
Of course, it’s about time. So many weeks of trial...
Okay, so come on, do you want to see it?
When?
-No. Come on, babe, drop it.
I told you at home. People
don’t want to see that right now.
Maybe after the food?
-Why? So you can say
that your kids are tired and bail?
-No, because I’m a bit hungry.
Come on, I’m dying to see it.
I wasn’t at the wedding after all.
Just so you know, sit down, people really talked about it
that it’s not nice you weren’t at the wedding.
I was in the delivery room, Riki.
-I know.
I’m just saying people talked.
-Okay, is the movie long?
No, it’s only three hours, come on.
Come on, babe, why the fuss now? Really.
We don’t have to watch everything. Come on, Adam,
talk to them. They’re so heavy. Come on.
Sit down, you were on epidural during that time.
I need to see it sober.
-What, aren’t you curious to see it?
Dude, I watch it a lot.
-You have to! There. For what?
Okay, I’m putting it on. I have to see.
Just a little.
-Oh, babe.
Tasty.
-Really tasty.
Really tasty.
Get up, get up.
It's starting, it's starting, it's starting.
-Oh, Shai, really tasty.
Okay, you’ve met her already. Enough, pest.
-No, but I didn’t say...
Tell me, what are you, a kid?
"Will you marry me, my love? Be my wife?
And give me your hand! I’ll stay by your side."
Heartfelt.
I'm dying, I can't take it.
"Come on, let’s swear by love
I’ll give you a ring at the wedding
I promise you, my woman
I’ll keep you forever like my heart
Because without you, my love, I can’t go on
So excited about you and don’t know how to ask
Will you marry me, my love? Be my wife?
And give me your hand and I’ll stay by your side."
"I’m dying.
-It’s like a cheesy movie.
But what did you expect? You dragged that photographer
to court for five weeks. This is what you got.
Mom, I’m dying...
Turn off the camera.
-Wait, just a second, babe.
I’ll break it for you.
-Babe, stop.
No! Stop. Babe, stop!
"Will you marry me, my love? Be my wife?
And give me your hand..."
Okay, son, can we stop this now?
Do you get it? According to the ruling
they were supposed to give us
the wedding video edited properly,
but because of the lawsuit...
they included everything unnecessary on purpose.
Michal, if I were you, I’d sue them again.
Let’s go eat.
-Wait, wait, come on, wait.
Maybe it gets better later in the wedding.
Just hold on, I want to see.
Just because you chose not to be at the wedding
doesn’t mean we all have to suffer.
I didn’t choose, Riki.
I gave birth. It’s not a choice.
You knew the wedding date.
You could have had a C-section a week earlier.
Mom, enough.
-Okay. What did I say?
I’m just saying people do things like that.
Okay, okay, I want to see what they did to me.
No, babe, why ruin a wedding
that in your memory was wonderful
and had great alcohol?
-Yeah, the slivovitz.
Look. The reception.
-I, son, babe.
I want to see that too.
Hello. Thank you, thank you very much.
Come here. Listen, go sit down.
Hello.
What was that?
No, it was like a jump in the movie.
Suddenly blinked one moment too long.
How many people did she invite?
I don’t know half of the friends here.
-Mom, they’re not.
Hey, here are my parents and my sister.
-Hello.
Congratulations.
-Good to see you. Congratulations to you too.
Thank you very much, thank you very much.
Really, you didn’t have to come. Thank you.
Did I tell you?
-She’s laughing.
You see, it’s not even edited. There’s no music.
I'm telling you, this is going to end badly.
It's his wedding. I want to know what happened there.
Hey, there you are, babe.
Shai..
-Thanks a lot.
What a hunk.
Shai's parents are already here.
-Congrats to you too, Mom.
Oh, thanks, bro. Thanks. Congrats to you too, Ar...
People will say she found the perfect time to give birth.
Why would they say that?
-Because people talk.
They're filming us.
-It's fine, they'll edit it later.
You, on the other hand, will squeeze that lemon.
She's not going to be here for many weeks, right?
Move it, you're causing a traffic jam.
You got it.
-Thanks a lot.
What did I even say?
This movie is not okay.
It takes things out of context.
Maybe it's better not to eat.
-Look, here comes Adam.
Adam's here. Adam, hello.
-Congrats.
Nice to meet you.
-Hello.
Adam.
Who was that with you at the wedding?
Just someone. I don't even
remember her name.
Not serious.
-Her name is Gabriela.
And she was lovely.
-Thanks, Mom.
I really thought she was the one for you.
Lovely.
-Great, thanks.
So, did you invite her to the wedding?
-My mom invited her with me.
She's the daughter of someone from her kibbutz.
I thought you could have given her a chance.
The daughter of Tabbabalat, from the first marriage.
I... I'm out.
-Okay, quiet, shut up.
Here comes the little guy.
Uncle Shmuel.
I put you at the family table.
The check box is here.
Who just walked by behind?
-Okay. Maybe enough of that?
Enough. I'll buy the raw materials from them,
I'll take it somewhere
they can prepare it properly,
logically, and that's it. Come on, shall we eat?
Yeah, let's go.
-Let's go.
Wasn't that his ex?
-Who? Smadar?
No way!
-No chance!
You're exaggerating.
-No way.
Shaker.
-Here comes my sister.
Take our picture.
Snap it.
-Cheers!
What are you doing here?
-Riki told me to come pick up the kids.
I'll bring the kids later, after the ceremony.
Out.
-Smadar, you're part of the family.
I even put you at the family table.
It's fine. What, it's Meital's night.
-Michal.
Michal.
I'm taking the kids and I'm leaving. What...
Do me a favor, Smadar, don't let Michal see you
because she'll kill me.
-The camera's already turning.
Thanks, thanks for coming.
Shh_
So nice to see you. What are you doing here?
What do you mean? It's my brother's wedding.
He's marrying my cousin.
Is Michal your cousin?
-Nice.
How about you? Already in the bathroom?
Who's that chubby one?
Believe me, I don't even remember
her name.
You two look great together.
-No, I'm dying.
You know her.
-I think...
I think she was with me
in the scouts or something.
-Right.
Sit down, we don't know her.
Hey, here’s my brother.
Congratulations.
-Thanks, thanks.
And you didn't connect Michal and me?
We have the same last name.
The Cohen.
-The Levi.
The Levi. Smadar?
Hey, congratulations.
-Thanks, thanks.
I just came
to pick up the kids right after the ceremony.
The camera keeps spinning over here,
I'm passing it to that section.
-Sure.
No, I'm dying.
-No, I'm dying.
Someone's gonna die here.
-Everyone dies in the end.
Yeah? That's a promise, Riki?
The music is really loud here.
What's that?
-A microphone.
Moshe, what's that? Something's moving on my plate.
Mom, we have a cockroach.
What should I do with it?
-Bless the couple.
It's a disaster. Really a disaster.
Let the cockroaches bless them.
The groom's mom looks like she's stressed out.
The food was way better in the army.
There's a clog in the bathroom.
That's why it smells.
Do you see the food?
I ate half, didn't eat half.
You really can't chew it.
Shai's family finished all the alcohol.
No. I'm dying! I'm in hell.
Well, babe, you know
we had a terrible ceremony.
Terrible isn't even the word.
-I enjoyed it.
You were drunk.
-That's why I enjoyed it.
That's not true, it's this garbage,
because of the speech he pushed all the bad parts.
Michali, I was at your wedding,
and you had a wonderful wedding.
Well, maybe we should stop this nightmare and go eat?
-Yeah, let’s go.
No, no, no. I want to see
what else happened behind my back.
Don't move!
-Babe...
You hear me? I'm setting your microphone
for exit number 2 for the ceremony.
Why is she here, why?
Why? Because you have a crazy mom.
Mom invited her?
-Of course, of course.
She thinks her son will dump
his wife at the wedding and marry her.
She put her at the family table.
Why did Mom think I would leave
Shani the day I had a girl?
Itamar will leave his wife, not you.
Ah... so the troublemaker isn't here because of Mom.
So listen to this, you won't believe
who Michal's cousin is!
What? Itamar? What about Itamar?
What’s Mom doing to Itamar? He's getting married today.
She's not normal.
Hey, isn't that guy over there filming us?
No, he's filming that girl.
Okay, I need more.
Bring me some too.
-Sure.
Of course I'm not normal. I married him.
What do you want, Rivka? You really overdid it.
Pinchas, if there's one thing I hate
it's people talking behind my back.
If you have something to say, say it to my face.
Who are those people sitting over there at that table?
I think they're from Michal's side.
That's the ugliest group I've ever seen in my life.
Well, what was I expecting? Did you see the food?
And the rag on Michal's head?
What is this awful music?
Rivka, try to see the glass half full.
I tried, but you drank it.
Chill with the drinking, Pinchas.
People are already talking.
Why can't you say one positive thing?
One.
-What is it? To bless the couple?
Are we starting?
Isn't it recording? It was connected to the boom.
Oh, okay.
-There, now it's recording.
So, let's start.
Congratulations to Michal and my Tamari,
you have a wonderful wedding.
I've never been to one like this.
They say, my Tamari,
third time's the charm - ice cream.
Nonsense, nonsense, I'm just kidding.
Congratulations, congratulations!
-Congratulations! Cheers!
Congratulations.
-See? I was positive.
Cheers!
-Cheers!
No, I have no words.
-There's always a first time.
Come on, Mom, maybe that's enough?
-What did I say?
Okay, enough with this.
It's Friday today. Let's all relax.
Yeah, what's up with the food? People are hungry.
I don't think I can put anything in my mouth.
No, no, let's go eat. We've seen enough.
Wait, wait, wait. At least let me see the chuppah.
There were other cameras there,
so why are we only seeing this one?
What was the lawsuit about anyway?
-Itamar didn't want to pay for the drone camera.
And for the entertainment system, which was extra
that they brought on their own.
Of course, babe.
No, I hate weddings.
-God willing, your turn will come too.
Amen.
Not now!
-Not now!
It's not what it looks like.
Her fork fell. I helped her look for it.
That's it.
And did you find it?
Because you left without a fork.
...will be heard in the cities of Judah
in the streets of Jerusalem,
the voice of joy and the voice of gladness, the voice of the groom and the voice of the bride.
I want to understand what I'm seeing.
I'm in labor, screaming in pain,
and you're flirting at a wedding with girls?
Not with girls, just with one girl.
-Pinchas, do me a favor.
First of all, you were already after giving birth.
Secondly, I wasn't flirting. She was flirting with me.
What could I do?
-What could you have done?
Maybe say no, maybe tell her to stop,
maybe tell her you're married,
Maybe tell her to go to Adam
because he's free for the ride.
Ouch.
-I told her, go at seven.
They just edited that out.
My tongue will stick to my palate if I don't remember you.
If I don't raise Jerusalem above my joy.
Break the glass.
-Break the glass.
Can I?
-What? Is that all I have from the wedding?
I had an amazing dress. I was...
don't you dare touch the remote.
Itamar, you taught me everything I know.
Baby--- you know, and I'm an excellent student.
So I wanted to say thank you.
To you, and to Michal, congratulations from me, your little brother.
!Hagit here also joins in the thanks.
Call her! Gabriela! She was lovely.
Let's pause this movie and go eat.
Yeah, food, right away.
-Come on.
You have to try my mom's schnitzel.
No schnitzel today. I made shlufas today.
Let's watch a bit more.
It must be getting better.
-It can't be worse than shlufas.
Gorgeous!
Come on, let's go, come on.
-What?
We told Shani we'd be at her place. Let's go.
But Meirav doesn't want to leave yet.
Then let Meirav come later.
!Turns out it was
worse than Mom's shlufas.
I can't believe Smadar was at my wedding.
She's family.
-She's his ex-wife.
Honey, she just came to pick up the kids.
Didn't you notice they disappeared at some point?
Well, they got tired of it too.
-You know what bothers me the most?
That you all hid her from me. You all made a kabubia.
Kabubia? My mom's shlufas are kabubia.
Just so you know, there are kids in Africa
who would be happy to get my shlufas.
Of course. It's a tool in a sack.
-Michal, no one tried to hide anything from you.
Yeah, honey. You just didn't notice,
you were drunk.
Drunk? I was drunk?
I maybe had two glasses.
Two glasses, but test tubes?
They had really pretty colors, the test tubes.
Okay, I need some air. Sh'.
-I'm coming.
Sh', you need to dance more.
You dance really well.
See, honey, I told you
you didn't need to see this.
Sometimes you need to see to believe.
-Well, I see and I don't believe.
But what do you want from me? It wasn't my fault.
I just want to remind you she was born 4.750.
What does that have to do with anything?
-When you get 4.750 out of your body,
then you'll understand what it has to do with it.
-Come on, sit down, really...
What, you realize there was nothing there.
She was drunk and a mess,
otherwise she wouldn't have hit on me.
What am I... it's not like I'm Brad Pitt.
Yeah, that's true.
-So, all good?
Are there more incriminating clips of me in the movie?
-I hope not.
I mean, no, none.
-So, all good.
Come on, let's go in before your mom
finds another reason to talk about us.
She doesn't need a reason.
-Yeah, that's true too.
You didn't drink anything, huh?
Look, this is where you first met Adam.
You're a charmer too.
No, that's it. Now I'm totally dead.
Is that a threat or a promise?
-Rebecca...
What do you want?
-What do I want?
At our wedding, you went and kissed your ex?
That was a good luck kiss,
not a "Hey, let's do this
right here in front of everyone."
Oh, thank God.
-Rebecca...
Oh, what did I say?
-I get it, the Rosen men
partied at that wedding.
-We were drunk!
Now I see why you didn’t want
to watch the wedding video.
What are you hinting at?
-I’m not hinting. I’m saying it.
Each of you had something to hide. All of you.
Shame on you! A wedding is supposed to be a celebration of...
happiness, joy, and innocence!
Endless love. That’s how
I felt at my wedding.
Congratulations, babe.
What congratulations? Do you realize
what family I married into?
What disgusting people. Itamar's whole side.
I’m telling you, they don’t deserve someone like me.
You’re on my side, right?
-I think so.
Then I love you.
Wow, you look beautiful. Stunning.
So, Liri, you said there’s shlofs?
Plenty.
-Shall we do a kiddush?
Yeah, let’s go.
Let’s go.
-Come on.
What is shlofs anyway?
-Shlofs.
You’ve never had shlofs?
-No.
Ah... you’re in for a real treat
because it’s like... like klops,
just heavier.
It’s a big joy!
Let me get this straight, is someone making fun of me and my shlofs?
No, of course not, Mom.
Great, because I made some for all of you to take home.
"And there was evening and there was morning, the sixth day
and the heavens and the earth and all their hosts
Sabri Maranan."
-Cheers!
It was actually nice, even though I usually
don’t like watching wedding movies.
It was fun to know, right?
Do you think she’ll put it on YouTube?
-I don’t think so.
So, what do we even do with this thing?
-Put it in the freezer.
It’s not coming into my house.
-Then throw it in the trash.
No, we don’t throw away food.
-This isn’t food. It’s shlofs.
Fine, stop by the trash can.
-Why is it called shlofs?
It’s called that because of the noise
it makes later in the bathroom.
Of it.
-Pass.
Her name is Gabriela, and she was lovely.
Thanks, Mom.
Why are you laughing?
I regret it today, Orna.
I finish around ten, eleven.
What happened?
Wasn’t that Smadar? No. What?
-Okay.
Exactly.
What is this awful music?
Rebecca, try once to see the glass half...
It got stuck, the advance got to the throat. Sorry.
You two look great together.
No, that’s not it.
Oh, really?
That she even brings it up at all.