What's up, bro?
-I can't deal with this anymore.
Every time he fights with his wife
is he gonna crash here? Enough.
Sorry.
-It's fine, we're heading to her parents'.
They actually like him since
he picked the name for Manny's son.
Like him...
-Maybe you can drop him off here and pick him up later?
That's a great idea.
-No way.
I have déjà vu like I've had this déjà vu before.
It's not déjà vu. It's total déjà vu.
Look at me, look at me and...
"Who loves Shabbat? Mom and Dad
Who loves Shabbat..."
Who even remembers Shabbat? Since Zuzu and Adva got here
we haven't really had a real weekend.
Those days have turned into just more days
in the week. Friday and Saturday.
Bro, you okay over there?
-Yeah. You know, I have a few too.
Here, the cup.
Come on, babe.
In blue
'out
Come. Be careful going down.
You good?
Help him out.
Come on.
Bro, I'm dropping them off at Grandma's
and we're heading to the beach. Just five minutes.
Did you say something? I didn't hear.
Your and my brother's clothes are noisy.
Ah, here we go.
Come on.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Meirav is sitting and the AC is broken.
-Then she should get up. Look at the time.
Come on, girls, run to the mezilof.
Okay, Tzvi is drying out in my car.
Congrats on the new grandson.
Thanks.
-Thank you very much.
Be careful not to say anything stupid.
What?
-No, nothing.
Kisses and out.
-Alright, bye.
What, what bye? Sit, I'll put some mezilof on you.
No, I would love to come,
but Tzvi is drying out in the car.
Do you have a friend downstairs?
Why didn't you tell him to come up? You know we
always have enough. What, is he shy?
Not shy, drying out. The crew's at the beach. They're waiting.
Nice pants.
-Dad, be careful. Don't encourage him.
Do they have those in white too?
Alright, bye. Wait, did you clean the filter?
Because it could just be the air suction.
What filter? It's central AC. What's wrong with you?
But central AC has a filter too.
It's those squares in the hallway ceiling.
And it's at the entrance?
-What, you never cleaned that?
Of course we cleaned it but not inside.
What? You have some kind of vents.
You open them. It's at the entrance.
The filter is a gray plate.
You take it out, wash it, put it back.
Just five minutes.
So it's not a problem at all.
What do you mean "not a problem"?
You're not climbing up there with that back of yours.
We have a trip next week.
Okay, come on, babe. Just five minutes.
Alright, but someone call the drying out guy.
-I'll call him.
No, you stay with the girls. I'll call him.
What do you think, huh? We have an ally.
He finally managed to prevent it.
This is really a big joy.
-The son of the son.
Change the subject.
-It's fine.
You know, Manny is from Mivchar,
named after my dad, may his memory be blessed.
I'm named after my grandpa, may his memory...
This tradition has been in the family for generations.
There's always a son, named after the...
memory... of him.
Yeah.
I heard they were thinking of another name, they said.
No! No! No!
-What do you mean "no"? That's not what Orna told you.
Or am I wrong?
-You have no idea how wrong you are.
They haven't decided. They're thinking.
They said?
What, are they thinking of naming the kid Omri?
They're not thinking of naming my son after me? What...
When were they planning to tell me this?
Shabbat Shalom.
You're kind of clueless.
Uh-huh... yeah.
I'm already on my way.
I'll text you when to buy
the beers and the jachnun. Okay?
Shai says it’s a five-minute thing. That’s it.
Cool. So, alright, bye.
"So why not every Shabbat..."
)Y
Tzav! and
Be...
Come up and eat something.
Instead of... filling up on those candies.
Okay.
I'm telling you "no" and you keep going?
-You didn't exactly say "no" to me.
It was more of a face that I really
couldn't understand at all.
I told you clearly that Alin
asked Orna not to tell anyone.
Especially not Moshe because he tells everyone everything.
And especially not Dad
before Manny talks to him. What’s not clear?
Everything.
-What don’t you understand?
For example, why?
-Because it’s important to him that his son is named after him.
No. Why am I standing here
fixing the air conditioner instead of being at the beach?
Because I’m telling you not to say anything and you’re talking.
I thought in your family you could
talk about everything. No? For heaven's sake...
I know how many things were done to Alon at birth and where,
so we can't talk about the name of the newborn?
-Because it’s important to him.
And isn’t it a shame for the kid?
Does he really want to be called Silvan?
Is that a name for 2011?
That’s the name of a fan of "Hapoel Be'er Sheva."
Not a name for a little kid, a soft name.
Poor thing. Why label him like that?
Tell me, excuse me.
Aren't you named after your grandpa?
Shai is short for Shmuel Yosef.
And you’re comparing Shai to Silvan?
Right. For you, it’s really easier.
That’s after the grandpa is already late.
Listen well, honey. I still remember,
as a kid, Manny's brit,
my brother, Grandpa Menachem sitting
in the honored chair, holding my brother from crying
crying on a pillow.
Dad stood next to him
and when the mohel asked what his name would be in Israel...
Menachem.
...I remember how Grandpa got emotional.
Then Grandpa told about our dad
who was born when they just came to the country.
His name will be called in Israel: Silvan.
You see, when I was three and a half,
I found out that every firstborn son in this family
is named after his grandpa.
Menachem.
And everyone had a mustache.
Silvan-
And it goes way back in time,
and no one knows where it started.
Menachem.
So now you understand the historical significance.
Your silly slip of the tongue?
I'm sorry I let it slip the name.
What am I supposed to do now?
You call Manny, tell him
you slipped and that Dad knows and to be careful.
No, but...
-Shai.
Okay.
Oh, bro. What's up?
-I'm washing these in the shower,
putting them back and heading out.
-Quick. Don't let them burn all day.
All day? It’s a five-minute thing.
Maybe a bit more.
I'm setting plates for Shai and Tzvi. Did you eat?
Tasty. Mom's turned out gross.
-Yeah?
Look at her. I tried making it for them
last week. It turned out so gross
that instead of mezilof, they called it megilof.
Why?
-From the word "jifa."
It never turns out the same for her
because Grandma has a secret.
What's the secret?
-A secret she'll reveal to Mom one day
just like my mom revealed it to me.
Maybe you'll tell me?
-No.
I won't tell.
Mom, tell me.
-I won't tell.
Oh dear, oh dear.
-Come on!
Dad, what's going on?
This is how it passes from generation to generation until our matriarch Sarah,
who made mezilof for Abraham our father
and the three angels.
You can laugh at me. It's funny.
Mom, listen.
Girls, go to your room and watch TV.
They'll be here soon! The cousins.
What happened?
-No, it's fine. Don't panic.
It's just that my Shai,
accidentally let it slip...
He told Dad they're not sure they'll name the kid Silvan.
Why did he do that?
Kind of silly.
Type A.
I'll put this together and we'll head out.
In the meantime, go eat mezilof.
Officially, Moshe has been ousted from the family's fool position. Congrats to the heir.
Am I more of a fool than Moshe?
-At least he knows he's a fool. Did you talk to him?
With Moshe?
-With Manny.
You said you'd talk.
-How did I talk? I was crying filters.
So talk to him.
-I thought about talking on the way to the beach.
Now talk to him.
But right now I'm...
-Now. It's dialing.
Please.
Hello Manny, it's Shai. Listen to this.
Shani told me you picked a name, Omri.
But she forgot to tell me it’s a secret.
So that's why I accidentally told your dad.
Give it to me. Why are you putting this on me?
Manny, babe, it wasn't like that.
I told him to sh...
Manny! Manny!
That's his secretary.
Tasty?
-Very. Very tasty.
You better not have left me any of the burnt stuff.
Wow, why didn't you say there were people here?
Tzvi, meet Alin's daughter, Meirav.
Don't stand in front of him. He spits.
Sali!
-Hey!
Hey!
Tzvi.
This mezilof is really tasty.
-It's mezilof.
It's with the Z and that little guy up there.
I'll take the recipe for your wife.
Your wife? Got it.
It happens.
-Sorry, Mom won't let you. It's a secret.
What's her deal? Did something happen at home
that I need to know about?
Moshe! Dad! The name of the new grandkid. Omri?
Oh, not a good day to be home.
I can tell from the clothes you're going to the beach.
Yeah, we got the day off from family, so we're meeting at the beach.
Looks like you got a glowing day off. Fun.
-Yeah.
So, you two are just sitting alone at the beach?
No, it's not just me and Shai.
We managed to gather a few people we used to hang out with
for this Shabbat.
It's been a while. Guys.
-Guys? Sounds tempting.
No, no. What are you talking about? It's...
A few guys sitting shirtless,
sweating, drinking beer
talking trash by the... beach.
So wait for me. I'm coming.
Hold on, but... oh.
What an idiot. What an idiot.
Ah, Sali. You're here.
What are you doing here?
-I'm watching with the girls.
"The Idiot Age."
-What an idiot.
Very, very idiotic.
-Listen to me, Sali.
They just think. Just thinking.
That doesn't mean it's set in stone.
Did you know?
-It's...
-It's not final.
Everyone knew. Just me who didn't.
Wow, bravo.
-Is the new baby Omri coming today?
What an idiot.
I'm done.
-Alright, come on, head to the beach,
and I'll cry after you, as usual.
-I love you too-
I'm dying for you. Dying.
-Come on, bro, let's go.
Listen, I think Meirav thinks
she's coming with us to the beach.
Did you tell her the word "guys"?
Rookie mistake.
-Alright, come on, it's time.
Move now, I'll cover for you
before Moshe gets here.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom. Shai, good to see you here.
What a...
-Hey there.
Wait a sec, I want to show you something.
-Moshe, we're on our way...
Just a minute, I'm just finishing
this "payments" round,
I want to show you something. Okay?
-Alright, move. Come on.
Orna, do you see that everyone is walking around
in these pants?
They're back in style. I told you.
Alright, come on, it's time. Move!
No, he said "just a second." Now we're not coming.
What, text them to bring the beers?
Are you normal?
I told you she said
not to tell anyone. What's unclear about "anyone"?
You're right, you're right. Now just go, go.
What, you guys are leaving? Did you hear? His name is Omri.
Yeah. I know. Moshe, what did you want to show me?
-Who is this?
This is Tzvi, a friend. Come?
-Nice to meet you. Moshe, Orna's husband, sister of.
You're Orna and Moshe.
-Katz. Orna and Moshe Katz.
Moshe, what's the deal?
-Look what I bought.
Nice. Is that their model 5?
-Yeah. You know it? Do you understand this stuff?
Enjoy it. Shabbat Shalom.
-Wait a sec. I think I have a problem with the device.
I can't get the apps to work. Can I have a minute?
-Moshe, we...
Wait, wait.
Man, the AC here is freezing.
It's giving me goosebumps.
-Zvi?
Just a five-minute thing?
Alright, I’ll handle it. Come on. I bought one for my daughter.
I know a bit about this. It’ll take me less time.
Great, you’re still here.
-I get it, from the outfit,
That Shani hasn’t talked to you.
-About what?
About the beach.
-No, that’s what your Zvi talked to me about.
Cute. Zvi.
So, do you have any single guys in your crew?
Divorced? Widowed?
No.
-Like, those in the process?
Not right now, but once you arrive
I’m sure there’ll be some who want to sue me.
And he’s really mad?
-More like upset.
You know how Dad gets when he’s upset.
Gross, you disgusting, look.
But it’s not Shai’s fault.
It’s you, the idiot, who told him.
Come on, what do you want? I didn’t think he’d talk.
Especially him, who’s been taught all his life
to keep secrets.
His family lives in the attic.
He grew up in a culture of hasty whispers.
Well, at least my husband isn’t the usual idiot.
How do you prefer the hairstyle? Like this
or...
Like this?
-I think the option... like this! Like this!
No... no... wait a second.
This isn’t the real device.
-What?
Moshe, do me a favor, let me have it.
Mgrub is experimenting on me in a bikini.
It’s hell on earth,
what I’m going through. I swear to you,
in hell, if you’re bad,
they send you to this hell.
-Wait, wait, what do you mean "this isn’t real"?
It’s not real. Where did you buy this?
-Online.
It’s some site from Hong Kong.
It’s 20 Hong Kong dollars.
Come on, so that’s why it doesn’t connect to the internet,
doesn’t make calls.
It’s not a "smartphone." It’s a "smirk-phone."
What an idiot I am.
-Come on, sit tight?
Alright. Or...
Wait.
-What happened?
I need to rest for a sec. Just a minute, I’m...
Jumping like a sand panther.
-So sit, sit and rest.
Shani hasn’t talked to her sister yet
and she’s standing at the door, ready and set.
It’s itching my ear.
-Where’s Shani?
Moshe, don’t you have an app
for a pillow to give him in the meantime?
Come on, what’s up?
-Shani!
Do you want to talk about the pants?
-Why, did you turn around?
Sorry a sec, Orna, you said you’d talk to Meirav.
I’m sorry, babe, I’m really sorry.
Okay, I’ll take Meirav to the room
and you and your Zvi get ready to scram.
Wait, wait, stop.
-What happened?
Manny got your message. He’s on his way here.
Manny’s coming?
-Is he here?
No, no. He’s in a life crisis.
He needs to come in any second.
If he’s in a life crisis,
it’s better he doesn’t come here now.
Silvan, relax. Think about your back.
Why? Where are they going?
-To the Dead Sea.
He won’t ruin his lineage.
His mom said they’ll name the grandkid after Umm Kulthum.
The grandkid of Silvan Hasson will be named Silvan Hasson.
Dad, you need to calm down.
-Dad, I’m really sorry
that it got to you like this, but really,
I’m sure Manny meant to tell you this himself.
-When?
At the circumcision?
Am I supposed to get offended in front of everyone?
Then I'd rather get offended in my own house. Why not?
And at the circumcision, everyone will see that Silvan Hasson's firstborn
will be called Silvy in Israel.
That's it, the trip is off.
-Moshe, want some za'atar?
What about the burnt one?
-Isn't it enough they ditched the mustache tradition,
now they want to shave off the name too?
What, is there no end to the shame?
Alright, bro, we gotta go. Come on!
What’s up, what happened to your ear?
-What happened?
No, it’s nothing.
-Okay, come on, move it now
before Michal gets here.
-Sit down, Meirav, move it.
Meirav, come here for a sec, please.
-Come on, we gotta go before...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-Congratulations.
Congrats, bro.
-Thanks a lot.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Michal, just listen, I’m really, really sorry...
Wait a sec while I finish the "Shabbat Shalom." Okay?
-Sure.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Congrats.
-I’m not feeling so great.
It’s okay, rest. It’ll pass in five...
Hey, sweetie.
-...Shabbats.
Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Dad.
-Peace on Shabbat.
Who's Omri, tell me?
-It’s not final.
Only death is final.
-Silvan...
Look, Dad, even in Alin's family
they wanted to name the kid after her dad
who passed away in Russia:
Ivan.
Ivan?
-Ivan?
Ivan.
They want to name my firstborn
What, that’s not even a Hebrew name?
-And Silvan is a Hebrew name?
Of course. Silvan Bar Moses Shalom.
Hebrew name.
-Sali. Chill, chill.
You’ll find someone else
to be the godfather. Someone else.
I’m not coming to Ivan's circumcision.
-Look...
Not coming.
-Look, Dad,
but they thought about adding the names Ivan and Silvan
as second and third names.
Then it’ll be Omri Ivan Silvan Hasson.
All so you won’t get offended.
-I’m not offended.
Not offended.
It’s your grandpa who’s offended.
And my grandpa's grandpa who’s offended.
Seven generations back of shame and humiliation
of being offended.
You’re the most annoying one I’ve seen.
-Tell me, how do I get out of here?
I’m willing to do anything. You know what?
I’m ready tomorrow at eight in the morning
to go to the Interior Ministry
to add "Ivan Silvan" to my name.
Silvan Ivan.
-Silvan Ivan.
Don’t you think that’s a bit over the top?
No. In my family, we don’t have the word "proportion."
לא. במשפחה שלי אין את המילה "פרופורציה".
Enough already, come on. I’ll break this for you.
Tell me, what should I do?
-You take yourself with your pants on.
Off to the beach! I’m taking Meirav with me.
Why?
-Because you deserve it.
Calm down! Calm down!
Enough, enough...
-No way.
Stop fighting. Enough.
-Wasn’t there a “Ivan the Terrible”?
For what?
-Be careful, you’re saying that near Alin.
Come on, enough now. Not again.
If your grandpa were alive, he’d be turning in his grave.
Tell me, seriously, when were you planning to tell me this?
When we meet face to face, I just didn’t know
it would reach you before me from some idiot.
Bro, come here.
Listen, I’m sorry
for the slip of the tongue I had earlier.
I had no intention of causing a fuss.
But let’s not throw the baby out with the bathwater.
Let’s find a compromise, something between Silvan and Ivan.
Sivan!
Sivan. That’s brilliant.
It’s a nice name, very Hebrew.
It’s also exactly this month on the calendar...
But now it’s Tamuz.
Sivan is the combination of Silvan and Ivan.
Sivan?
-Sivan.
Sivan.
Sivan, come here right now.
-Sivan, pass the ball,
you see I’m alone!
-See? It works.
Sivan, my dear, Sivan...
It’s in a week, right?
-Yeah.
Honestly, it’s a nice name.
Sivan. Nice name.
I think I can get used to it.
That’s a great idea. Can I call Alon?
Alright, let it be a good hour.
-Big joy.
Call, may it be with luck.
-Thank you very much.
Sivan is a lovely name for a boy.
-Sivan?
Experience
experience.
Sivan.
-Sivan. Actually, nice name.
That’s a bummer.
It’s not working. What did you give me?
-What an idiot I am. Hong Kong.
Mine returned to its natural place.
-Sivan, it suits you.
No, that was Tzvi’s idea.
Oh my, what’s this? He’s allergic to something.
We need to take him to the hospital.
What, we’re not going to the beach?
-Why allergic?
He only ate from your mom’s drizzle.
-What do you mean?
I saw him spitting out candies in the car.
What’s this, why are you allergic? Are you allergic to something?
To candies.
-Sivan!
Got it. You nailed it with the name. Now, what are you allergic to?
Silan?
Mom?
-What?
Tell me, do you put Silan in the drizzle?
Sol... what, what? What do you mean Silan? What do you mean?
Date honey. Are you allergic to that?
Mom!
No!
Yes, Silan.
Yes!
-Yes!
Mom, he puffed up like a balloon.
-Sure thing, sweetheart.
But they gave him a shot and it passed.
And he exploded?
-No.
See, he's here. Everything's fine.
Can Dad also puff up?
I think the girls are getting confused. Because of your clothes.
They think you’re balloons.
Bro, I’ll put them in a bouncy house.
Just a matter of five minutes.
No, no.
Can I at least give him
something from your mom's boxes?
No, I’m not touching that drizzle.
-No, anyway, at the end of the drizzle,
But there's a secret recipe, want it?
Okay?
Another name, I’m saying.
Enough already, chill. I’ll explain it to you.
Tell me, what am I doing?
What are you doing now? You’re taking yourself...
What’s up, bro?
Rotem.
Pull over to the side.
L
o
v
e
It’s scratching inside my ear.
You didn’t know there’s silan at the grocery store too?
No, no, I didn’t know.
But come on, drive to the hospital fast,
before he blows up in front of the girls.