R, Sh, T. I'm done.
Very nice, good job, sweetie.
Good job, babe,
Now let’s see you say it all from the beginning,
But quietly, in your heart, in your inner voice.
Okay. A... go on.
So, in short, I talked to my mom. Well, that’s not a good start.
Funny.
It’s about Rosh Hashanah.
What, Rosh Hashanah is still a few months away, right?
No, it’s in a month and a bit.
Anyway, my mom wants us to celebrate the holiday at her place
!She’s inviting the parents too
But we were at their place last year, right?
No, we were at our parents' for Passover at your parents'.
Can’t we skip it? You think?
Alright, babe. Okay, I’m done.
'Yep', babe.
Sweetheart.
Look at me, look at me and...
Hey there. Well, hey, great, I was really worried.
How’s it going, Riki?
Girls, don’t run, don’t touch the walls,
I spent all yesterday on my hands and knees scrubbing.
Pinchas, Shabbat Shalom. Well, Shabbat Shalom, sit down.
How are you?
Riki, are you listening?
I just talked to my mom on the way here,
!She’s inviting you to celebrate the holiday with them.
How nice.
Really? Well, yes.
She didn’t have to.
How nice, really sweet of her.
We’d love to come, sit down, it’s been a while since we were there.
Yeah, but until Rosh Hashanah, who knows.
What do you mean?
Why does your mom need this?
To cook for all of us?
Don’t forget she’s not a little girl anymore, your mom.
Nonsense, Riki, she loves it.
Do I need to bring something? Sweet stuff for Rosh Hashanah?
I have a calendar in the kitchen, I’ll go check.
What, Riki, it’s really just a month and a bit away.
What’s up with her? Why is she like that?
Because on the other hand, maybe she’s right, why does your mom need to cook for all of us?
Oh, I’m dying, I love your mom’s food.
Especially those little stuffed circles. Yum, mikhalehta.
Yeah, maybe not, no, no, no,
Was it a Gimel or a Zayin?
Oh, and I’m just remembering her spicy fish, it’s to die for.
Shai, talk to your mom, I need an answer
because I want to let my mom know. Well, okay.
She has this really spicy dough, spicy.
Just thinking about it makes me sweat.
Will there be kubbeh too?
No, kubbeh is from a different cuisine.
Well, Mom, what do you say?
I don’t know, Shayka, why do we need all this mess?
I agree with you, it really is a big mess.
It’s really nice of them, but I have a home and I’m good here.
Why do I have to go to strangers' houses?
Mom, Mom, they’re not strangers. Well, I know.
But I don’t feel like going. Well, neither do I.
So what do we do? How do we get out of this?
Because you know they'll be really offended, they’re really sensitive people.
I know. Well, it’s really important to them, their honor.
I don’t want to generalize, and I don’t want to sound, you know what.
God forbid. Well, but they, specifically them,
are really sensitive. Well, yeah.
Wait, where is Itamar celebrating the holiday? Well, I don’t know.
Right, I can’t celebrate the holiday without my kids.
Of course, they’re your kids.
Wait, what about Dad? Since the invitation, he’s been drooling on the living room carpet.
You leave Dad to me.
And what about the twin sister? Is she still in Los Angeles?
Yeah, yeah—
What do they do there? Falafel, right?
No, no. High tech. Well, oh, I remembered something like that.
And will they be at the holiday? Well, no, they’re not coming.
Yeah, fine. The main thing is we’ll be there. Well, yeah.
Hey there. Well, hi, Shabbat Shalom.
What’s up? I need to use the bathroom.
What’s this, are you alone?
No, Michal is downstairs, she’s looking for parking.
I just came up first because I had to use the bathroom.
And the kids are okay? Well, yeah, of course they’re okay,
they’re on their way, I have to...
What do you mean on their way? Are they walking by themselves? Well, where are they coming from?
No, Smadar will pick them up later. Well, I’m running to the bathroom.
They sat with Smadar? Well, yeah, of course they sat with Smadar.
Dad, what’s wrong with you? If I don’t go to the bathroom now, it’ll end in tears.
And mostly ours.
What’s that? I thought I heard Tamar.
That woman can hear a pin drop.
Yeah, yeah, he’s here, he went to the bathroom, Riki.
Great, I was really worried, you know he has a really small bladder.
Now I know.
What’s going on with the holiday? What’s the deal?
I don’t know, there are a few problems.
What problems? We’re at the parents’ for the holiday.
Yeah, and where will your kids be? Well, Itamar and Adam?
Do you have more that I don’t know about?
So Pinchas, if you don’t have anything smart to say, well, it’s better you talk about the weather.
No, Shai, it’s just that my mom doesn’t want to leave my siblings alone.
We don’t want to burden your mom with the fact that we’re all coming.
What face will I have leaving my kids alone for the holiday?
Okay, but Riki, your kids might have plans.
No way,
my kids know that the first thing they need to do is tell Mom.
Right, Pinchas?
It’s hotter today than usual for this season.
High humidity.
I wanted to stop on the way, well, but Michal didn’t let me.
Okay, tell me, Itamar, well, where are you and your bladder for the holiday?
What holiday? Well, what holiday? Rosh Hashanah.
Where are you? Here, right?
How should I know? That’s still a long time away.
Apparently not for them. In their calendar, it’s already holiday eve.
Don’t mess with my head. Well, I need to know, are you here for the holiday?
No, I’m in the Maldives. Well, no way, Maldives.
So now there’s really no problem, right? It’s just Adam left.
My mom won’t have any problem hosting one more person.
Shani, you can’t decide that for her, you need to check.
Okay, I’ll go call her, I’ll find out.
Are you out of your mind?
Who celebrates a holiday abroad?
And with strangers, with foreigners?
Pinchas, say something to him.
It was cool yesterday, today it’s hot and it’s only going to get hotter.
Hello. Hey, Mom.
Hey sweetie, what’s up? Are they coming?
It’s not confirmed yet. I told you she’d cause trouble.
No, no, no, she really wants to come, really,
She just asked me to check if it’s okay for Adam, Shai’s brother, to come too
because he’s alone for the holiday.
What do you mean, what’s the problem? What problem?
Why are you even asking?
I don’t know, but she asked me to check, she feels awkward.
It’s family, right?
It’s fine, Mom, she’s not listening. Great.
And don’t you dare bring anything, you hear? Nothing.
Okay, Mom, I’ll talk to her when it’s settled.
Alright, bye sweetie. Bye.
What’s she saying? Of course it’s fine for her brother to come.
And all these arrangements are starting to drive me crazy.
You don’t have to, you know. You can separate forces too.
Forget it, son, Shai, it’ll be fine.
Who? What?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Mom, what happened to Dad? Why did he swallow the doctor’s advice?
Where are the kids? Did something happen? Nothing happened.
Michal’s downstairs, looking for parking,
the kids were with Smadar, and she’ll drop them off later, she’ll call from downstairs.
How nice. Smadar, I just had coffee with her at the mall this week.
What? We ran into each other.
So we sat and chatted a bit.
She’s doing well: in Hadar, does Orna know?
Are you kidding me? She looks great in Hadar.
When she arrives, tell her to come up a bit.
What do you mean come up? What’s wrong with you? What’s there to...
Guys, do you remember we’re divorced?
Just because you divorced her doesn’t mean I did too.
I never had a problem with Smadar.
Mom, I don’t want to talk about Smadar anymore, got it?
Michal needs to come in any minute, and I don’t want to talk about it anymore,
enough already, we’re not talking about it anymore. Okay, okay. What did I even say?
I don’t understand why you’re so sensitive about it.
What, are you talking about Smadar? Enough already, come on.
Okay, Michal looks good in Hadar too,
but not like Smadar.
And just because she wears clothes for a three-year-old
doesn’t make her anything special. Mom, enough, stop.
No, I’m dying, there’s no parking at all. You won’t believe where the house is.
I just gave up and dumped the car, I’m dying.
But look, you still made it.
And you look great. Cute, right?
Hello, Pinchas. Hello.
הלו, פנחס. הלו.
Hey, babe. So, Michal, Maldives?
What Maldives? What do you mean Maldives?
Maldives. I thought for Rosh Hashanah I'd surprise you.
And we could just hop over to the Maldives.
What, you decided that just now?
What, is that a surprise? She had no idea?
That's wild, seriously, Shani would kill me
if I made decisions like that on my own.
Maldives?
Honestly, it's a Muslim country, come on, Shai.
Maldives. Yeah, right, Maldives, babe. What do you think?
Cool, how fun.
Karin from my class was there,
she says it's amazing, like, just incredible.
Great, babe. Well, great, babe.
Incredible.
Tell me, why are you making a fuss? What do you care about going to the Hassons for the holiday?
Why are you putting words in my mouth?
I didn't say I care, I said I prefer not to go.
But why? Because I just don't feel like it.
Don't feel like it? You?
Do you know what traffic is like during the holiday? Come on, I'll drive.
Seriously, do me a favor.
You're just being stubborn,
you know it’ll save you all the cooking. Have you thought about that?
I don't mind cooking. Come on, Rebecca, your excuses are running out.
Give me another minute, I'll find you three more besides that.
I want to know what Adam is doing. I'm not leaving him alone for the holiday.
Okay, okay.
Smadar is coming and you're messing with my head about the Hasson family.
I need to take the pastries out of the freezer.
Okay, dear God.
So amazing.
I don't know, just a second.
What's the weather like in the Maldives anyway? I don't know, ask Pinchas.
Shabbat shalom, what's up? Is there food? I'm starving.
Mom, what's going on with the food? It's almost ready.
When Smadar arrives, tell her to come up. Okay, okay.
What Smadar? Why would she come up?
I'll get back to you.
I read an article in the newspaper about her husband, who just became a partner in gas.
She caught a husband, huh? She succeeded this time, huh?
What's up, guys?
Babe, can you come here for a sec? I want to talk to you for a moment.
Shut up, you idiots.
So, Adam, what's new? Everything good.
Yeah, living the dream? We're trying.
Speaking of dreams, where will you be for Rosh Hashanah?
How should I know? What, that's in 30 days, right?
A month away.
Oh, where did the dust go? Did you vacuum?
Why are you asking?
No, because Itamar and Michal are in the Maldives.
And my parents invited your family. Wait a second,
cool, so that means I'm off the hook, I can do the holiday alone,
cool, extreme. Seriously, cool.
What's cool? Mom, come here for a sec.
What happened? No, nothing happened,
Adam decided he's doing the holiday alone. Cool, right?
In Nasser's grave, that might be cool,
This isn't happening.
Where did you drag Bazir from now, oh my God.
Pinchas, do me a favor,
my son isn't sitting home alone in the dark like a dog.
Why like a dog?
Because you have family and you don't sit alone on the holiday.
How do you know he'll be alone? Maybe he'll have a girl with him?
Pinchas, do me a favor,
you know very well what kind of girls are out there
not at their family's house on holiday evening.
Oh really? Well, not good girls.
But that's exactly the type I like. Well, whatever. Forget it, Adam,
anyway, you're also invited to my family.
Shani, I love you, it’s not about that,
but I really don’t want to go to a family I don’t really know, if you don’t mind.
Shani, I’m really sorry,
tell Mom thank you very much, but we can’t make it this year.
No way.
Riki, I don’t understand, what, are you three just going to sit alone on the holiday?
Yeah. Adam, Dad, and me. Well, just the three of you? That’s a little,
isn’t that a bit sad?
No, this way we’ll have quality time with Adam.
Did you know Bazir loved to wear women’s clothes?
Yeah, that’s known.
So tell me, Shani, is the food at your place good? Totally amazing.
I swear to you, Smadar won’t come here. It’s just my mom and her nonsense.
Listen, Shani... well, then focus on the Maldives and a new swimsuit,
you know what, forget the swimsuit? It’s the Maldives, who knows you there?
You think so?
Okay, listen for a second, that’s not what I wanted to talk to you about.
Is there a chance we can postpone the Maldives to Yom Kippur?
What’s Yom Kippur?
Because my mom is hosting the holiday at her place this year.
Come? Well, we’ve never been to my mom’s for the holiday.
We’ve never been to Sachne either, so what? Well, that’s not nice.
But, babe, well, fine, if you don’t want to, then it doesn’t matter.
No way.
Okay, then I’m calling.
Yeah, yeah, call your mom.
No, suddenly you remember Mom’s sweets.
You can’t have sweets. Well, but I can.
No, it’s not good for you either, it gives you worms.
And Shani, when you call your mom, tell her I’m not eating goat.
Goat? What do you mean goat? We don’t have goats, Riki.
Sit down, you can’t know.
Riki, I know very well. We don’t have goats, what goats?
I’m going to call them.
So what, Adam,
do you remember Meirav?
Shani’s sister? Well, what, she still hasn’t married?
She’d be really happy if you came.
Really.
No way. Well, I don’t understand what your problem is
with us being three on the holiday.
We’ll light candles, sing holiday songs.
I can print song sheets.
Dad will wait for us, animals. Well, yeah.
I’m going to Shani’s parents. Well, yeah, yeah.
No way.
What's her problem now?
No problem at all, Mom, they'll come! They'll be happy to come.
They'll even bring Adam.
Is it final? Yep, definitely final.
Hey, Mom, I wanted to ask you,
Are you cooking something with goats?
No, why would I cook goats?
I don't know, just asking, never mind.
Sit, sit, wait a sec with Mom, come here.
Okay, Mom... I told you she'd cause trouble.
Why would I cook goats? Who cooks goats?
Bye, Mom, I'll talk to you later.
Come on, babe, you're without kids, we can celebrate at my mom's.
But babe, think about it,
Maldives, just you and me, alone,
no kids, no family, white sand, blue sea, peace and quiet.
All you hear is
What’s that? Oh, it’s the sound of the waves, babe.
Tamari, I didn’t know you were here.
So, are you listening?
Do I have a choice? Nope.
So, if I'm not mistaken,
the kids should be with you for Rosh Hashanah
because they were with Smadar's parents for Passover.
I don’t know, I hadn’t thought about it.
So think, because those are your kids. Yeah, I think you’re right.
Of course I’m right.
So what, are you taking the kids to the Maldives now?
The kids are with you for the holiday?
What do we do? I'll tell you what we do,
we celebrate the holiday here.
Sit, my sweet, I’m really sorry,
tell Mom thank you but we can’t come this year.
Okay, Riki.
Come on. Why are you being a jerk?
One day you’ll be my husband. What do you want from me?
Besides, I could’ve had a solo vacation,
Orna ruined that with Mom.
Hey, Grandpa. Hey, Raz.
Come on, Lian, come here, come to Grandpa. Don’t change the subject now.
Hey, I knocked but you didn’t answer.
Smadar, so nice you came.
Hi, Smadar. Hey.
Still a blonde, I see.
How’s it going? It was good until I met you.
Smadar. Hey, Roko.
Oh, wow.
So nice you arrived, how are you?
I’m good, thanks, and you?
I’m healthy, thanks. So, what’s up?
At home, look who’s here.
Oh, hey, so... sit down.
Hi, Smadar. Hey.
Mom, I think my shirt ripped...
Oh, Smadar, what are you doing here? Why did you come up?
You said you’d call. I would’ve come down. For what...
Why didn’t you call? I would’ve come down right away to get you.
Yeah, I tried to call
but your phone was probably off for some reason.
What do you mean it's closed, never!
Where's the... you know, is this a place?
It's really closed. Come on, please.
How are you, Smadar? You look great.
Thanks, Pinchas, you too.
Smadar, come on, sit here, why are you standing?
No, no, no, I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
Itamar, can I have a quick word with you?
Sure, what's the problem? Let's go to the balcony like usual,
nothing ever changes here. Excuse me?
Unfortunately.
She looks... great. Yeah, right.
Itamar Tzafan and Smadar Malda.
What's up?
It's about the kids for the holiday. So, I wanted to talk to you about that.
Yeah? So listen,
I’d really love it if they could be with me for Rosh Hashanah,
my mom is getting cozy. For Rosh Hashanah?
Yeah, I know it's a religious thing, but are you okay with that?
Of course, of course. So,
because for Sukkot, Gilan and I are planning to go to the Maldives
with my mom and the kids for the whole week of Sukkot.
Yeah. Gilan has a place there, so... cheers to him.
Yeah.
And cheers to you, a week with the kids in the Maldives and your mom.
It's like...
Good for you, I haven't really been in touch with the kids lately.
Me neither.
Did you see Raz's girlfriend?
I saw her and regretted it immediately.
With your mom, that's a double whammy.
Yeah.
I wonder what they're talking about, huh?
Come on, it's not nice to eavesdrop like that.
Leave them alone, it's none of our business.
Did you talk to Mom? Wait, maybe Itamar wants to switch with her?
No way, no chance, you don't know Smadar.
But she looks... okay, we get it, Pinchas, she looks amazing.
I think she wants Itamar back.
Riki, maybe you forgot, but Itamar is mine.
Why are you putting words in my mouth?
I didn't say he wants you, I said she wants you.
Are we eating today too?
I don't understand a word of what she's saying either.
And if I manage to understand, I don't get what I understood.
Well, it's not hard to say things you don't understand at all.
I didn't get it. We're just joking with you.
Sorry, I don't want to interrupt. Of course not.
Smadar, my dear, why don't you stay and eat with us?
I'm defrosting.
Wow, I miss your shleiker so much, wow.
What, is that going to bother you? Look...
No way.
Alright, fine, whatever.
Gilan is playing soccer.
How fun, I'm excited.
How fun, just like old times, my boy.
Amazing kids.
Alright,
I'm going to set the table.
What, she's in shock? Yeah, totally.
Itamar, come here for a sec. Sure thing.
So what, gas, huh? Yeah, right.
Alright, I'm gonna help Riki with the kids.
Why is your mom doing this to me?
Babe, Smadar just came to tell me
she wants to take the kids for Rosh Hashanah, that's all.
So why is she in shock?
Michali, babe, it's okay. No, it's not.
Of course, it's fine from your side, but from Riki's side, it's totally not okay.
Come on, what? This time she really overdid it a bit.
What are you doing here? I just took the kid to the bathroom.
Michali, I'm telling you, there's no reason to get upset and cry.
No, sorry, it's her right.
No, I mean, don’t give my mom the pleasure of seeing you like this,
like she beat you, fight back.
Yeah, if you're like a thorn in the throat, be a thorn in the throat. Right, thorn in the throat.
What, are you all here? Why did you come?
Dad sent me to check if everything's okay. Everything's fine.
Exactly, everything's fine, don’t be afraid of anyone.
This time she really overdid it. Totally.
Dad.
Are you guys normal? I'm totally here alone.
Come on.
And Shani, about your mom, we are going for the holiday after all.
Really? Yeah.
What a mess
Great. Babe. Babe.
Alright, Riki, I think I’ll head out, I’m just making a mess.
What would we do without all this chaos?
The bigger the mess, the bigger the personality.
Just like all your jokes, funny and whiny.
Oh, you're so sensitive that you're leaving because of the...
Meital. Michal.
Michal, Michal.
Just know you'll always be like my daughter.
This is like home.
Come in, come in.
Come on.
Alright, I'm out.
What a mess
So what, for the holiday, you're with the kids at your mom's?
Big suffering, huh? Yeah, but on the other hand, a week in the Maldives after that.
What a coincidence, Itamar and Michal will be in the Maldives too.
When? Rosh Hashanah.
What, you can't,
the little one has a dance performance after the holiday at Polishuk's,
there's no way you're skipping that again.
Alright, bye. Bye, bye.
What a mess
I knew everything was too good to be true.
You're not spending the holiday alone.
And what about me? We're doing the holiday here.
Sorry, Riki, but this year we're doing the holiday at my mom's.
No, but... at my mom's!
There's a good chance we'll be in a mess the next day.
You said she would cause problems.
What problems, Mom? Come on, really,
she's really happy to come.
Did you tell her not to bring anything? I don’t understand why she insists.
It's not tasty to anyone anyway.
I told her, she won't bring anything, Mom.
Is it final? Well, it's settled.
I'm on my way home, Mom.
K'no! And `nubenrnorino'no'ben A. `ben.
Hey, Rachel.
Don't get me wrong, I love your mom's cooking.
Good week. Well, good week.
What peace, a little quiet at last.
I swear, no one wants these holidays.
I agree with you—
By the way, for the holiday, I'll be with Moshe's family.
If I'm not mistaken! If I remember correctly,
The kids were at... they need...
Is there a chance I can postpone Yom Kippur?
You postpone Yom Kippur?
As far as I'm concerned, cancel it. Well, it doesn't sit well with me.
What's the problem with the three of us being together for the holiday?
I'll light the candles, we'll sing Hanukkah songs.
I can print song sheets. Well, Dad...
Hanukkah songs on Rosh Hashanah? Well, let's do a pick-up.
Don't be afraid of anyone.
This time she really went too far. Totally.
Dad, what are you...