Not true.
When are we arriving?
Soon, soon, and enough, quiet down over there.
Enough, put on some music for them.
What will we do when this stops working?
To improvise?
I don’t get why we can’t have one Friday alone.
My family week,
Tell me, what, are you normal?
You think both families will eat at our place?
No, a week alone, just alone.
I’ll make shakshuka.
What do you say? And a cake too?
Because the cleaner comes on Thursday.
For one Friday alone, I’d be willing to lick the floor.
That sounds good, but I don’t think so.
You think so?
Laundry, cooking, dishwasher, ironing,
Bringing the girls, putting them to bed,
Do me a favor, come on, enough.
You can talk to my mom about it.
You’ve seen that movie 25 times already.
They keep getting better.
What, is she a whore?
She’s like...
She...
She’s the "big mistake,"
A whore.
What a hunk, Richard Gere, huh?
Julia Roberts is a beautiful woman too.
What are you saying? No, because you can
At least I don’t swallow and fade away.
I’m not committing.
It’s clear that whatever your mom doesn’t say,
Yeah, why not? Of course, sure, why not?
Why is the door locked?
I don’t understand how you always do this,
how you always manage to argue
and have to say the last word.
Come in, come in! Come on.
I love you.
Shabbat shalom.
What are you doing here?
Where is everyone?
Today you’re at Rosie’s.
So?
Alright, come on, Shabbat shalom.
Shabbat shalom.
Why are they here, huh? Why are they here?
And what if we were in the middle of something?
Eli, look at me and...
So this is Goldie.
Hello.
What, is she Dutch?
Yeah, Dutch.
Because she doesn’t understand a word of Hebrew.
Definitely.
If you marry him, you’re killing his dad.
Mom, in English, if you please.
If you please, nice one.
Shut up.
She said you’re beautiful.
Yeah, you know, you could kill someone.
Murder, murder.
No, because of your beauty.
Babe.
She said she’d like you, babe, what do you want?
Thanks.
Goldie, Goldie, first let me
introduce you to everyone.
So, this is Itamar, he’s Adam’s brother.
Yeah, and you know, you know, Goldie,
Itamar is named after my grandpa. He went through...
He went through a massacre in the Holocaust.
Mom.
She’s Dutch. They saved Jews, right?
Welcome to Israel.
I’m his wife, Michal.
How old are you?
Wow, in vision: a lot of Yefradir.
Michal.
Goldie, Itamar is...
What exactly are you doing?
An entrepreneur?
He’s a performer.
A clown?
I’m not a clown, I’m not, I’m an entrepreneur, an entrepreneur.
No, no, no...
Okay.
Have you called Shai and Shani yet? Where are they? What’s going on?
People are hungry here.
I’ve been so worried. They got confused,
Shabbat Shalom.
Yeah, Mom, they just arrived.
Sorry for the delay,
Goldie, deep mistake, deep as a nightingale.
Mom, yeah, I know she was a beautiful woman.
Excuse me for a second, I’m sorry.
Are they coming now? People are hungry here,
let’s sit at the table,
she hopes the schnitzel didn’t dry out.
What’s this?
This is Goldie, she’s Dutch.
Dutch.
Nice to meet you, welcome.
You haven’t brought one like her yet, you assimilator.
He’s not marrying her, he’s not marrying her.
Wait, why is she in the front?
What’s this, she’s European,
the Dutch love the Jews.
"Ajax," Anne Frank.
Anne Frank?
I’m not planning to visit my grandchildren.
Schiphol.
What?
Maybe we should sit down to eat, what do you think?
Yeah, Michal, go call Shani.
Come on.
Mom, it's okay, sorry, it was a mistake, a mistake,
We went by mistake, okay?
It's fine, sweetie, I forgive you.
But there's a problem with Dad, he's really mad.
But...
What if we were in the middle of it?
Mom, I can hear them.
She can hear you.
So you talk to her.
I don't want to talk to her, I want you to give back the key.
What key?
I'm not giving back the key.
Now, Mom, now that I know what's planned,
Next time I'll ring the bell, okay?
Sit down.
Honey, they're all at the table...
No, because I can't talk.
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Shai, nice to meet you.
"And there was evening and there was morning.
The sixth day, and the heavens and the earth and all their hosts were finished."
Friday, the heavens, the earth are done.
And their army.
Their hosts.
"And God finished on the seventh day His work which He had done
and He rested on the seventh day from all His work which He had done."
And God...
And God took a break.
"And He blessed the seventh day and sanctified it
because in it He rested from all His work."
Great, He took a break again.
"Sabri Maranan."
Does anyone have a clue what the bar mitzvah is?
The Sabri Maranan.
Sit down, don't curse, there are kids here.
It's something in Aramaic, okay.
"Blessed are You, Lord our God, King of the universe
who creates the fruit of the vine."
Thank you, God, for giving us the...
grapes.
Guys, do me a favor, okay?
Let Dad finish, then you can translate everything.
Guys, let Dad finish and we'll translate...
Sorry, please, no...
For You have chosen us from all the nations
and Your holy Sabbath You have given us with love and goodwill.
Blessed are You, Lord, who sanctifies the Sabbath.
Amen.
Because You have chosen us from all the nations...
This is a prayer, wonderful God, beautiful God,
and now food, sit down, sit down.
I want to say something to everyone.
Dad, I booked us for two weeks from now.
Great.
So that it doesn't turn out we won't see each other,
I thought maybe we could meet next week instead.
If we could switch the shifts on Friday.
Sure, of course.
No problem.
Tell me, what are you doing?
What did I do?
Are you normal?
Oops.
Now I have to explain to your mom
that I need to ask my mom first.
It'll be fine.
No, it won't be fine, that's a definite wasp.
Why do you go straight to the obvious, come on,
please.
Here.
Riki?
Sorry, just a second, sit down,
I need to check on this.
No problem, I'm sure it'll be fine,
call them.
So when?
Okay, I need to check that too.
I'm going to check, now, now, when?
Just a second.
Shai, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
Turns out it's a problem to move the Shabbat dinners.
Goldie, look here, look here. This...
It's a complete mess, that's it.
Very good, very tasty.
I was just about to go in.
She always does that.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry...
Okay, enough, enough, stop with your apologies,
you're ruining all the fun of arguing.
So what do we do?
I'll try to sort out all the mess you made.
Why mess? I said sorry.
And stop saying, Shai, nice to meet you.
She already knows you.
I'm telling you, there's something suspicious about her.
Hello.
Mom.
No, no, everything's fine, just relax.
I thought something happened, why did you call?
Who is this?
Her again? Why is she calling?
Maybe we're in the middle of something?
Tell her we're in the middle of something, right now!
Mom, tell her I can hear her.
She can hear you.
So no? Are you sure?
No.
Okay, so no.
Alright, no. Got it, bye.
So yes?
My brother's wife has a cousin who's having a Shabbat dinner,
and we have to be there.
What obligations?
My mom won't like that.
So what do you say, of course, sure,
it's because of the food, she...
It confused me, she always does this to me.
So where in the north?
Fighters of the Ghetto.
I know, the Nazis, "may their name and memory be cursed."
We need to clear these plates.
Where's the bathroom?
Let me, let me show you.
Go away from there.
Watch out for the wind.
So you're from Amsterdam,
So you know "Ajax"? "The Jews."
No, I'm... look, I'm not a good liar,
I'm not really Dutch,
German...
So German.
Nice, nice.
Well, the bathroom's over there.
How do you say it in your place?
The crap sets you free.
Thanks.
Change?
But it depends on so many other people.
And you want me to call everyone now?
Mom, I'm in the middle of dinner at Rina Rosen's.
And you're in the middle of "Pretty Woman."
Wait, explain to me again, why did Shai say it was okay?
Mom...
Okay, fine, I'll call soon.
Tell me, why didn't you tell her we're in the middle?
Tell me you succeeded.
I don't get it,
Come on, this is your chance,
You think? If I say something like that to her,
it's like I poured Tippex on myself and I'm erased.
Alright, come on, we need to go back.
I love you too.
On a completely different note:
Turns out Goldie is...
German.
No way.
Just like Hitler, but without the mustache.
Seriously.
Just like Eichmann, but without the brutality.
Great.
Goldie, Goldie,
she makes the best shlufas in the world.
Yeah, in the world.
Shai, enough with your nonsense.
Rina.
I have a problem with next week,
What happened? Why?
May you know no more sorrow.
Can't we postpone or move it up?
It's a Shabbat Katan so...
Not really.
Yeah, oh dear.
Well, I... I understand,
you know I always say,
Sit down, can you please come help me for a sec?
She said, the best family in...
The most important thing is family.
Do you like the shlufas? Are the shlufas good?
Yeah.
Eat up, eat up, sweetheart.
Sweetheart-sweetheart.
Bro, come here for a sec.
What?
I think I understand them better than I do myself,
Tell me, are they doing this to us on purpose?
Who?
I don’t know, why would I understand them better than you?
I don’t know,
They say her parents' background
what?
I don’t know, how would I know those suburbs?
So you don’t think they hate us?
Why did he have to leave Smadar?
Rina, come here, I’ll teach you something in suburb slang?
Enough.
So Adam asked her to say she’s Dutch.
But she...
Is German.
No way.
In all kinds of ways.
What, this is going to be a disaster.
But without telling the parents,
Definitely abusing Adam.
On the other hand, just so you know, if Mom
I’m shifting all the blame to the Bian-Bardit.
Don’t you dare.
Okay, okay.
You’re not telling anyone.
Tell me, what are you, a kid? What’s wrong with you?
Schnitzels.
I hope it’s not the stew.
Babe, check this out.
She’s German.
Times six million.
So what, Kibbutz Fighters of the Ghettos? That’s nice.
Yeah, what do they eat there?
Spaghetti?
Very funny, really,
And besides, we probably need to not end up.
Mine.
No, I’m dying.
Okay Riki, you can relax,
the cousin decided not to get married.
And Ash.
Shai.
You’re going to ruin everything.
Next week at his place again.
Itamar, tell me,
Massah, the kids.
Okay, I’m going to make a quick call to Smadar.
Is everything okay?
He just went to talk to his wife earlier.
The commotion on the phone.
You know my first wife's dad
was really, really rich, you know?
Half the neighborhood was his, you know.
Her family came from Germany.
Yeah, they came from Germany before the war, you know.
Great family.
What happened? What did I say?
Maybe because you talked.
You could say that.
Wow, the goulash is delicious.
I didn’t say it’s a shame he divorced her.
I’m going to talk to her.
With Smadar.
Peepee? Come here.
Me too.
And Michal, we do consider you sometimes.
And there’s a family gathering, what can you do?
Show a little flexibility, it’s not a wedding.
What’s going on? Why is this taking so long?
Turns out next Saturday her parents have a housewarming.
They finally finished all the renovations.
Yeah, I’m listening, Smadar, come on.
Do you want me to talk to her?
It’s fine, Riki, he can talk to her.
Itamar, buddy, give me Smadar, please.
Mom, I’m fine.
Give it to me.
Hello.
Smadar, hey.
Yeah.
I miss you so much, I really need you.
Listen, Smadar.
But I’m doing it alone.
Wait a second, don’t start.
Sit down, come here for a sec.
Why, Mom?
Because we need to talk about grown-up stuff.
What happened? Did something happen to her?
Nothing happened, she’s fine.
While you were busy with the goulash.
Mom went to handle Itamar’s crisis.
So maybe you should try calling your mom for a moment.
To see what can be sped up.
Wow, your family is so stressful.
Hello, Alin?
You again?
She’s waiting for a call from Manny’s wife’s sister-in-law.
Give me Mom.
Can’t, she’s talking to the mother-in-law.
What’s her name? Yafit.
How should I know? Dad’s side.
Give me Shai, okay?
He wants you.
Hello, Silvan.
Are you out of your mind? You’re completely crazy!
I don’t get it, why are you fighting windmills?
Why? Why? It’s just trouble.
Of course, Silvan, but...
You don’t mess with Shabbat.
It’s like forcing a democracy on a country.
Is that Shabi? Give her to me.
Hello.
Yeah, Dad.
Mom.
I'm hungry!
Just do everything now, so you won't have to later.
So, here's the deal, I talked to the part I caught
They needed to check.
No way, it clashes with the birthday.
Impossible.
Until everyone is in meetings.
I think they have tickets to Burgos.
I'll check.
And then they asked around the table
What do they want?
No, that's not right.
Now? That's not going to work.
No way.
What do they want? I'll check.
Well, we can't move Shabbat,
realistically, it's not happening.
So what do we do?
Is it possible?
Well, I know you figured it out
but stop it.
Stop what? All the whispering,
Excuse me, what is this, are we not allowed to gather?
Sorry, I just don't want to upset the parents.
Neither do we,
we're just organizing Righteous Among the Nations.
We wanted to plant a tree in her honor, it's...
Where did you meet her?
Tourist, wanted to see a Friday dinner.
I just found out this morning that Goldie is German.
Is she a Nazi?
Grandpa watched soccer and said the Germans are Nazis.
You're fifth generation, get over it.
But I can't when you guys are here.
Just jealous.
Come back.
Crazy...
Is this final?
We can't move Shabbat in my family.
And once again, it falls on us.
Well, stay strong.
Hey cutie, stay strong, where are you going exactly?
Stay here and take out the trash.
Did you hear? You're dead, she's talking to her ex.
The kebab is tasty.
I miss her so much, she agreed easily.
You don't know this, but it's just,
she... everything works.
Next week you’re at my place.
It's happening now.
Riki.
We can't next week,
What's not working out?
I'm sorry, a lot of reasons.
No, no, no, no. It's fine,
you know family is the most important to me.
Michal, can you please come help me for a sec?
It's fine, I took care of it. Now.
Grandpa.
What you told me isn’t true.
You said all Germans are Nazis, but Goldie is German.
What?
Thanks, I love you.
So proud of her.
Look how she’s grown.
At least it won't be this Friday.
But this Friday the Nazi is coming.
Your dad is thrilled that Adam is getting back at the Germans, huh?
Adam, Adam, overall...
Honestly, it would be nice like this.
Sure, son, for you, it would be genius.
But tomorrow we’re going to my mom’s.
And why do we have to go to the parents' every Saturday?
What, can’t we just have toast?
What’s that?
The toast.
Why not a tortilla in Guadalajara?
You and your brothers are always together:
Singing together.
Honey...
Ugh.
It's impossible, but I'll check.
No, it’s... uh, not possible.
Impossible. No. Can’t do it.
Can’t do it, but I’ll check.
Can’t do it.
Can’t do it, but...
But...
Can’t do it, but I’ll check.
You’re not telling anyone.
Stay here and take out the trash for the girl.
Stay here and take out the trash.
Dvir, he’s a jerk.
It’s not my fault.